{
    "name": "JPDB 40K",
    "cards": [
  {
    "question": "弁が立つ",
    "answer": "べんがたつ",
    "meaning": "to be eloquent, to have a way with words"
  },
  {
    "question": "白梅",
    "answer": "しらうめ,はくばい",
    "meaning": "white plum blossoms, white Japanese apricot, white-blossomed plum"
  },
  {
    "question": "百眼",
    "answer": "ひゃくまなこ",
    "meaning": "using multiple simple paper masks to represent different emotions in a play (from the middle of the"
  },
  {
    "question": "公理",
    "answer": "こうり",
    "meaning": "axiom, maxim, self-evident truth"
  },
  {
    "question": "月世界",
    "answer": "げっせかい",
    "meaning": "moon, lunar world"
  },
  {
    "question": "遺品整理",
    "answer": "いひんせいり",
    "meaning": "estate sale, estate liquidation"
  },
  {
    "question": "白バイ",
    "answer": "しろバイ",
    "meaning": "motorcycle police, white-colored police motorcycle"
  },
  {
    "question": "浄土",
    "answer": "じょうど",
    "meaning": "pure land (esp. the Western Pure Land paradise of Amitabha), (Buddhist) paradise, Pure Land Buddhism"
  },
  {
    "question": "鉱床",
    "answer": "こうしょう",
    "meaning": "mineral deposit, ore deposit"
  },
  {
    "question": "鰭",
    "answer": "ひれ,はた",
    "meaning": "fin (e.g. of a fish)"
  },
  {
    "question": "面貌",
    "answer": "めんぼう",
    "meaning": "looks"
  },
  {
    "question": "不様",
    "answer": "ぶざま",
    "meaning": "unshapely, unsightly, clumsy, unpresentable, uncouth, awkward, ungainly"
  },
  {
    "question": "原子炉",
    "answer": "げんしろ",
    "meaning": "atomic reactor, nuclear reactor"
  },
  {
    "question": "打点",
    "answer": "だてん",
    "meaning": "runs batted in, RBI, position of a ball when struck (e.g. in tennis, volleyball)"
  },
  {
    "question": "時事",
    "answer": "じじ",
    "meaning": "events of the day, current affairs"
  },
  {
    "question": "堆肥",
    "answer": "たいひ",
    "meaning": "compost, manure"
  },
  {
    "question": "毛織物",
    "answer": "けおりもの",
    "meaning": "woollen material, woollen goods or fabric"
  },
  {
    "question": "各界",
    "answer": "かっかい,かくかい",
    "meaning": "each field, various circles"
  },
  {
    "question": "生け花",
    "answer": "いけばな",
    "meaning": "ikebana, Japanese art of flower arrangement"
  },
  {
    "question": "自演",
    "answer": "じえん",
    "meaning": "starring in one's own play, movie, etc., directing one's own play, etc."
  },
  {
    "question": "御挨拶",
    "answer": "ごあいさつ",
    "meaning": "greeting, a fine thing to say"
  },
  {
    "question": "性善説",
    "answer": "せいぜんせつ",
    "meaning": "belief that human nature is fundamentally good"
  },
  {
    "question": "娑婆",
    "answer": "しゃば",
    "meaning": "this world, this life, the free world (outside of prison, the army, red light district, etc.), this"
  },
  {
    "question": "相撲取り",
    "answer": "すもうとり,すまいとり",
    "meaning": "wrestler, rikishi"
  },
  {
    "question": "森林浴",
    "answer": "しんりんよく",
    "meaning": "forest bathing, forest therapy, peaceful walk through the woods for health benefits"
  },
  {
    "question": "生け捕る",
    "answer": "いけどる",
    "meaning": "to capture alive, to catch alive, to take prisoner"
  },
  {
    "question": "再訪",
    "answer": "さいほう",
    "meaning": "revisit"
  },
  {
    "question": "台数",
    "answer": "だいすう",
    "meaning": "number of large objects such as cars, computers, etc."
  },
  {
    "question": "離乳食",
    "answer": "りにゅうしょく",
    "meaning": "baby food"
  },
  {
    "question": "先鋭",
    "answer": "せんえい",
    "meaning": "radical, acute, sharp"
  },
  {
    "question": "教鞭",
    "answer": "きょうべん",
    "meaning": "teacher's cane, teacher's pointer"
  },
  {
    "question": "小事",
    "answer": "しょうじ",
    "meaning": "trifling matter, trifle"
  },
  {
    "question": "熱血漢",
    "answer": "ねっけつかん",
    "meaning": "hot-blooded man"
  },
  {
    "question": "同義語",
    "answer": "どうぎご",
    "meaning": "synonym"
  },
  {
    "question": "雛菊",
    "answer": "ひなぎく",
    "meaning": "daisy (Bellis perennis), English daisy"
  },
  {
    "question": "雪兎",
    "answer": "ゆきうさぎ",
    "meaning": "mountain hare (Lepus timidus), blue hare, tundra hare, variable hare, white hare, alpine hare, hare"
  },
  {
    "question": "徒弟",
    "answer": "とてい",
    "meaning": "apprentice"
  },
  {
    "question": "虻",
    "answer": "あぶ,あむ",
    "meaning": "horsefly, gadfly"
  },
  {
    "question": "同朋",
    "answer": "どうぼう,どうほう",
    "meaning": "companions, fellows"
  },
  {
    "question": "丁稚",
    "answer": "でっち",
    "meaning": "apprentice, shop boy"
  },
  {
    "question": "香木",
    "answer": "こうぼく",
    "meaning": "fragrant wood, aromatic tree"
  },
  {
    "question": "薬膳",
    "answer": "やくぜん",
    "meaning": "medicinal cooking (based on traditional Chinese medicine)"
  },
  {
    "question": "寝衣",
    "answer": "ねまき,しんい",
    "meaning": "sleep-wear, nightclothes, pyjamas, pajamas, nightgown, nightdress"
  },
  {
    "question": "財貨",
    "answer": "ざいか",
    "meaning": "commodity, property"
  },
  {
    "question": "絵巻",
    "answer": "えまき",
    "meaning": "picture scroll"
  },
  {
    "question": "人身事故",
    "answer": "じんしんじこ",
    "meaning": "accident resulting in personal injury or death (esp. traffic, rail, etc.)"
  },
  {
    "question": "心療内科",
    "answer": "しんりょうないか",
    "meaning": "psychosomatic medicine"
  },
  {
    "question": "猫足",
    "answer": "ねこあし",
    "meaning": "cabriole leg (of a table, chair, etc.), stealthy footsteps, walking silently"
  },
  {
    "question": "評す",
    "answer": "ひょうす",
    "meaning": "to evaluate, to appraise, to comment on"
  },
  {
    "question": "超満員",
    "answer": "ちょうまんいん",
    "meaning": "overcrowded, congested"
  },
  {
    "question": "競演",
    "answer": "きょうえん",
    "meaning": "contest (between performers), competitive performance, competition between theatres putting on the s"
  },
  {
    "question": "競歩",
    "answer": "きょうほ",
    "meaning": "racewalking, race walking, walking race"
  },
  {
    "question": "泊り",
    "answer": "とまり",
    "meaning": "overnight stay, stopover, inn, hotel, anchorage, night duty"
  },
  {
    "question": "秋の日",
    "answer": "あきのひ",
    "meaning": "autumn day, autumn sun"
  },
  {
    "question": "未払い",
    "answer": "みはらい,みばらい",
    "meaning": "unpaid, overdue"
  },
  {
    "question": "下げ",
    "answer": "さげ",
    "meaning": "lowering, sinking, bringing down, letting down, depreciation, price fall, punch line (of a rakugo st"
  },
  {
    "question": "餞",
    "answer": "はなむけ,せん",
    "meaning": "farewell gift, parting gift, viaticum"
  },
  {
    "question": "がた落ち",
    "answer": "がたおち",
    "meaning": "sharp drop, plunge, nosedive, slump, (value or amount) plummeting"
  },
  {
    "question": "通じ",
    "answer": "つうじ",
    "meaning": "bowel movement, evacuation, understanding"
  },
  {
    "question": "第三帝国",
    "answer": "だいさんていこく",
    "meaning": "the Third Reich, Nazi Germany"
  },
  {
    "question": "僧院",
    "answer": "そういん",
    "meaning": "monastery, temple"
  },
  {
    "question": "邪鬼",
    "answer": "じゃき",
    "meaning": "devil, imp, evil spirit"
  },
  {
    "question": "海女",
    "answer": "あま,あまめ",
    "meaning": "ama, female diver (who collects shells, seaweed, etc.)"
  },
  {
    "question": "大弓",
    "answer": "だいきゅう,おおゆみ",
    "meaning": "bow, longbow"
  },
  {
    "question": "旧暦",
    "answer": "きゅうれき",
    "meaning": "Japan's old (lunisolar) calendar"
  },
  {
    "question": "法被",
    "answer": "はっぴ",
    "meaning": "happi coat, happy coat, workman's livery coat, traditional Japanese straight-sleeved coat"
  },
  {
    "question": "移築",
    "answer": "いちく",
    "meaning": "dismantling a (historic) building and reconstructing it elsewhere"
  },
  {
    "question": "送電線",
    "answer": "そうでんせん",
    "meaning": "power line"
  },
  {
    "question": "稚児",
    "answer": "ちご,やや,ややこ",
    "meaning": "(festivity) page, baby, child, boys kept by pederasts"
  },
  {
    "question": "目顔",
    "answer": "めがお",
    "meaning": "signal, look"
  },
  {
    "question": "白眼",
    "answer": "しろめ,はくがん",
    "meaning": "white of the eye, cold, unwelcoming eyes"
  },
  {
    "question": "受粉",
    "answer": "じゅふん",
    "meaning": "pollination"
  },
  {
    "question": "一刹那",
    "answer": "いっせつな",
    "meaning": "(a) moment, an instant"
  },
  {
    "question": "払い戻し",
    "answer": "はらいもどし",
    "meaning": "repayment, refund, payback"
  },
  {
    "question": "竜の口",
    "answer": "たつのくち",
    "meaning": "dragon-head gargoyle, gutter spout"
  },
  {
    "question": "謎掛け",
    "answer": "なぞかけ",
    "meaning": "telling a riddle"
  },
  {
    "question": "崖崩れ",
    "answer": "がけくずれ",
    "meaning": "landslide, landslip"
  },
  {
    "question": "瞭然",
    "answer": "りょうぜん",
    "meaning": "obvious, evident, clear"
  },
  {
    "question": "うそ寒い",
    "answer": "うそさむい",
    "meaning": "somewhat cold, a bit chilly"
  },
  {
    "question": "褒章",
    "answer": "ほうしょう",
    "meaning": "medal of honour, medal of merit"
  },
  {
    "question": "見せ掛け",
    "answer": "みせかけ",
    "meaning": "seeming, pose, show, pretense, sham, mock"
  },
  {
    "question": "易",
    "answer": "えき,い",
    "meaning": "type of cleromancy divination (described in the Book of Changes) performed with long sticks, The Boo"
  },
  {
    "question": "稼ぎ出す",
    "answer": "かせぎだす",
    "meaning": "to gain, to earn (for oneself), to win"
  },
  {
    "question": "言論",
    "answer": "げんろん",
    "meaning": "(one's) speech, expression of views, discussion"
  },
  {
    "question": "地熱",
    "answer": "ちねつ,じねつ",
    "meaning": "geothermal energy, terrestrial heat"
  },
  {
    "question": "粗忽者",
    "answer": "そこつもの",
    "meaning": "careless person, thoughtless person"
  },
  {
    "question": "尋ね人",
    "answer": "たずねびと",
    "meaning": "missing person, wanted person"
  },
  {
    "question": "中火",
    "answer": "ちゅうび",
    "meaning": "medium flame (cooking), medium heat, medium fire"
  },
  {
    "question": "上納",
    "answer": "じょうのう",
    "meaning": "payment to the government"
  },
  {
    "question": "棲み分け",
    "answer": "すみわけ",
    "meaning": "habitat isolation, compartmentalization, segregation, isolation"
  },
  {
    "question": "見兼ねる",
    "answer": "みかねる",
    "meaning": "to be unable to let pass unnoticed, to be unable to be indifferent, to be unable to just watch (with"
  },
  {
    "question": "文化人",
    "answer": "ぶんかじん",
    "meaning": "person of culture, cultured person"
  },
  {
    "question": "勝ち鬨",
    "answer": "かちどき",
    "meaning": "shout of victory, cry of triumph"
  },
  {
    "question": "真夏日",
    "answer": "まなつび",
    "meaning": "day on which the temperature rises above 30 degrees Celsius"
  },
  {
    "question": "居辛い",
    "answer": "いづらい",
    "meaning": "difficult to be (in a place), not feeling like staying"
  },
  {
    "question": "洗面",
    "answer": "せんめん",
    "meaning": "washing one's face"
  },
  {
    "question": "耳に挟む",
    "answer": "みみにはさむ",
    "meaning": "to happen to hear, to overhear"
  },
  {
    "question": "重役出勤",
    "answer": "じゅうやくしゅっきん",
    "meaning": "arriving at work late as if one were an executive, management attendance at work"
  },
  {
    "question": "翌月",
    "answer": "よくげつ",
    "meaning": "following month"
  },
  {
    "question": "賢木",
    "answer": "さかき",
    "meaning": "sakaki (species of evergreen sacred to Shinto, Cleyera japonica), evergreen (esp. one planted or use"
  },
  {
    "question": "空音",
    "answer": "そらね",
    "meaning": "imitated cry (of an animal), lie"
  },
  {
    "question": "天主",
    "answer": "てんしゅ",
    "meaning": "Lord of Heaven, God, castle tower"
  },
  {
    "question": "賽の河原",
    "answer": "さいのかわら",
    "meaning": "Children's Limbo, futile, unrewarding"
  },
  {
    "question": "通気",
    "answer": "つうき",
    "meaning": "ventilation, airflow"
  },
  {
    "question": "粉飾",
    "answer": "ふんしょく",
    "meaning": "embellishment (e.g. of a story), ornamentation, decoration, putting on makeup"
  },
  {
    "question": "慰霊",
    "answer": "いれい",
    "meaning": "consoling the spirits of the dead"
  },
  {
    "question": "不寝番",
    "answer": "ねずばん,ふしんばん",
    "meaning": "sleepless vigil, night watch, vigilance"
  },
  {
    "question": "騙り",
    "answer": "かたり",
    "meaning": "swindle, fraud"
  },
  {
    "question": "象牙色",
    "answer": "ぞうげいろ",
    "meaning": "ivory-white"
  },
  {
    "question": "裁決",
    "answer": "さいけつ",
    "meaning": "decision, ruling, judgement, judgment"
  },
  {
    "question": "珍種",
    "answer": "ちんしゅ",
    "meaning": "rare species"
  },
  {
    "question": "指南書",
    "answer": "しなんしょ",
    "meaning": "handbook, instruction book, manual"
  },
  {
    "question": "煮沸",
    "answer": "しゃふつ",
    "meaning": "boiling up"
  },
  {
    "question": "直営",
    "answer": "ちょくえい",
    "meaning": "direct management"
  },
  {
    "question": "金鉱",
    "answer": "きんこう",
    "meaning": "gold ore, gold deposit, gold mine"
  },
  {
    "question": "見掛け",
    "answer": "みかけ",
    "meaning": "outward appearance, apparent"
  },
  {
    "question": "乾パン",
    "answer": "かんパン",
    "meaning": "cracker, hard biscuit, hardtack"
  },
  {
    "question": "淡水魚",
    "answer": "たんすいぎょ",
    "meaning": "freshwater fish"
  },
  {
    "question": "翔る",
    "answer": "かける",
    "meaning": "to soar, to fly, to run, to dash"
  },
  {
    "question": "同窓",
    "answer": "どうそう",
    "meaning": "being a graduate of the same school, person who went to the same school, fellow alumnus"
  },
  {
    "question": "狭窄",
    "answer": "きょうさく",
    "meaning": "contraction, narrowing, stricture, stenosis"
  },
  {
    "question": "購う",
    "answer": "あがなう",
    "meaning": "to buy, to pay for"
  },
  {
    "question": "転回",
    "answer": "てんかい",
    "meaning": "revolution, rotation"
  },
  {
    "question": "無糖",
    "answer": "むとう",
    "meaning": "sugarless, unsweetened"
  },
  {
    "question": "相関関係",
    "answer": "そうかんかんけい",
    "meaning": "correlation, interrelation, intertwining"
  },
  {
    "question": "謗る",
    "answer": "そしる",
    "meaning": "to slander, to libel, to criticize, to criticise"
  },
  {
    "question": "古事記",
    "answer": "こじき,ふることふみ",
    "meaning": "Kojiki, Records of Ancient Matters, Japan's oldest historical record"
  },
  {
    "question": "押し出し",
    "answer": "おしだし",
    "meaning": "pushing something out, extrusion, presence, appearance, run walked in, pushing one's opponent out by"
  },
  {
    "question": "伯仲",
    "answer": "はくちゅう",
    "meaning": "being evenly matched, being equal with, being on a par with, being well contested, eldest and second"
  },
  {
    "question": "店を畳む",
    "answer": "みせをたたむ",
    "meaning": "to close down a business, to shut a business"
  },
  {
    "question": "蹴躓く",
    "answer": "けつまずく,けつまづく",
    "meaning": "to stumble (over), to trip, to fail, to suffer a setback"
  },
  {
    "question": "割安",
    "answer": "わりやす",
    "meaning": "economical, comparatively cheap"
  },
  {
    "question": "愛顧",
    "answer": "あいこ",
    "meaning": "patronage, favour, favor"
  },
  {
    "question": "初犯",
    "answer": "しょはん",
    "meaning": "first offence, first offense, first offender"
  },
  {
    "question": "不振",
    "answer": "ふしん",
    "meaning": "dullness, slump, stagnation, inactivity, depression"
  },
  {
    "question": "着痩せ",
    "answer": "きやせ",
    "meaning": "looking slender in clothing"
  },
  {
    "question": "深ける",
    "answer": "ふける",
    "meaning": "to get late, to advance, to wear on"
  },
  {
    "question": "宮地",
    "answer": "みやち,みやじ",
    "meaning": "grounds of a Shinto shrine"
  },
  {
    "question": "霊木",
    "answer": "れいぼく",
    "meaning": "sacred tree"
  },
  {
    "question": "腸詰",
    "answer": "ちょうづめ",
    "meaning": "sausage"
  },
  {
    "question": "氷刃",
    "answer": "ひょうじん",
    "meaning": "sharp, glistening sword"
  },
  {
    "question": "国葬",
    "answer": "こくそう",
    "meaning": "state funeral, national funeral"
  },
  {
    "question": "戯け",
    "answer": "おどけ,たわけ",
    "meaning": "joke, witticism, pleasantry, attempt at humour, attempt at humor, tomfoolery, foolish act, nonsense,"
  },
  {
    "question": "楽士",
    "answer": "がくし",
    "meaning": "musician, bandsman"
  },
  {
    "question": "精確",
    "answer": "せいかく",
    "meaning": "detailed and accurate, exhaustive and precise, meticulous, finely detailed"
  },
  {
    "question": "遠望",
    "answer": "えんぼう",
    "meaning": "vista, distant view"
  },
  {
    "question": "鋼板",
    "answer": "こうはん,こうばん",
    "meaning": "steel sheet, steel plate, steel plates"
  },
  {
    "question": "中る",
    "answer": "あたる",
    "meaning": "to be hit, to strike, to touch, to be in contact, to be affixed, to be equivalent to, to be applicab"
  },
  {
    "question": "降板",
    "answer": "こうばん",
    "meaning": "leaving the mound, being knocked out, resignation, stepping down, withdrawing"
  },
  {
    "question": "金魚鉢",
    "answer": "きんぎょばち",
    "meaning": "goldfish bowl"
  },
  {
    "question": "月桂樹",
    "answer": "げっけいじゅ",
    "meaning": "bay laurel (Laurus nobilis), bay tree, sweet bay, laurel tree"
  },
  {
    "question": "素通し",
    "answer": "すどおし",
    "meaning": "transparent, plain (glass or glasses)"
  },
  {
    "question": "戦略兵器",
    "answer": "せんりゃくへいき",
    "meaning": "strategic arms"
  },
  {
    "question": "快哉",
    "answer": "かいさい",
    "meaning": "joy, exultation"
  },
  {
    "question": "肉弾",
    "answer": "にくだん",
    "meaning": "human bullet"
  },
  {
    "question": "分数",
    "answer": "ぶんすう",
    "meaning": "fraction"
  },
  {
    "question": "掛け違う",
    "answer": "かけちがう",
    "meaning": "to cross paths, to conflict"
  },
  {
    "question": "対称的",
    "answer": "たいしょうてき",
    "meaning": "symmetrical"
  },
  {
    "question": "表題",
    "answer": "ひょうだい",
    "meaning": "title, index, heading, headline, caption"
  },
  {
    "question": "前職",
    "answer": "ぜんしょく",
    "meaning": "last position, previous job, predecessor"
  },
  {
    "question": "国策",
    "answer": "こくさく",
    "meaning": "national policy"
  },
  {
    "question": "景気付け",
    "answer": "けいきづけ",
    "meaning": "putting life into, animating, cheering up"
  },
  {
    "question": "二の矢",
    "answer": "にのや",
    "meaning": "second arrow, second move, second step"
  },
  {
    "question": "爆上げ",
    "answer": "ばくあげ",
    "meaning": "explosive increase, rising dramatically, shooting up"
  },
  {
    "question": "植物性",
    "answer": "しょくぶつせい",
    "meaning": "botanical, vegetable, vegetal, vegetative"
  },
  {
    "question": "発起人",
    "answer": "ほっきにん",
    "meaning": "originator, promoter"
  },
  {
    "question": "冷血漢",
    "answer": "れいけつかん",
    "meaning": "cold-blooded person, heartless, coldhearted person"
  },
  {
    "question": "内面的",
    "answer": "ないめんてき",
    "meaning": "inner, internal, inside"
  },
  {
    "question": "流人",
    "answer": "るにん,りゅうじん",
    "meaning": "(an) exile, vagrant, wanderer, nomad"
  },
  {
    "question": "泉水",
    "answer": "せんすい",
    "meaning": "garden pond, miniature lake, fountain"
  },
  {
    "question": "転変",
    "answer": "てんぺん",
    "meaning": "mutation, change, vicissitude"
  },
  {
    "question": "上等兵",
    "answer": "じょうとうへい",
    "meaning": "private first-class (army), airman first class (air force), lance corporal (US Marines; Commonwealth"
  },
  {
    "question": "鬼瓦",
    "answer": "おにがわら",
    "meaning": "decorative ridge-end tile (traditionally bearing the face of a demon and resembling a gargoyle), hid"
  },
  {
    "question": "要石",
    "answer": "かなめいし",
    "meaning": "keystone"
  },
  {
    "question": "水牛",
    "answer": "すいぎゅう",
    "meaning": "water buffalo (Bubalus bubalis), domestic Asian water buffalo, wild water buffalo (Bubalus arnee), A"
  },
  {
    "question": "出会す",
    "answer": "でくわす",
    "meaning": "to happen to meet, to come across"
  },
  {
    "question": "氷菓子",
    "answer": "こおりがし",
    "meaning": "frozen dessert"
  },
  {
    "question": "薄膜",
    "answer": "うすまく,はくまく",
    "meaning": "thin film"
  },
  {
    "question": "宿帳",
    "answer": "やどちょう",
    "meaning": "hotel register"
  },
  {
    "question": "不起訴",
    "answer": "ふきそ",
    "meaning": "nonprosecution, nonindictment"
  },
  {
    "question": "五体投地",
    "answer": "ごたいとうち",
    "meaning": "prostration, placing knees, hands and forehead on the ground to show utmost respect"
  },
  {
    "question": "早番",
    "answer": "はやばん",
    "meaning": "early shift, morning shift, early arrival"
  },
  {
    "question": "アミノ酸",
    "answer": "アミノさん",
    "meaning": "amino acid"
  },
  {
    "question": "奇縁",
    "answer": "きえん",
    "meaning": "strange coincidence"
  },
  {
    "question": "馬の足",
    "answer": "うまのあし",
    "meaning": "minor or untalented actor (relegated to roles such as the legs of a stage horse)"
  },
  {
    "question": "老け顔",
    "answer": "ふけがお",
    "meaning": "old-looking face"
  },
  {
    "question": "右左",
    "answer": "みぎひだり",
    "meaning": "right and left"
  },
  {
    "question": "紙細工",
    "answer": "かみざいく",
    "meaning": "articles made out of paper (by hand), paperware"
  },
  {
    "question": "別命",
    "answer": "べつめい",
    "meaning": "another or separate order"
  },
  {
    "question": "極楽浄土",
    "answer": "ごくらくじょうど",
    "meaning": "Amitabha's Pure Land, Sukhavati"
  },
  {
    "question": "常緑樹",
    "answer": "じょうりょくじゅ",
    "meaning": "evergreen tree"
  },
  {
    "question": "自律神経",
    "answer": "じりつしんけい",
    "meaning": "autonomic nerves"
  },
  {
    "question": "冗長",
    "answer": "じょうちょう",
    "meaning": "tedious, verbose, wordy, lengthy, longwinded, prolix, redundancy"
  },
  {
    "question": "遊佐",
    "answer": "",
    "meaning": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "大老",
    "answer": "たいろう",
    "meaning": "(Edo-period) chief minister"
  },
  {
    "question": "仲買人",
    "answer": "なかがいにん",
    "meaning": "broker, jobber"
  },
  {
    "question": "臨時政府",
    "answer": "りんじせいふ",
    "meaning": "provisional government"
  },
  {
    "question": "人形遣い",
    "answer": "にんぎょうつかい,にんぎょうづかい",
    "meaning": "puppet operator, puppet manipulator, puppeteer"
  },
  {
    "question": "呉れる",
    "answer": "くれる",
    "meaning": "to give, to let (one) have, to do for one, to take the trouble to do, to do to someone's disadvantag"
  },
  {
    "question": "指し手",
    "answer": "さして",
    "meaning": "move (in shogi, chess, etc.)"
  },
  {
    "question": "爆圧",
    "answer": "ばくあつ",
    "meaning": "pressure from an explosion, blast pressure, shock wave"
  },
  {
    "question": "寡婦",
    "answer": "かふ,やもめ",
    "meaning": "widow, divorced woman not remarried, unmarried woman"
  },
  {
    "question": "背凭れ",
    "answer": "せもたれ",
    "meaning": "back (of a chair)"
  },
  {
    "question": "干し柿",
    "answer": "ほしがき",
    "meaning": "dried persimmons"
  },
  {
    "question": "圧し折る",
    "answer": "へしおる",
    "meaning": "to smash, to break"
  },
  {
    "question": "分派",
    "answer": "ぶんぱ",
    "meaning": "faction, branch, sect, denomination, branching off"
  },
  {
    "question": "呉服屋",
    "answer": "ごふくや",
    "meaning": "kimono fabrics shop, draper"
  },
  {
    "question": "旗手",
    "answer": "きしゅ",
    "meaning": "standard-bearer, flag-bearer"
  },
  {
    "question": "裸電球",
    "answer": "はだかでんきゅう",
    "meaning": "naked light bulb"
  },
  {
    "question": "葬列",
    "answer": "そうれつ",
    "meaning": "funeral procession"
  },
  {
    "question": "公転",
    "answer": "こうてん",
    "meaning": "revolution (of heavens)"
  },
  {
    "question": "内申書",
    "answer": "ないしんしょ",
    "meaning": "school record (on a student), transcript (of grades), confidential report"
  },
  {
    "question": "専売",
    "answer": "せんばい",
    "meaning": "monopoly, monopolization, exclusive sales rights"
  },
  {
    "question": "自給",
    "answer": "じきゅう",
    "meaning": "self-support"
  },
  {
    "question": "低次元",
    "answer": "ていじげん",
    "meaning": "low-level, trivial, coarse, vulgar, low-dimension"
  },
  {
    "question": "分泌物",
    "answer": "ぶんぴつぶつ,ぶんぴぶつ",
    "meaning": "secretion"
  },
  {
    "question": "五寸釘",
    "answer": "ごすんくぎ",
    "meaning": "long nail, spike"
  },
  {
    "question": "判読",
    "answer": "はんどく",
    "meaning": "decipherment, interpretation, making out, identification"
  },
  {
    "question": "写実的",
    "answer": "しゃじつてき",
    "meaning": "realistic, graphic, true to life"
  },
  {
    "question": "煙い",
    "answer": "けむい,けぶい",
    "meaning": "smoky"
  },
  {
    "question": "遊星",
    "answer": "ゆうせい",
    "meaning": "planet"
  },
  {
    "question": "緑青",
    "answer": "ろくしょう,りょくしょう",
    "meaning": "verdigris, green rust, copper rust"
  },
  {
    "question": "間合",
    "answer": "まあい",
    "meaning": "interval, distance, break, pause, suitable time, appropriate opportunity, distance between opponents"
  },
  {
    "question": "行政官",
    "answer": "ぎょうせいかん",
    "meaning": "executive officer, administrative official"
  },
  {
    "question": "陸自",
    "answer": "りくじ",
    "meaning": "Japan Ground Self-Defense Force, JGSDF"
  },
  {
    "question": "段位",
    "answer": "だんい",
    "meaning": "dan rank (in martial arts, go, etc.), advanced rank, grade of black belt"
  },
  {
    "question": "稜",
    "answer": "りょう",
    "meaning": "edge, angle, ridge (e.g. of a mountain)"
  },
  {
    "question": "帝政",
    "answer": "ていせい",
    "meaning": "imperial government, imperialism, monarchical rule"
  },
  {
    "question": "物見櫓",
    "answer": "ものみやぐら",
    "meaning": "watchtower, observation tower, lookout"
  },
  {
    "question": "薬缶",
    "answer": "やかん",
    "meaning": "kettle"
  },
  {
    "question": "為人",
    "answer": "ひととなり",
    "meaning": "hereditary disposition, temperament, nature, body build"
  },
  {
    "question": "重油",
    "answer": "じゅうゆ",
    "meaning": "heavy oil, fuel oil"
  },
  {
    "question": "廃線",
    "answer": "はいせん",
    "meaning": "abandoned railway line, closed railway line, discontinued line"
  },
  {
    "question": "用地",
    "answer": "ようち",
    "meaning": "site"
  },
  {
    "question": "尾羽",
    "answer": "おは,おばね",
    "meaning": "tail and feathers, tail feathers"
  },
  {
    "question": "薄明",
    "answer": "はくめい",
    "meaning": "twilight, dusk, faint light"
  },
  {
    "question": "給油",
    "answer": "きゅうゆ",
    "meaning": "refueling (car, plane, etc.), lubricating (a machine), oiling"
  },
  {
    "question": "発光体",
    "answer": "はっこうたい",
    "meaning": "luminous body"
  },
  {
    "question": "不戦",
    "answer": "ふせん",
    "meaning": "war renunciation, anti-war, bout cancelled due to absence of one of the wrestlers"
  },
  {
    "question": "表門",
    "answer": "おもてもん",
    "meaning": "front gate"
  },
  {
    "question": "勝ち星",
    "answer": "かちぼし",
    "meaning": "(mark indicating) a win"
  },
  {
    "question": "鬼子",
    "answer": "おにご,おにっこ",
    "meaning": "child born with teeth, child which does not resemble its parents, changeling, wild child, badly-beha"
  },
  {
    "question": "思考実験",
    "answer": "しこうじっけん",
    "meaning": "thought experiment, gedankenexperiment"
  },
  {
    "question": "嗄らす",
    "answer": "からす",
    "meaning": "to talk oneself hoarse, to shout oneself hoarse"
  },
  {
    "question": "涌く",
    "answer": "わく",
    "meaning": "to well (up), to gush forth (of water), to spring out, to surge, to appear (esp. suddenly) (sweat, t"
  },
  {
    "question": "非モテ",
    "answer": "ひモテ",
    "meaning": "unpopular (esp. with the opposite sex)"
  },
  {
    "question": "初任給",
    "answer": "しょにんきゅう",
    "meaning": "initial salary"
  },
  {
    "question": "一捻り",
    "answer": "ひとひねり",
    "meaning": "a reworking, a pushover"
  },
  {
    "question": "予防策",
    "answer": "よぼうさく",
    "meaning": "preventive measure, precautionary measure"
  },
  {
    "question": "寝付き",
    "answer": "ねつき",
    "meaning": "falling asleep, going to sleep"
  },
  {
    "question": "懐っこい",
    "answer": "なつっこい",
    "meaning": "amiable, affable, likable"
  },
  {
    "question": "邯鄲",
    "answer": "かんたん",
    "meaning": "tree cricket (Oecanthus longicauda)"
  },
  {
    "question": "猶",
    "answer": "なお",
    "meaning": "still, yet, more, still more, greater, further, as ..., like ..., furthermore, in addition, moreover"
  },
  {
    "question": "蹴鞠",
    "answer": "けまり,しゅうきく",
    "meaning": "kemari, type of football played by courtiers in ancient Japan"
  },
  {
    "question": "県知事",
    "answer": "けんちじ",
    "meaning": "prefectural governor"
  },
  {
    "question": "串カツ",
    "answer": "くしカツ",
    "meaning": "kushikatsu, deep-fried skewered meat and vegetables"
  },
  {
    "question": "博徒",
    "answer": "ばくと",
    "meaning": "gambler"
  },
  {
    "question": "丙",
    "answer": "へい,ひのえ",
    "meaning": "third rank, third class, third person (in a contract, etc.), third sign of the Chinese calendar"
  },
  {
    "question": "貸金庫",
    "answer": "かしきんこ",
    "meaning": "safe-deposit box"
  },
  {
    "question": "氷原",
    "answer": "ひょうげん",
    "meaning": "ice field, ice floe"
  },
  {
    "question": "缶蹴り",
    "answer": "かんけり",
    "meaning": "'kick the can' game"
  },
  {
    "question": "修学",
    "answer": "しゅうがく",
    "meaning": "learning"
  },
  {
    "question": "原発",
    "answer": "げんぱつ",
    "meaning": "nuclear power plant, nuclear power generation, primary (e.g. primary immunodeficiency syndrome)"
  },
  {
    "question": "黒糖",
    "answer": "こくとう,くろとう",
    "meaning": "(unrefined) brown sugar, muscovado"
  },
  {
    "question": "夜の底",
    "answer": "よるのそこ",
    "meaning": "dark of the night, darkness of the night"
  },
  {
    "question": "王侯",
    "answer": "おうこう",
    "meaning": "king and princes, noble rank"
  },
  {
    "question": "愚連隊",
    "answer": "ぐれんたい",
    "meaning": "gang of young toughs, hooligans, hoodlums, hoods, yobbos"
  },
  {
    "question": "吸入",
    "answer": "きゅうにゅう",
    "meaning": "inhalation"
  },
  {
    "question": "釣り道具",
    "answer": "つりどうぐ",
    "meaning": "fishing tackle"
  },
  {
    "question": "雨露",
    "answer": "うろ,あめつゆ,あまつゆ",
    "meaning": "rain and dew"
  },
  {
    "question": "総評",
    "answer": "そうひょう",
    "meaning": "general comment, Sohyo (General Council of Trade Unions of Japan)"
  },
  {
    "question": "税制",
    "answer": "ぜいせい",
    "meaning": "tax system"
  },
  {
    "question": "訪問販売",
    "answer": "ほうもんはんばい",
    "meaning": "door-to-door selling"
  },
  {
    "question": "寵児",
    "answer": "ちょうじ",
    "meaning": "favorite child, favourite child, darling, favorite, star, hero"
  },
  {
    "question": "消する",
    "answer": "しょうする",
    "meaning": "to disappear, to cause to disappear, to get rid of, (of time) to pass, to while away"
  },
  {
    "question": "俗人",
    "answer": "ぞくじん",
    "meaning": "person with low tastes, uncultured person, worldly person, ordinary person (who has not entered the"
  },
  {
    "question": "酸い",
    "answer": "すい",
    "meaning": "sour, acid"
  },
  {
    "question": "肥やす",
    "answer": "こやす",
    "meaning": "to fertilize, to fertilise, to manure, to enrich"
  },
  {
    "question": "極め付け",
    "answer": "きわめつけ",
    "meaning": "certified (as genuine, valuable, etc.), guaranteed (article), of established reputation, acknowledge"
  },
  {
    "question": "糸状",
    "answer": "しじょう",
    "meaning": "stringlike, thready, linear, filamentous, filiform"
  },
  {
    "question": "粉状",
    "answer": "ふんじょう",
    "meaning": "pulverized, pulverised, powder(ed)"
  },
  {
    "question": "人いきれ",
    "answer": "ひといきれ",
    "meaning": "body heat from several people in close quarters, stuffy air"
  },
  {
    "question": "東征",
    "answer": "とうせい",
    "meaning": "eastern expedition"
  },
  {
    "question": "襷",
    "answer": "たすき",
    "meaning": "cord used to tuck up the sleeves of a kimono, sash (worn across chest, e.g. by election candidate or"
  },
  {
    "question": "運転士",
    "answer": "うんてんし",
    "meaning": "(professional) driver (of a taxi, train, etc.), motorman, mate (on a ship), officer"
  },
  {
    "question": "官房長官",
    "answer": "かんぼうちょうかん",
    "meaning": "Chief Cabinet Secretary, Chief of Staff of the Presidency"
  },
  {
    "question": "会報",
    "answer": "かいほう",
    "meaning": "bulletin (issued by a society), report, newsletter"
  },
  {
    "question": "睡蓮",
    "answer": "すいれん",
    "meaning": "water lily (any plant of genus Nymphaea), pygmy waterlily (Nymphaea tetragona)"
  },
  {
    "question": "寺子屋",
    "answer": "てらこや",
    "meaning": "temple elementary school (during the Edo period)"
  },
  {
    "question": "稚魚",
    "answer": "ちぎょ",
    "meaning": "fry, juvenile fish, fingerling"
  },
  {
    "question": "高知",
    "answer": "こうち",
    "meaning": "Kōchi (city, prefecture)"
  },
  {
    "question": "工業地帯",
    "answer": "こうぎょうちたい",
    "meaning": "industrial area"
  },
  {
    "question": "肥",
    "answer": "こえ",
    "meaning": "manure, night soil, dung, fertiliser, fertilizer"
  },
  {
    "question": "電文",
    "answer": "でんぶん",
    "meaning": "telegram"
  },
  {
    "question": "凄艶",
    "answer": "せいえん",
    "meaning": "weirdly beautiful"
  },
  {
    "question": "植林",
    "answer": "しょくりん",
    "meaning": "afforestation"
  },
  {
    "question": "設備投資",
    "answer": "せつびとうし",
    "meaning": "capital investment, capital expenditure, investment in plant and equipment"
  },
  {
    "question": "雪片",
    "answer": "せっぺん",
    "meaning": "snowflake (cluster of ice crystals)"
  },
  {
    "question": "二目",
    "answer": "ふため",
    "meaning": "for a second time"
  },
  {
    "question": "駄馬",
    "answer": "だば,だうま",
    "meaning": "packhorse, workhorse, hack"
  },
  {
    "question": "新書",
    "answer": "しんしょ",
    "meaning": "new book, 17x11 cm paperback book"
  },
  {
    "question": "十字砲火",
    "answer": "じゅうじほうか",
    "meaning": "cross fire"
  },
  {
    "question": "降雪",
    "answer": "こうせつ",
    "meaning": "snowfall, snow"
  },
  {
    "question": "捩じる",
    "answer": "ねじる",
    "meaning": "to screw, to twist, to distort, to parody, to make a pun, to torture, to wrest"
  },
  {
    "question": "無毒",
    "answer": "むどく",
    "meaning": "nonpoisonous, nontoxic, harmless"
  },
  {
    "question": "好き者",
    "answer": "すきもの",
    "meaning": "dilettante, lecher, nymphomaniac"
  },
  {
    "question": "筆を執る",
    "answer": "ふでをとる",
    "meaning": "to pen, to write, to draw"
  },
  {
    "question": "大器",
    "answer": "たいき",
    "meaning": "large container, person of great talent"
  },
  {
    "question": "不許可",
    "answer": "ふきょか",
    "meaning": "not permitting, not authorizing"
  },
  {
    "question": "北北西",
    "answer": "ほくほくせい",
    "meaning": "north-northwest"
  },
  {
    "question": "脳梗塞",
    "answer": "のうこうそく",
    "meaning": "stroke (blocked blood vessel in brain), cerebral infarction"
  },
  {
    "question": "下っ腹",
    "answer": "したっぱら",
    "meaning": "abdomen, stomach, under parts"
  },
  {
    "question": "人権侵害",
    "answer": "じんけんしんがい",
    "meaning": "human rights violation"
  },
  {
    "question": "正義漢",
    "answer": "せいぎかん",
    "meaning": "just person, man of justice, righteous person, upright person"
  },
  {
    "question": "沈静",
    "answer": "ちんせい",
    "meaning": "stillness, tranquility, tranquillity, dullness"
  },
  {
    "question": "天明",
    "answer": "てんめい",
    "meaning": "dawn, daybreak, Tenmei era (1781.4.2-1789.1.25)"
  },
  {
    "question": "碩学",
    "answer": "せきがく",
    "meaning": "great scholar, profound scholar"
  },
  {
    "question": "警吏",
    "answer": "けいり",
    "meaning": "police officer"
  },
  {
    "question": "真南",
    "answer": "まみなみ",
    "meaning": "due south"
  },
  {
    "question": "蛍火",
    "answer": "けいか,ほたるび",
    "meaning": "light of a firefly"
  },
  {
    "question": "奏功",
    "answer": "そうこう",
    "meaning": "success, achievement, fruition"
  },
  {
    "question": "板金",
    "answer": "ばんきん,いたがね",
    "meaning": "sheet metal, metal plate"
  },
  {
    "question": "見交わす",
    "answer": "みかわす",
    "meaning": "to exchange glances"
  },
  {
    "question": "格子戸",
    "answer": "こうしど",
    "meaning": "lattice door"
  },
  {
    "question": "横書き",
    "answer": "よこがき",
    "meaning": "writing horizontally, horizontal writing"
  },
  {
    "question": "漂泊",
    "answer": "ひょうはく",
    "meaning": "roaming, drifting about, wandering"
  },
  {
    "question": "哀悼",
    "answer": "あいとう",
    "meaning": "condolence, regret, tribute, sorrow, sympathy, lament"
  },
  {
    "question": "可燃物",
    "answer": "かねんぶつ",
    "meaning": "combustibles, inflammables, flammables, burnables"
  },
  {
    "question": "平方",
    "answer": "へいほう",
    "meaning": "square (e.g. metre)"
  },
  {
    "question": "殉死",
    "answer": "じゅんし",
    "meaning": "following one's master into the grave, committing suicide after one's lord has died"
  },
  {
    "question": "参観",
    "answer": "さんかん",
    "meaning": "visit, inspection"
  },
  {
    "question": "縁の下",
    "answer": "えんのした",
    "meaning": "out of sight, in the background, unnoticed, under the veranda"
  },
  {
    "question": "晒し",
    "answer": "さらし",
    "meaning": "bleaching, bleached cotton, doxxing, doxing, making someone's private information public without per"
  },
  {
    "question": "活動家",
    "answer": "かつどうか",
    "meaning": "activist"
  },
  {
    "question": "昼御飯",
    "answer": "ひるごはん",
    "meaning": "lunch, midday meal"
  },
  {
    "question": "口真似",
    "answer": "くちまね",
    "meaning": "mimicry, imitating someone's way of speaking"
  },
  {
    "question": "悪戯小僧",
    "answer": "いたずらこぞう",
    "meaning": "mischievous boy"
  },
  {
    "question": "決起集会",
    "answer": "けっきしゅうかい",
    "meaning": "kickoff party, rally, pep party"
  },
  {
    "question": "枕カバー",
    "answer": "まくらカバー",
    "meaning": "pillowcase"
  },
  {
    "question": "サラダ油",
    "answer": "サラダゆ",
    "meaning": "salad oil"
  },
  {
    "question": "酒気",
    "answer": "しゅき",
    "meaning": "liquor smell, tipsiness"
  },
  {
    "question": "支配階級",
    "answer": "しはいかいきゅう",
    "meaning": "ruling classes"
  },
  {
    "question": "初年度",
    "answer": "しょねんど",
    "meaning": "first year, initial (year)"
  },
  {
    "question": "内輪揉め",
    "answer": "うちわもめ",
    "meaning": "internal conflict, family quarrel, domestic trouble"
  },
  {
    "question": "真情",
    "answer": "しんじょう",
    "meaning": "true feeling"
  },
  {
    "question": "不忠",
    "answer": "ふちゅう",
    "meaning": "disloyalty, infidelity"
  },
  {
    "question": "読み上げ",
    "answer": "よみあげ",
    "meaning": "reading aloud, recitation"
  },
  {
    "question": "焼き増し",
    "answer": "やきまし",
    "meaning": "photo reprint"
  },
  {
    "question": "結露",
    "answer": "けつろ",
    "meaning": "condensation, formation of dew"
  },
  {
    "question": "多様化",
    "answer": "たようか",
    "meaning": "diversification"
  },
  {
    "question": "乳臭い",
    "answer": "ちちくさい",
    "meaning": "green, wet behind the ears, immature, smelling of milk"
  },
  {
    "question": "伸び代",
    "answer": "のびしろ",
    "meaning": "room for growth, potential, promise"
  },
  {
    "question": "好人物",
    "answer": "こうじんぶつ",
    "meaning": "good-natured person, nice person"
  },
  {
    "question": "冥福",
    "answer": "めいふく,みょうふく",
    "meaning": "happiness in the next world"
  },
  {
    "question": "公館",
    "answer": "こうかん",
    "meaning": "official residence"
  },
  {
    "question": "仁君",
    "answer": "じんくん",
    "meaning": "benevolent ruler"
  },
  {
    "question": "花梨",
    "answer": "かりん",
    "meaning": "Burmese rosewood (Pterocarpus indicus), angsana, amboyna, amboina, flowering quince (of genus Chaeno"
  },
  {
    "question": "弾正",
    "answer": "だんじょう",
    "meaning": "judge (of the Imperial Prosecuting and Investigating Office), judicial officer, minister of justice,"
  },
  {
    "question": "温熱",
    "answer": "おんねつ",
    "meaning": "warmth, heat"
  },
  {
    "question": "十二支",
    "answer": "じゅうにし",
    "meaning": "12 signs of the Chinese zodiac"
  },
  {
    "question": "公儀",
    "answer": "こうぎ",
    "meaning": "imperial court, shogunate government, authorities, public affairs, official, government"
  },
  {
    "question": "匕首",
    "answer": "あいくち,ひしゅ",
    "meaning": "dagger, dirk"
  },
  {
    "question": "駐在所",
    "answer": "ちゅうざいしょ",
    "meaning": "police substation, residential police box"
  },
  {
    "question": "社会主義",
    "answer": "しゃかいしゅぎ",
    "meaning": "socialism"
  },
  {
    "question": "湧出",
    "answer": "ゆうしゅつ,ようしゅつ",
    "meaning": "gushing out, welling up, springing up"
  },
  {
    "question": "救難",
    "answer": "きゅうなん",
    "meaning": "rescue, salvage"
  },
  {
    "question": "始原",
    "answer": "しげん",
    "meaning": "start, origin, beginnings"
  },
  {
    "question": "浄める",
    "answer": "きよめる",
    "meaning": "to purify, to cleanse, to exorcise, to purge, to ward off"
  },
  {
    "question": "常勤",
    "answer": "じょうきん",
    "meaning": "full-time employment"
  },
  {
    "question": "同心",
    "answer": "どうしん",
    "meaning": "concentricity, same mind, unanimity, policeman, constable in the Edo period"
  },
  {
    "question": "漕ぎ手",
    "answer": "こぎて",
    "meaning": "rower, oarsman"
  },
  {
    "question": "陪審員",
    "answer": "ばいしんいん",
    "meaning": "juror, juryman"
  },
  {
    "question": "何となし",
    "answer": "なんとなし",
    "meaning": "somehow or other, for some reason or another"
  },
  {
    "question": "掣肘",
    "answer": "せいちゅう",
    "meaning": "restraint, restriction, control, check"
  },
  {
    "question": "諸般",
    "answer": "しょはん",
    "meaning": "various, several"
  },
  {
    "question": "気象庁",
    "answer": "きしょうちょう",
    "meaning": "(Japanese) Meteorological Agency, JMA"
  },
  {
    "question": "四重",
    "answer": "しじゅう",
    "meaning": "fourfold"
  },
  {
    "question": "有識者",
    "answer": "ゆうしきしゃ",
    "meaning": "expert, knowledgeable person, authority (on a subject)"
  },
  {
    "question": "不貞寝",
    "answer": "ふてね",
    "meaning": "sulking in bed, going to bed in a huff"
  },
  {
    "question": "丸写し",
    "answer": "まるうつし",
    "meaning": "copying in entirety (verbatim)"
  },
  {
    "question": "二次災害",
    "answer": "にじさいがい",
    "meaning": "secondary disaster"
  },
  {
    "question": "擦れ",
    "answer": "すれ",
    "meaning": "chafing, sore, scrape, scratch, mark, rub, rubbing together, blister"
  },
  {
    "question": "梃子",
    "answer": "てこ",
    "meaning": "lever, agent (causing something to happen), instrument, force, assistant, helper"
  },
  {
    "question": "三段目",
    "answer": "さんだんめ",
    "meaning": "third lowest division"
  },
  {
    "question": "青豆",
    "answer": "あおまめ",
    "meaning": "large green soybean, green peas"
  },
  {
    "question": "青藍",
    "answer": "せいらん",
    "meaning": "indigo blue"
  },
  {
    "question": "青島",
    "answer": "",
    "meaning": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "掩護",
    "answer": "えんご",
    "meaning": "covering, protection, backing, relief"
  },
  {
    "question": "天正",
    "answer": "てんしょう",
    "meaning": "Tenshō era (1573.7.28-1592.12.8)"
  },
  {
    "question": "宮家",
    "answer": "みやけ",
    "meaning": "house of a prince of the blood"
  },
  {
    "question": "無能力者",
    "answer": "むのうりょくしゃ",
    "meaning": "incompetent person, incapable person, person without legal capacity"
  },
  {
    "question": "法力",
    "answer": "ほうりき",
    "meaning": "power of Buddhism"
  },
  {
    "question": "耐寒",
    "answer": "たいかん",
    "meaning": "resistance to cold"
  },
  {
    "question": "宗主国",
    "answer": "そうしゅこく",
    "meaning": "suzerain state"
  },
  {
    "question": "無謬",
    "answer": "むびゅう",
    "meaning": "infallibility, inerrancy"
  },
  {
    "question": "竹串",
    "answer": "たけぐし",
    "meaning": "bamboo skewer"
  },
  {
    "question": "重金属",
    "answer": "じゅうきんぞく",
    "meaning": "heavy metals"
  },
  {
    "question": "密使",
    "answer": "みっし",
    "meaning": "secret messenger"
  },
  {
    "question": "帰参",
    "answer": "きさん",
    "meaning": "returning to the service of one's master"
  },
  {
    "question": "養父母",
    "answer": "ようふぼ",
    "meaning": "adoptive parents"
  },
  {
    "question": "雨季",
    "answer": "うき",
    "meaning": "rainy season"
  },
  {
    "question": "永年",
    "answer": "ながねん,えいねん",
    "meaning": "long time, many years"
  },
  {
    "question": "短編小説",
    "answer": "たんぺんしょうせつ",
    "meaning": "short story, novella"
  },
  {
    "question": "累",
    "answer": "るい",
    "meaning": "trouble, harmful effect, evil influence, implication, involvement"
  },
  {
    "question": "内部告発",
    "answer": "ないぶこくはつ",
    "meaning": "whistleblowing"
  },
  {
    "question": "例文",
    "answer": "れいぶん",
    "meaning": "example sentence, illustrative sentence, model sentence"
  },
  {
    "question": "嫋やか",
    "answer": "たおやか",
    "meaning": "willowy, graceful"
  },
  {
    "question": "胃潰瘍",
    "answer": "いかいよう",
    "meaning": "stomach ulcer"
  },
  {
    "question": "念書",
    "answer": "ねんしょ",
    "meaning": "written pledge, signed note of assurance, memorandum, legal instrument"
  },
  {
    "question": "開闢",
    "answer": "かいびゃく,かいひゃく",
    "meaning": "beginning of the world, creation"
  },
  {
    "question": "封ずる",
    "answer": "ふうずる,ほうずる",
    "meaning": "to seal (letter), to prevent, to forbid, to block, to enfeoff"
  },
  {
    "question": "遊離",
    "answer": "ゆうり",
    "meaning": "separation, isolation, extrication, release"
  },
  {
    "question": "凶作",
    "answer": "きょうさく",
    "meaning": "bad harvest, poor crop"
  },
  {
    "question": "子沢山",
    "answer": "こだくさん",
    "meaning": "many children, large family"
  },
  {
    "question": "ベニヤ板",
    "answer": "ベニヤいた",
    "meaning": "plywood"
  },
  {
    "question": "絶対量",
    "answer": "ぜったいりょう",
    "meaning": "absolute amount, absolute quantity"
  },
  {
    "question": "追跡調査",
    "answer": "ついせきちょうさ",
    "meaning": "follow-up (tracing) survey"
  },
  {
    "question": "卵形",
    "answer": "らんけい,たまごがた",
    "meaning": "oval shape, egg shape"
  },
  {
    "question": "統計学",
    "answer": "とうけいがく",
    "meaning": "(the study of) statistics"
  },
  {
    "question": "捧げ物",
    "answer": "ささげもの",
    "meaning": "offering, sacrifice"
  },
  {
    "question": "二枚舌",
    "answer": "にまいじた",
    "meaning": "double-dealing, duplicity, equivocation, double-tongued"
  },
  {
    "question": "鎬を削る",
    "answer": "しのぎをけずる",
    "meaning": "to compete ruthlessly, to sharpen swords"
  },
  {
    "question": "身罷る",
    "answer": "みまかる",
    "meaning": "to pass away, to die"
  },
  {
    "question": "困り切る",
    "answer": "こまりきる",
    "meaning": "to be greatly perplexed, to be at a loss, to be sorely troubled, to be greatly embarrassed"
  },
  {
    "question": "報道機関",
    "answer": "ほうどうきかん",
    "meaning": "information media, press, news organs"
  },
  {
    "question": "隣近所",
    "answer": "となりきんじょ",
    "meaning": "neighbors, neighbours, neighborhood, neighbourhood"
  },
  {
    "question": "切り捨て",
    "answer": "きりすて",
    "meaning": "cutting a person down (without a second thought), sacrificing, throwing to the wolves, treating as s"
  },
  {
    "question": "転位",
    "answer": "てんい",
    "meaning": "transposition, dislocation, rearrangement"
  },
  {
    "question": "銀時計",
    "answer": "ぎんどけい",
    "meaning": "silver watch"
  },
  {
    "question": "陪臣",
    "answer": "ばいしん",
    "meaning": "rear vassal, daimyo's retainer"
  },
  {
    "question": "認識票",
    "answer": "にんしきひょう",
    "meaning": "identification tag"
  },
  {
    "question": "五重塔",
    "answer": "ごじゅうのとう",
    "meaning": "five-storied pagoda"
  },
  {
    "question": "索引",
    "answer": "さくいん",
    "meaning": "index (in a book)"
  },
  {
    "question": "特等",
    "answer": "とくとう",
    "meaning": "special quality, class or grade"
  },
  {
    "question": "内科医",
    "answer": "ないかい",
    "meaning": "physician, internist"
  },
  {
    "question": "無気味",
    "answer": "ぶきみ",
    "meaning": "weird, ominous, eerie, uncanny, ghastly"
  },
  {
    "question": "落下傘",
    "answer": "らっかさん",
    "meaning": "parachute"
  },
  {
    "question": "答礼",
    "answer": "とうれい",
    "meaning": "return of a courtesy, returning one's thanks, return salute, return call"
  },
  {
    "question": "炉心",
    "answer": "ろしん",
    "meaning": "nuclear reactor core"
  },
  {
    "question": "廃城",
    "answer": "はいじょう",
    "meaning": "abandoned castle"
  },
  {
    "question": "反問",
    "answer": "はんもん",
    "meaning": "cross-examination, retort, asking in return"
  },
  {
    "question": "高射砲",
    "answer": "こうしゃほう",
    "meaning": "antiaircraft gun"
  },
  {
    "question": "町役場",
    "answer": "まちやくば",
    "meaning": "town hall"
  },
  {
    "question": "製紙",
    "answer": "せいし",
    "meaning": "papermaking, paper-making, paper making, paper manufacture"
  },
  {
    "question": "糖蜜",
    "answer": "とうみつ",
    "meaning": "molasses, black treacle, (sugar) syrup"
  },
  {
    "question": "賽の目",
    "answer": "さいのめ",
    "meaning": "pip (spot on a die), small cube (esp. of food), die, dice"
  },
  {
    "question": "外来種",
    "answer": "がいらいしゅ",
    "meaning": "introduced species, non-native species, alien species"
  },
  {
    "question": "短小",
    "answer": "たんしょう",
    "meaning": "short and small"
  },
  {
    "question": "今しも",
    "answer": "いましも",
    "meaning": "just now, right now, at this moment"
  },
  {
    "question": "秘めやか",
    "answer": "ひめやか",
    "meaning": "secret"
  },
  {
    "question": "終身",
    "answer": "しゅうしん",
    "meaning": "the whole life"
  },
  {
    "question": "氷枕",
    "answer": "こおりまくら",
    "meaning": "ice pillow"
  },
  {
    "question": "俊英",
    "answer": "しゅんえい",
    "meaning": "excellence, genius"
  },
  {
    "question": "物見高い",
    "answer": "ものみだかい",
    "meaning": "burning curiosity"
  },
  {
    "question": "虚無的",
    "answer": "きょむてき",
    "meaning": "nihilistic"
  },
  {
    "question": "素揚げ",
    "answer": "すあげ",
    "meaning": "deep-frying without breading or batter, food deep-fried without breading or batter"
  },
  {
    "question": "砂漠化",
    "answer": "さばくか",
    "meaning": "desertification"
  },
  {
    "question": "酒量",
    "answer": "しゅりょう",
    "meaning": "amount of drink, one's drinking capacity"
  },
  {
    "question": "自然死",
    "answer": "しぜんし",
    "meaning": "(dying of) natural causes"
  },
  {
    "question": "消臭剤",
    "answer": "しょうしゅうざい",
    "meaning": "deodorant, deodorizer, air freshener"
  },
  {
    "question": "凱歌",
    "answer": "がいか",
    "meaning": "victory song, victory"
  },
  {
    "question": "尊称",
    "answer": "そんしょう",
    "meaning": "honorary title"
  },
  {
    "question": "人身",
    "answer": "じんしん,ひとみ",
    "meaning": "the human body, one's person"
  },
  {
    "question": "鼠色",
    "answer": "ねずみいろ",
    "meaning": "dark gray, dark grey, slate (color, colour)"
  },
  {
    "question": "毛筆",
    "answer": "もうひつ",
    "meaning": "(writing, painting) brush"
  },
  {
    "question": "豪放",
    "answer": "ごうほう",
    "meaning": "largehearted, frank, unaffected"
  },
  {
    "question": "滋味",
    "answer": "じみ",
    "meaning": "nutriment, wholesome, savoriness, savouriness, rich food, nourishment"
  },
  {
    "question": "財政的",
    "answer": "ざいせいてき",
    "meaning": "economic, financial, fiscal"
  },
  {
    "question": "農産物",
    "answer": "のうさんぶつ",
    "meaning": "agricultural produce"
  },
  {
    "question": "苦楽",
    "answer": "くらく",
    "meaning": "pleasure and pain, joys and sorrows"
  },
  {
    "question": "一石",
    "answer": "いっせき,いっこく",
    "meaning": "one game (of go), one koku (measure)"
  },
  {
    "question": "根比べ",
    "answer": "こんくらべ",
    "meaning": "endurance contest, test of endurance"
  },
  {
    "question": "大鎧",
    "answer": "おおよろい",
    "meaning": "box-shaped heavy armour, esp. used on horseback, ō-yoroi"
  },
  {
    "question": "朋輩",
    "answer": "ほうばい",
    "meaning": "comrade, friend, associate, colleague, fellow student, fellow apprentice"
  },
  {
    "question": "舗道",
    "answer": "ほどう",
    "meaning": "pavement, paved street"
  },
  {
    "question": "各層",
    "answer": "かくそう",
    "meaning": "each stratum, each class"
  },
  {
    "question": "屑鉄",
    "answer": "くずてつ",
    "meaning": "scrap iron"
  },
  {
    "question": "遍在",
    "answer": "へんざい",
    "meaning": "omnipresence, ubiquity"
  },
  {
    "question": "駐留軍",
    "answer": "ちゅうりゅうぐん",
    "meaning": "stationed troops"
  },
  {
    "question": "誰誰",
    "answer": "だれだれ",
    "meaning": "so-and-so, who?, which people?"
  },
  {
    "question": "養蜂",
    "answer": "ようほう",
    "meaning": "beekeeping, apiculture"
  },
  {
    "question": "発艦",
    "answer": "はっかん",
    "meaning": "aeroplane taking off from a warship (airplane)"
  },
  {
    "question": "三毛",
    "answer": "みけ",
    "meaning": "calico (pattern), tortoiseshell-and-white, calico cat, tortoiseshell-and-white cat"
  },
  {
    "question": "行員",
    "answer": "こういん",
    "meaning": "bank clerk"
  },
  {
    "question": "覚書",
    "answer": "おぼえがき",
    "meaning": "memo, memorandum, note, (diplomatic) memorandum"
  },
  {
    "question": "仰臥",
    "answer": "ぎょうが",
    "meaning": "lying on one's back, lying face upward, lying supine"
  },
  {
    "question": "先公",
    "answer": "せんこう",
    "meaning": "teacher, previous ruler, previous lord, lord of the previous generation"
  },
  {
    "question": "黄金時代",
    "answer": "おうごんじだい",
    "meaning": "Golden Age"
  },
  {
    "question": "下げ渡す",
    "answer": "さげわたす",
    "meaning": "to make a (government) grant, to release (a criminal)"
  },
  {
    "question": "講評",
    "answer": "こうひょう",
    "meaning": "criticism (by a teacher or coach, with commentary, especially at a poetry reading), review, critique"
  },
  {
    "question": "学籍",
    "answer": "がくせき",
    "meaning": "school register"
  },
  {
    "question": "純化",
    "answer": "じゅんか",
    "meaning": "purification, refining, simplification"
  },
  {
    "question": "雪遊び",
    "answer": "ゆきあそび",
    "meaning": "playing in the snow"
  },
  {
    "question": "三股",
    "answer": "さんまた",
    "meaning": "forked stick"
  },
  {
    "question": "証券会社",
    "answer": "しょうけんがいしゃ",
    "meaning": "brokerage, brokerage firm, broking house, securities company"
  },
  {
    "question": "化学兵器",
    "answer": "かがくへいき",
    "meaning": "chemical weapon"
  },
  {
    "question": "御用聞き",
    "answer": "ごようきき",
    "meaning": "the rounds of tradesmen going door to door, route man, door-to-door tradesman, order taker, order-ta"
  },
  {
    "question": "原子力",
    "answer": "げんしりょく",
    "meaning": "atomic energy, nuclear power"
  },
  {
    "question": "彩度",
    "answer": "さいど",
    "meaning": "chroma, chroma saturation, color saturation (colour)"
  },
  {
    "question": "母堂",
    "answer": "ぼどう",
    "meaning": "your (his) mother"
  },
  {
    "question": "諸氏",
    "answer": "しょし",
    "meaning": "(all of) you or them"
  },
  {
    "question": "猿真似",
    "answer": "さるまね",
    "meaning": "indiscriminate imitation, monkey see, monkey do, blind follower"
  },
  {
    "question": "二重丸",
    "answer": "にじゅうまる",
    "meaning": "double circle (indicating 'very good' on a piece of school work)"
  },
  {
    "question": "魚群",
    "answer": "ぎょぐん",
    "meaning": "school of fish"
  },
  {
    "question": "鈍臭い",
    "answer": "どんくさい,のろくさい",
    "meaning": "slow, clumsy, stupid, irritating"
  },
  {
    "question": "加湿器",
    "answer": "かしつき",
    "meaning": "humidifier"
  },
  {
    "question": "血腥い",
    "answer": "ちなまぐさい",
    "meaning": "reeking of blood, stinking of blood, bloody (battle, crime, etc.)"
  },
  {
    "question": "啜り泣き",
    "answer": "すすりなき",
    "meaning": "sobbing, sob, weeping"
  },
  {
    "question": "転換期",
    "answer": "てんかんき",
    "meaning": "turning point, transition phase"
  },
  {
    "question": "細切り",
    "answer": "こまぎり,ほそぎり",
    "meaning": "chopping finely, slicing up finely, something chopped up finely, thin strips, matchstick-like strips"
  },
  {
    "question": "動物性",
    "answer": "どうぶつせい",
    "meaning": "animal (in nature), animal (in origin)"
  },
  {
    "question": "陳謝",
    "answer": "ちんしゃ",
    "meaning": "apology"
  },
  {
    "question": "迷わす",
    "answer": "まよわす",
    "meaning": "to puzzle, to perplex, to bewilder, to delude, to mislead, to fascinate"
  },
  {
    "question": "日刊",
    "answer": "にっかん",
    "meaning": "daily publication, daily issue"
  },
  {
    "question": "金木犀",
    "answer": "きんもくせい",
    "meaning": "fragrant olive (Osmanthus fragrans var. aurantiacus)"
  },
  {
    "question": "鉄鉱",
    "answer": "てっこう",
    "meaning": "iron ore"
  },
  {
    "question": "欅",
    "answer": "けやき",
    "meaning": "Japanese zelkova (species of elm-like tree, Zelkowa serrata)"
  },
  {
    "question": "蚊帳",
    "answer": "かや,かちょう,ぶんちょう",
    "meaning": "mosquito net"
  },
  {
    "question": "暮し",
    "answer": "くらし",
    "meaning": "life, living, livelihood, life circumstances"
  },
  {
    "question": "水星",
    "answer": "すいせい",
    "meaning": "Mercury (planet)"
  },
  {
    "question": "絶対音感",
    "answer": "ぜったいおんかん",
    "meaning": "absolute pitch, perfect pitch"
  },
  {
    "question": "剣法",
    "answer": "けんぽう",
    "meaning": "(art of) fencing, swordsmanship"
  },
  {
    "question": "敵勢",
    "answer": "てきせい,てきぜい",
    "meaning": "enemy's strength or fighting power"
  },
  {
    "question": "参内",
    "answer": "さんだい",
    "meaning": "palace visit"
  },
  {
    "question": "蚯蚓",
    "answer": "みみず,めめず,きゅういん",
    "meaning": "earthworm"
  },
  {
    "question": "生活保護",
    "answer": "せいかつほご",
    "meaning": "livelihood protection, public assistance, welfare"
  },
  {
    "question": "狂奔",
    "answer": "きょうほん",
    "meaning": "rushing around, running wild"
  },
  {
    "question": "公示",
    "answer": "こうじ,こうし",
    "meaning": "edict, public announcement"
  },
  {
    "question": "行儀作法",
    "answer": "ぎょうぎさほう",
    "meaning": "etiquette, good manners"
  },
  {
    "question": "闇市場",
    "answer": "やみしじょう",
    "meaning": "black market"
  },
  {
    "question": "気炎",
    "answer": "きえん",
    "meaning": "high spirits, boastful talk"
  },
  {
    "question": "批評家",
    "answer": "ひひょうか",
    "meaning": "critic"
  },
  {
    "question": "末子",
    "answer": "ばっし,まっし,すえこ",
    "meaning": "youngest child"
  },
  {
    "question": "千日手",
    "answer": "せんにちて",
    "meaning": "repetition of position (in chess, shogi, etc.), repetition draw"
  },
  {
    "question": "誑し込む",
    "answer": "たらしこむ",
    "meaning": "to cajole, to deceive, to seduce"
  },
  {
    "question": "酢の物",
    "answer": "すのもの",
    "meaning": "vinegared dish, pickled dish"
  },
  {
    "question": "不均衡",
    "answer": "ふきんこう",
    "meaning": "imbalance, lack of balance, lopsidedness, disproportion, inequality, disparity"
  },
  {
    "question": "英気",
    "answer": "えいき",
    "meaning": "great wisdom, excellent disposition, strength (to face something), willpower, vigor, vigour, energy"
  },
  {
    "question": "梅雨時",
    "answer": "つゆどき",
    "meaning": "wet season, rainy season"
  },
  {
    "question": "糖度",
    "answer": "とうど",
    "meaning": "sugar content (e.g. in degrees Brix)"
  },
  {
    "question": "細胞分裂",
    "answer": "さいぼうぶんれつ",
    "meaning": "cell division"
  },
  {
    "question": "鎮魂歌",
    "answer": "ちんこんか",
    "meaning": "requiem"
  },
  {
    "question": "客観性",
    "answer": "きゃっかんせい",
    "meaning": "objectivity"
  },
  {
    "question": "不案内",
    "answer": "ふあんない",
    "meaning": "ignorance, inexperience, unfamiliarity"
  },
  {
    "question": "道徳心",
    "answer": "どうとくしん",
    "meaning": "moral sense"
  },
  {
    "question": "午後一",
    "answer": "ごごいち",
    "meaning": "first thing in the afternoon"
  },
  {
    "question": "身辺整理",
    "answer": "しんぺんせいり",
    "meaning": "putting one's affairs in order, ordering one's affairs, tidying up"
  },
  {
    "question": "血盟",
    "answer": "けつめい",
    "meaning": "blood pledge, oath signed in blood"
  },
  {
    "question": "特攻隊",
    "answer": "とっこうたい",
    "meaning": "special attack unit, kamikaze unit, suicide squad"
  },
  {
    "question": "瑞穂",
    "answer": "",
    "meaning": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "橋上",
    "answer": "きょうじょう",
    "meaning": "(on the) bridge"
  },
  {
    "question": "十八禁",
    "answer": "じゅうはちきん",
    "meaning": "18 certificate, R-18, restricted to those 18 years or older"
  },
  {
    "question": "進駐",
    "answer": "しんちゅう",
    "meaning": "occupation, stationing"
  },
  {
    "question": "残り滓",
    "answer": "のこりかす",
    "meaning": "residue, remnants, dregs"
  },
  {
    "question": "福袋",
    "answer": "ふくぶくろ",
    "meaning": "lucky-dip bag, grab bag, mystery package (with a variety of articles possibly worth more than the pu"
  },
  {
    "question": "化粧箱",
    "answer": "けしょうばこ",
    "meaning": "vanity case, cosmetics case"
  },
  {
    "question": "署員",
    "answer": "しょいん",
    "meaning": "staff member, station employee, official"
  },
  {
    "question": "賊軍",
    "answer": "ぞくぐん",
    "meaning": "rebel army"
  },
  {
    "question": "喝破",
    "answer": "かっぱ",
    "meaning": "arguing someone down, scolding, rebuking, proclaiming (the truth), expounding"
  },
  {
    "question": "雪雲",
    "answer": "ゆきぐも",
    "meaning": "snow-laden clouds"
  },
  {
    "question": "型式",
    "answer": "かたしき,けいしき",
    "meaning": "model (e.g. of a vehicle), type"
  },
  {
    "question": "日本時間",
    "answer": "にほんじかん",
    "meaning": "Japan time, Japan Standard Time, JST"
  },
  {
    "question": "劇作家",
    "answer": "げきさっか",
    "meaning": "playwright, dramatist"
  },
  {
    "question": "内角",
    "answer": "ないかく",
    "meaning": "interior angle, internal angle, inside corner"
  },
  {
    "question": "会計士",
    "answer": "かいけいし",
    "meaning": "accountant"
  },
  {
    "question": "液体窒素",
    "answer": "えきたいちっそ",
    "meaning": "liquid nitrogen"
  },
  {
    "question": "職業訓練",
    "answer": "しょくぎょうくんれん",
    "meaning": "job (work) training (for the unskilled)"
  },
  {
    "question": "見分",
    "answer": "けんぶん",
    "meaning": "inspection, examination, survey"
  },
  {
    "question": "波頭",
    "answer": "なみがしら,はとう",
    "meaning": "wave crest, whitecaps"
  },
  {
    "question": "狂宴",
    "answer": "きょうえん",
    "meaning": "revelry, tumultuous party, wild party, uproarious banquet"
  },
  {
    "question": "当て付け",
    "answer": "あてつけ",
    "meaning": "something done out of spite, snide remark, insinuation, innuendo, dig"
  },
  {
    "question": "竜馬",
    "answer": "りゅうめ",
    "meaning": "splendid horse, promoted bishop"
  },
  {
    "question": "連接",
    "answer": "れんせつ",
    "meaning": "connection, link (on a web page)"
  },
  {
    "question": "捕手",
    "answer": "ほしゅ,とりて",
    "meaning": "catcher, policeman, official in charge of imprisoning offenders, art of defeating (and capturing) an"
  },
  {
    "question": "砲術",
    "answer": "ほうじゅつ",
    "meaning": "gunnery, artillery"
  },
  {
    "question": "軍刀",
    "answer": "ぐんとう",
    "meaning": "military sword, saber, sabre"
  },
  {
    "question": "伝導率",
    "answer": "でんどうりつ",
    "meaning": "conductivity"
  },
  {
    "question": "普請",
    "answer": "ふしん",
    "meaning": "building, construction, group effort by Buddhist practitioners, group activities by a community (e.g"
  },
  {
    "question": "幟",
    "answer": "のぼり",
    "meaning": "flag, banner, streamer"
  },
  {
    "question": "農機具",
    "answer": "のうきぐ",
    "meaning": "agricultural machinery and equipment"
  },
  {
    "question": "姪御",
    "answer": "めいご",
    "meaning": "(another person's) niece"
  },
  {
    "question": "皮下",
    "answer": "ひか",
    "meaning": "subcutaneous"
  },
  {
    "question": "形而上",
    "answer": "けいじじょう",
    "meaning": "metaphysical"
  },
  {
    "question": "献策",
    "answer": "けんさく",
    "meaning": "suggestion, proposal"
  },
  {
    "question": "競走馬",
    "answer": "きょうそうば",
    "meaning": "racehorse"
  },
  {
    "question": "秘事",
    "answer": "ひじ",
    "meaning": "secret"
  },
  {
    "question": "整体",
    "answer": "せいたい",
    "meaning": "seitai, manipulative therapy based on Chinese and Japanese traditions, and encompassing osteopathy,"
  },
  {
    "question": "泥んこ",
    "answer": "どろんこ",
    "meaning": "mud, muddy, covered in mud"
  },
  {
    "question": "合理主義",
    "answer": "ごうりしゅぎ",
    "meaning": "rationalism"
  },
  {
    "question": "晴々",
    "answer": "せいせい,はればれ",
    "meaning": "feeling refreshed, feeling relieved, bright, cheerful"
  },
  {
    "question": "誅する",
    "answer": "ちゅうする",
    "meaning": "to put to death"
  },
  {
    "question": "摩擦音",
    "answer": "まさつおん",
    "meaning": "fricative, fricative consonant"
  },
  {
    "question": "入刀",
    "answer": "にゅうとう",
    "meaning": "cutting the cake (at a wedding)"
  },
  {
    "question": "水彩画",
    "answer": "すいさいが",
    "meaning": "watercolor painting, watercolour painting"
  },
  {
    "question": "虫がいい",
    "answer": "むしがいい",
    "meaning": "selfish, asking too much"
  },
  {
    "question": "正否",
    "answer": "せいひ",
    "meaning": "right and wrong"
  },
  {
    "question": "梅雨明け",
    "answer": "つゆあけ",
    "meaning": "end of the rainy season"
  },
  {
    "question": "一糸",
    "answer": "いっし",
    "meaning": "thread, strand, string"
  },
  {
    "question": "自己矛盾",
    "answer": "じこむじゅん",
    "meaning": "self-contradiction, paradox, antinomy"
  },
  {
    "question": "一樹",
    "answer": "いちじゅ,いっき",
    "meaning": "one tree, a tree"
  },
  {
    "question": "吃音",
    "answer": "きつおん",
    "meaning": "stammering, stuttering, dysphemia"
  },
  {
    "question": "祖霊",
    "answer": "それい",
    "meaning": "ancestral spirit, collective of ancestral spirits which have lost their individualities, ancestor de"
  },
  {
    "question": "副砲",
    "answer": "ふくほう",
    "meaning": "secondary armament (of a warship), secondary battery, secondary gun"
  },
  {
    "question": "酉",
    "answer": "とり",
    "meaning": "the Rooster (tenth sign of the Chinese zodiac), the Cock, the Chicken, the Bird, hour of the Rooster"
  },
  {
    "question": "卒アル",
    "answer": "そつアル",
    "meaning": "classbook, yearbook, school graduation album"
  },
  {
    "question": "身許",
    "answer": "みもと",
    "meaning": "person's identity, ID, past, background"
  },
  {
    "question": "陣幕",
    "answer": "じんまく",
    "meaning": "camp enclosure"
  },
  {
    "question": "座薬",
    "answer": "ざやく",
    "meaning": "suppository"
  },
  {
    "question": "目出し帽",
    "answer": "めだしぼう",
    "meaning": "ski mask, balaclava"
  },
  {
    "question": "うさ耳",
    "answer": "うさみみ",
    "meaning": "bunny-ears headband"
  },
  {
    "question": "若衆",
    "answer": "わかしゅ,わかしゅう",
    "meaning": "young man (in the Edo period, esp. one with forelocks who has not yet had his coming-of-age ceremony"
  },
  {
    "question": "顔貌",
    "answer": "かおかたち,がんぼう",
    "meaning": "features, looks"
  },
  {
    "question": "小作人",
    "answer": "こさくにん",
    "meaning": "tenant farmer"
  },
  {
    "question": "成獣",
    "answer": "せいじゅう",
    "meaning": "adult animal"
  },
  {
    "question": "弑逆",
    "answer": "しぎゃく,しいぎゃく",
    "meaning": "murder of one's own lord or father"
  },
  {
    "question": "試用期間",
    "answer": "しようきかん",
    "meaning": "evaluation period (software, new employee, etc.), trial period, probation period"
  },
  {
    "question": "濃茶",
    "answer": "こいちゃ",
    "meaning": "koicha, exceptionally dark, opaque matcha"
  },
  {
    "question": "保証金",
    "answer": "ほしょうきん",
    "meaning": "deposit (esp. on renting a house), security money, bond payment, guarantee"
  },
  {
    "question": "食客",
    "answer": "しょっかく,しょっきゃく",
    "meaning": "free-loader, hanger-on, parasite, house guest"
  },
  {
    "question": "肉色",
    "answer": "にくいろ",
    "meaning": "flesh-color, flesh-colour"
  },
  {
    "question": "交感神経",
    "answer": "こうかんしんけい",
    "meaning": "sympathetic nerves"
  },
  {
    "question": "消化液",
    "answer": "しょうかえき",
    "meaning": "digestive fluids"
  },
  {
    "question": "生水",
    "answer": "なまみず",
    "meaning": "unboiled water"
  },
  {
    "question": "愚挙",
    "answer": "ぐきょ",
    "meaning": "foolish undertaking"
  },
  {
    "question": "共存共栄",
    "answer": "きょうそんきょうえい,きょうぞんきょうえい",
    "meaning": "co-existence and co-prosperity"
  },
  {
    "question": "ひ弱い",
    "answer": "ひよわい",
    "meaning": "weak, sickly"
  },
  {
    "question": "類型",
    "answer": "るいけい",
    "meaning": "type, pattern, shape, genre, breed, similar type, similar pattern"
  },
  {
    "question": "極北",
    "answer": "きょくほく",
    "meaning": "extreme north, North Pole"
  },
  {
    "question": "編み目",
    "answer": "あみめ",
    "meaning": "stitch"
  },
  {
    "question": "破れ目",
    "answer": "やぶれめ,やれめ,われめ",
    "meaning": "rent, tear, split, chasm, interstice, crevice, crack, cleft, rift, fissure, vulva, slit, cunt, vagin"
  },
  {
    "question": "論者",
    "answer": "ろんしゃ,ろんじゃ",
    "meaning": "advocate, disputant, debater, (present) writer, author"
  },
  {
    "question": "積載量",
    "answer": "せきさいりょう",
    "meaning": "loading capacity"
  },
  {
    "question": "小春日和",
    "answer": "こはるびより",
    "meaning": "Indian summer (around November), mild late autumn weather, mild late fall weather"
  },
  {
    "question": "偏頭痛",
    "answer": "へんずつう,へんとうつう",
    "meaning": "migraine"
  },
  {
    "question": "山の幸",
    "answer": "やまのさち",
    "meaning": "food of the mountains (wild game, mountain vegetables, mushrooms, etc.), fruits of the land"
  },
  {
    "question": "難聴",
    "answer": "なんちょう",
    "meaning": "hardness of hearing, bradyacusia, deafness, hearing loss"
  },
  {
    "question": "関連会社",
    "answer": "かんれんがいしゃ",
    "meaning": "associated company"
  },
  {
    "question": "一挙両得",
    "answer": "いっきょりょうとく",
    "meaning": "killing two birds with one stone, serving two ends"
  },
  {
    "question": "振り幅",
    "answer": "ふりはば",
    "meaning": "amplitude"
  },
  {
    "question": "誰彼",
    "answer": "だれかれ,たれかれ",
    "meaning": "this or that person, anybody, many people"
  },
  {
    "question": "遊び仲間",
    "answer": "あそびなかま",
    "meaning": "playmate"
  },
  {
    "question": "遠め",
    "answer": "とおめ",
    "meaning": "somewhat far, fairly distant"
  },
  {
    "question": "入り浸り",
    "answer": "いりびたり",
    "meaning": "frequenting, staying around"
  },
  {
    "question": "絵羽",
    "answer": "えば",
    "meaning": "figured, patterned, figured haori (coat)"
  },
  {
    "question": "宮女",
    "answer": "きゅうじょ,みやおんな",
    "meaning": "female court attendant, court lady"
  },
  {
    "question": "沼田",
    "answer": "ぬまた,ぬまだ",
    "meaning": "marshy rice field or paddy"
  },
  {
    "question": "海上都市",
    "answer": "かいじょうとし",
    "meaning": "artificial island city, floating city"
  },
  {
    "question": "船大工",
    "answer": "ふなだいく",
    "meaning": "shipwright, boatbuilder"
  },
  {
    "question": "牛舎",
    "answer": "ぎゅうしゃ",
    "meaning": "cow shed, cattle barn"
  },
  {
    "question": "旗本",
    "answer": "はたもと",
    "meaning": "shogunal vassal, direct retainer of a shogun"
  },
  {
    "question": "荷揚げ",
    "answer": "にあげ",
    "meaning": "unloading, landing"
  },
  {
    "question": "桂",
    "answer": "かつら,けい",
    "meaning": "katsura (Cercidiphyllum japonicum), Japanese Judas tree, knight"
  },
  {
    "question": "冥王星",
    "answer": "めいおうせい",
    "meaning": "Pluto (dwarf planet)"
  },
  {
    "question": "黄泉路",
    "answer": "よみじ",
    "meaning": "road to Hades"
  },
  {
    "question": "茅",
    "answer": "かや,ちがや,ち",
    "meaning": "grass used for thatching, sedge used for thatching, cogon grass (Imperata cylindrica)"
  },
  {
    "question": "仕込み杖",
    "answer": "しこみづえ",
    "meaning": "sword cane"
  },
  {
    "question": "格子窓",
    "answer": "こうしまど",
    "meaning": "latticed window"
  },
  {
    "question": "小犬",
    "answer": "こいぬ",
    "meaning": "puppy, small dog"
  },
  {
    "question": "人工生命",
    "answer": "じんこうせいめい",
    "meaning": "artificial life"
  },
  {
    "question": "震源",
    "answer": "しんげん",
    "meaning": "hypocentre (of an earthquake), hypocenter"
  },
  {
    "question": "受胎",
    "answer": "じゅたい",
    "meaning": "conception, fertilization, fertilisation"
  },
  {
    "question": "愚妹",
    "answer": "ぐまい",
    "meaning": "younger sister"
  },
  {
    "question": "雨滴",
    "answer": "うてき",
    "meaning": "raindrop"
  },
  {
    "question": "鏡餅",
    "answer": "かがみもち",
    "meaning": "kagami mochi, New Year offering consisting of two mochi stacked on each other with a bitter orange o"
  },
  {
    "question": "五七",
    "answer": "ごしち",
    "meaning": "five and seven, 35th day after a person's death"
  },
  {
    "question": "一期",
    "answer": "いちご,いっき",
    "meaning": "one's whole life, one's lifetime, one term, one period, first term, first period"
  },
  {
    "question": "愛国",
    "answer": "あいこく",
    "meaning": "love of (one's) country, patriotism"
  },
  {
    "question": "村内",
    "answer": "そんない",
    "meaning": "interior of a village"
  },
  {
    "question": "天下り",
    "answer": "あまくだり",
    "meaning": "retiring high-ranking government officials taking a lucrative job in a private or semi-private corpo"
  },
  {
    "question": "保釈",
    "answer": "ほしゃく",
    "meaning": "bail, releasing on bail"
  },
  {
    "question": "老木",
    "answer": "ろうぼく",
    "meaning": "old tree"
  },
  {
    "question": "悪罵",
    "answer": "あくば",
    "meaning": "curse, vilification"
  },
  {
    "question": "射角",
    "answer": "しゃかく",
    "meaning": "angle of fire"
  },
  {
    "question": "戸板",
    "answer": "といた",
    "meaning": "sliding door (esp. when removed from its frame and used for carrying things or people), large flound"
  },
  {
    "question": "夏草",
    "answer": "なつくさ,なつぐさ",
    "meaning": "summer grass"
  },
  {
    "question": "言説",
    "answer": "げんせつ",
    "meaning": "remark, statement, discourse"
  },
  {
    "question": "敵前",
    "answer": "てきぜん",
    "meaning": "in the face of the enemy, before the enemy"
  },
  {
    "question": "囲い込み",
    "answer": "かこいこみ",
    "meaning": "enclosure"
  },
  {
    "question": "登記",
    "answer": "とうき",
    "meaning": "registry, registration"
  },
  {
    "question": "今日日",
    "answer": "きょうび",
    "meaning": "nowadays"
  },
  {
    "question": "土葬",
    "answer": "どそう",
    "meaning": "burial, interment"
  },
  {
    "question": "五重",
    "answer": "いつえ,ごじゅう",
    "meaning": "five-storied, quintuplicate, fivefold"
  },
  {
    "question": "軟着陸",
    "answer": "なんちゃくりく",
    "meaning": "soft-landing"
  },
  {
    "question": "相続権",
    "answer": "そうぞくけん",
    "meaning": "heirship, (claim) the (right of) succession, one's inheritance rights"
  },
  {
    "question": "正三角形",
    "answer": "せいさんかくけい,せいさんかっけい",
    "meaning": "equilateral triangle, regular triangle"
  },
  {
    "question": "逆説",
    "answer": "ぎゃくせつ",
    "meaning": "paradox"
  },
  {
    "question": "続発",
    "answer": "ぞくはつ",
    "meaning": "successive occurrence, frequent occurrence, succession (of), series"
  },
  {
    "question": "折々",
    "answer": "おりおり",
    "meaning": "occasionally, now and then, from time to time"
  },
  {
    "question": "自然光",
    "answer": "しぜんこう",
    "meaning": "natural light, unpolarized light"
  },
  {
    "question": "心肺",
    "answer": "しんぱい,しんはい",
    "meaning": "heart and lungs, cardiopulmonary, heart and lung machine"
  },
  {
    "question": "薄明るい",
    "answer": "うすあかるい",
    "meaning": "slightly bright"
  },
  {
    "question": "泣き付く",
    "answer": "なきつく",
    "meaning": "to cling to ... in tears, to beg ... in tears, to appeal, to throw oneself on someone's mercy"
  },
  {
    "question": "至言",
    "answer": "しげん",
    "meaning": "wise saying"
  },
  {
    "question": "庇い立て",
    "answer": "かばいだて,かばいたて",
    "meaning": "protecting (someone), defending, standing up for"
  },
  {
    "question": "満ち引き",
    "answer": "みちひき",
    "meaning": "ebb and flow"
  },
  {
    "question": "水飲み",
    "answer": "みずのみ",
    "meaning": "(act of) drinking water, (water) drinking container, glass, tumbler, peasant"
  },
  {
    "question": "諒",
    "answer": "りょう",
    "meaning": "fact, truth, understanding, consideration"
  },
  {
    "question": "如意",
    "answer": "にょい",
    "meaning": "going according to one's wishes, ceremonial sceptre used by monks when reciting sutras (scepter)"
  },
  {
    "question": "水無月",
    "answer": "みなづき,みなつき",
    "meaning": "sixth month of the lunar calendar (approx. July), June, sixth month of Gregorian calendar, triangles"
  },
  {
    "question": "石斧",
    "answer": "せきふ",
    "meaning": "stone axe (ax)"
  },
  {
    "question": "校医",
    "answer": "こうい",
    "meaning": "school doctor"
  },
  {
    "question": "遺灰",
    "answer": "いはい",
    "meaning": "ashes (of the deceased), remains from cremation"
  },
  {
    "question": "改悪",
    "answer": "かいあく",
    "meaning": "deterioration, changing for the worse"
  },
  {
    "question": "進発",
    "answer": "しんぱつ",
    "meaning": "start, leaving, marching off"
  },
  {
    "question": "南岸",
    "answer": "なんがん",
    "meaning": "south coast, south bank"
  },
  {
    "question": "菌糸",
    "answer": "きんし",
    "meaning": "fungal filament, hypha, hyphae"
  },
  {
    "question": "胸郭",
    "answer": "きょうかく",
    "meaning": "chest, thorax"
  },
  {
    "question": "古井戸",
    "answer": "ふるいど",
    "meaning": "old unused well"
  },
  {
    "question": "関数",
    "answer": "かんすう",
    "meaning": "function, function (programming)"
  },
  {
    "question": "重曹",
    "answer": "じゅうそう",
    "meaning": "baking soda, sodium bicarbonate"
  },
  {
    "question": "山の手",
    "answer": "やまのて",
    "meaning": "hilly section of a city (usu. residential), Yamanote (hilly residential section of western Tokyo, in"
  },
  {
    "question": "荒れ野",
    "answer": "あれの",
    "meaning": "wasteland, wilderness, deserted land, prairie, vast plain, wilds, desert, wild land"
  },
  {
    "question": "連弾",
    "answer": "れんだん",
    "meaning": "four handed performance (on the piano)"
  },
  {
    "question": "獣毛",
    "answer": "じゅうもう",
    "meaning": "animal hair"
  },
  {
    "question": "落命",
    "answer": "らくめい",
    "meaning": "losing one's life, death"
  },
  {
    "question": "鋼線",
    "answer": "こうせん",
    "meaning": "steel wire"
  },
  {
    "question": "民事",
    "answer": "みんじ",
    "meaning": "civil affairs, civil case"
  },
  {
    "question": "検温",
    "answer": "けんおん",
    "meaning": "temperature measurement"
  },
  {
    "question": "補助輪",
    "answer": "ほじょりん",
    "meaning": "training wheels, stabilizers"
  },
  {
    "question": "無頼漢",
    "answer": "ぶらいかん,ならずもの",
    "meaning": "ruffian, villain, scoundrel"
  },
  {
    "question": "一線級",
    "answer": "いっせんきゅう",
    "meaning": "top notch, first rate, top-of-the-line, leading"
  },
  {
    "question": "両雄",
    "answer": "りょうゆう",
    "meaning": "two great men (rivals)"
  },
  {
    "question": "前衛芸術",
    "answer": "ぜんえいげいじゅつ",
    "meaning": "avant-garde art"
  },
  {
    "question": "脇目",
    "answer": "わきめ",
    "meaning": "looking aside, (from the) eyes of an onlooker"
  },
  {
    "question": "無味",
    "answer": "むみ",
    "meaning": "tasteless, flavourless, uninteresting, dull, dry, insipid"
  },
  {
    "question": "飲み歩く",
    "answer": "のみあるく",
    "meaning": "to go bar-hopping, to go on a pub crawl"
  },
  {
    "question": "夕霧",
    "answer": "ゆうぎり,せきむ",
    "meaning": "evening mist"
  },
  {
    "question": "亜門",
    "answer": "あもん",
    "meaning": "subphylum, subdivision"
  },
  {
    "question": "管領",
    "answer": "かんりょう",
    "meaning": "(person in) control"
  },
  {
    "question": "官女",
    "answer": "かんじょ",
    "meaning": "court lady"
  },
  {
    "question": "奇譚",
    "answer": "きたん",
    "meaning": "mysterious story"
  },
  {
    "question": "捕球",
    "answer": "ほきゅう",
    "meaning": "catch"
  },
  {
    "question": "淫語",
    "answer": "いんご",
    "meaning": "indecent language, dirty talk"
  },
  {
    "question": "室町",
    "answer": "むろまち",
    "meaning": "Muromachi (era 1392-1573, or 1333-1573, or 1336-1573)"
  },
  {
    "question": "揺籃",
    "answer": "ゆりかご,ようらん",
    "meaning": "cradle"
  },
  {
    "question": "往還",
    "answer": "おうかん",
    "meaning": "traffic, coming and going, highway"
  },
  {
    "question": "黒い雨",
    "answer": "くろいあめ",
    "meaning": "heavily polluted, radioactive rain sometimes following an atmospheric nuclear explosion (esp. that o"
  },
  {
    "question": "巻貝",
    "answer": "まきがい",
    "meaning": "snail, spiral shell"
  },
  {
    "question": "ユダヤ人",
    "answer": "ユダヤじん",
    "meaning": "Jew, Jewish person"
  },
  {
    "question": "医科大学",
    "answer": "いかだいがく",
    "meaning": "medical school"
  },
  {
    "question": "保養所",
    "answer": "ほようじょ,ほようしょ",
    "meaning": "sanatorium, rest home"
  },
  {
    "question": "帰化",
    "answer": "きか",
    "meaning": "naturalization, naturalisation"
  },
  {
    "question": "長姉",
    "answer": "ちょうし",
    "meaning": "eldest sister, oldest sister"
  },
  {
    "question": "銚子",
    "answer": "ちょうし",
    "meaning": "(sake) decanter"
  },
  {
    "question": "賃料",
    "answer": "ちんりょう",
    "meaning": "rent, rental"
  },
  {
    "question": "研究生",
    "answer": "けんきゅうせい",
    "meaning": "research student"
  },
  {
    "question": "恥毛",
    "answer": "ちもう",
    "meaning": "pubic hair"
  },
  {
    "question": "暫時",
    "answer": "ざんじ",
    "meaning": "short while"
  },
  {
    "question": "懐中",
    "answer": "かいちゅう",
    "meaning": "one's pocket"
  },
  {
    "question": "乳母車",
    "answer": "うばぐるま",
    "meaning": "baby carriage, perambulator, pram"
  },
  {
    "question": "土石流",
    "answer": "どせきりゅう",
    "meaning": "avalanche of earth and rocks"
  },
  {
    "question": "白痴",
    "answer": "はくち,たわけ",
    "meaning": "idiot, retard, idiocy, profound mental retardation, tomfoolery, foolish act, nonsense, fool"
  },
  {
    "question": "凡愚",
    "answer": "ぼんぐ",
    "meaning": "common person, foolish commoner"
  },
  {
    "question": "売買契約",
    "answer": "ばいばいけいやく",
    "meaning": "contract for (of) sale"
  },
  {
    "question": "思い当る",
    "answer": "おもいあたる",
    "meaning": "to suddenly understand (esp. on basis of experience or memory), to come to mind, to recall (in a fla"
  },
  {
    "question": "手描き",
    "answer": "てがき",
    "meaning": "handwriting, handwritten, hand-painted, hand-drawn"
  },
  {
    "question": "洋書",
    "answer": "ようしょ",
    "meaning": "Western book"
  },
  {
    "question": "事大",
    "answer": "じだい",
    "meaning": "subserviency to the stronger"
  },
  {
    "question": "対向車線",
    "answer": "たいこうしゃせん",
    "meaning": "opposite lane, oncoming lane, opposite side of the road"
  },
  {
    "question": "俸給",
    "answer": "ほうきゅう",
    "meaning": "salary (esp. public employees), wages, pay"
  },
  {
    "question": "産気づく",
    "answer": "さんけづく",
    "meaning": "to go into labor, to go into labour"
  },
  {
    "question": "敬具",
    "answer": "けいぐ",
    "meaning": "Yours sincerely, Yours truly, Sincerely yours"
  },
  {
    "question": "時を稼ぐ",
    "answer": "ときをかせぐ",
    "meaning": "to play for time, to use delaying tactics"
  },
  {
    "question": "明くる日",
    "answer": "あくるひ",
    "meaning": "next day, following day"
  },
  {
    "question": "陰性",
    "answer": "いんせい",
    "meaning": "negative"
  },
  {
    "question": "独占的",
    "answer": "どくせんてき",
    "meaning": "monopolistic"
  },
  {
    "question": "保養",
    "answer": "ほよう",
    "meaning": "health preservation, recuperation, recreation"
  },
  {
    "question": "聖徳",
    "answer": "せいとく",
    "meaning": "imperial virtue, heavenly virtue, greatest virtue, highest virtue"
  },
  {
    "question": "冬木",
    "answer": "ふゆき,ふゆぎ",
    "meaning": "tree as seen in winter (esp. a barren deciduous tree), evergreen tree"
  },
  {
    "question": "異称",
    "answer": "いしょう",
    "meaning": "another name"
  },
  {
    "question": "蓼",
    "answer": "たで",
    "meaning": "knotweed (Polygonaceae), jointweed, smartweed, water pepper (Persicaria hydropiper)"
  },
  {
    "question": "二塁",
    "answer": "にるい",
    "meaning": "second base"
  },
  {
    "question": "帳場",
    "answer": "ちょうば",
    "meaning": "(hotel) reception"
  },
  {
    "question": "民主化",
    "answer": "みんしゅか",
    "meaning": "democratization, democratisation"
  },
  {
    "question": "豚足",
    "answer": "とんそく",
    "meaning": "pig's feet"
  },
  {
    "question": "領事館",
    "answer": "りょうじかん",
    "meaning": "consulate"
  },
  {
    "question": "半導体",
    "answer": "はんどうたい",
    "meaning": "semiconductor, solid-state"
  },
  {
    "question": "風刺",
    "answer": "ふうし",
    "meaning": "satire, irony, sarcasm"
  },
  {
    "question": "染色体",
    "answer": "せんしょくたい",
    "meaning": "chromosome"
  },
  {
    "question": "特需",
    "answer": "とくじゅ",
    "meaning": "emergency demands, special procurement (particularly in time of war)"
  },
  {
    "question": "低地",
    "answer": "ていち",
    "meaning": "depression, lowlands, low ground, bottom land, plain"
  },
  {
    "question": "緊急発進",
    "answer": "きんきゅうはっしん",
    "meaning": "scrambling, scramble"
  },
  {
    "question": "白星",
    "answer": "しろぼし",
    "meaning": "white circle, white star, victory mark"
  },
  {
    "question": "南風",
    "answer": "なんぷう,みなみかぜ,はえ",
    "meaning": "south wind, southerly wind, summer"
  },
  {
    "question": "工法",
    "answer": "こうほう",
    "meaning": "method of construction"
  },
  {
    "question": "小六",
    "answer": "しょうろく",
    "meaning": "sixth year of elementary school, sixth year elementary school student"
  },
  {
    "question": "公判",
    "answer": "こうはん",
    "meaning": "public hearing, trial"
  },
  {
    "question": "座位",
    "answer": "ざい",
    "meaning": "sitting position"
  },
  {
    "question": "領空",
    "answer": "りょうくう",
    "meaning": "territorial airspace"
  },
  {
    "question": "宿泊所",
    "answer": "しゅくはくじょ",
    "meaning": "lodgings, quarters"
  },
  {
    "question": "開館",
    "answer": "かいかん",
    "meaning": "opening (for that day's business; of a library, museum, cinema, etc.), opening (of a new library, mu"
  },
  {
    "question": "代理店",
    "answer": "だいりてん",
    "meaning": "agent, agency"
  },
  {
    "question": "村外れ",
    "answer": "むらはずれ",
    "meaning": "edge of town, outskirts of a village"
  },
  {
    "question": "数え",
    "answer": "かぞえ",
    "meaning": "East Asian age reckoning, traditional system of age reckoning whereby newborns are considered one ye"
  },
  {
    "question": "黒帯",
    "answer": "くろおび",
    "meaning": "black belt (judo, karate, etc.)"
  },
  {
    "question": "縁石",
    "answer": "えんせき,ふちいし,へりいし",
    "meaning": "curb (stone), kerb"
  },
  {
    "question": "努々",
    "answer": "ゆめゆめ",
    "meaning": "certainly, absolutely, (not even) a little bit, diligently"
  },
  {
    "question": "判例",
    "answer": "はんれい",
    "meaning": "(judicial) precedent"
  },
  {
    "question": "年格好",
    "answer": "としかっこう",
    "meaning": "apparent age (of someone), rough age"
  },
  {
    "question": "心静か",
    "answer": "こころしずか",
    "meaning": "calm, serene, tranquil, peaceful"
  },
  {
    "question": "先史",
    "answer": "せんし",
    "meaning": "prehistory"
  },
  {
    "question": "佐賀",
    "answer": "さが",
    "meaning": "Saga (city, prefecture)"
  },
  {
    "question": "宋",
    "answer": "そう",
    "meaning": "Song dynasty (China, 960-1279), Sung dynasty, Liu Song dynasty (China, 420-479), Liu Sung dynasty, S"
  },
  {
    "question": "丹波",
    "answer": "たんば",
    "meaning": "Tanba (former province located in parts of present-day Kyōto, Hyōgo and Ōsaka prefectures)"
  },
  {
    "question": "碧玉",
    "answer": "へきぎょく",
    "meaning": "jasper"
  },
  {
    "question": "些",
    "answer": "いさら,いささ",
    "meaning": "small, little"
  },
  {
    "question": "硬球",
    "answer": "こうきゅう",
    "meaning": "hard ball, regulation ball"
  },
  {
    "question": "石弓",
    "answer": "いしゆみ",
    "meaning": "crossbow (incl. large models operated by a number of people), netted apparatus atop a wall containin"
  },
  {
    "question": "松山",
    "answer": "まつやま",
    "meaning": "Matsuyama (city in Ehime)"
  },
  {
    "question": "円弧",
    "answer": "えんこ",
    "meaning": "arc"
  },
  {
    "question": "議席",
    "answer": "ぎせき",
    "meaning": "parliamentary seat"
  },
  {
    "question": "青酸カリ",
    "answer": "せいさんカリ",
    "meaning": "potassium cyanide"
  },
  {
    "question": "兄嫁",
    "answer": "あによめ",
    "meaning": "elder brother's wife, sister-in-law"
  },
  {
    "question": "陸海空",
    "answer": "りくかいくう",
    "meaning": "land, sea, and air, army, navy and air force"
  },
  {
    "question": "石塊",
    "answer": "いしころ,せっかい,いしくれ",
    "meaning": "stone, rock, pebble"
  },
  {
    "question": "四三",
    "answer": "しそう,しぞう,しさん",
    "meaning": "one four-of-a-kind and one three-of-a-kind in a dealt hand, three and a four (in dice games)"
  },
  {
    "question": "都立",
    "answer": "とりつ",
    "meaning": "metropolitan, managed by the Tokyo Metropolitan Government"
  },
  {
    "question": "当り",
    "answer": "あたり",
    "meaning": "hit, success, guess, prediction, affability, friendliness, sensation, touch, bruise (on fruit), situ"
  },
  {
    "question": "木肌",
    "answer": "きはだ,こはだ",
    "meaning": "bark (of a tree)"
  },
  {
    "question": "滅菌",
    "answer": "めっきん",
    "meaning": "sterilization, sterilisation"
  },
  {
    "question": "被膜",
    "answer": "ひまく",
    "meaning": "coating, film, membrane, tunic (plants), capsule"
  },
  {
    "question": "東アジア",
    "answer": "ひがしアジア",
    "meaning": "East Asia"
  },
  {
    "question": "文鎮",
    "answer": "ぶんちん",
    "meaning": "paperweight"
  },
  {
    "question": "処女作",
    "answer": "しょじょさく",
    "meaning": "(one's) maiden work, debut work"
  },
  {
    "question": "賛意",
    "answer": "さんい",
    "meaning": "approval, assent"
  },
  {
    "question": "勝負師",
    "answer": "しょうぶし",
    "meaning": "gambler, risk taker"
  },
  {
    "question": "大尽",
    "answer": "だいじん",
    "meaning": "rich person, millionaire, magnate, big spender, debauchee"
  },
  {
    "question": "油脂",
    "answer": "ゆし",
    "meaning": "fat, fats and oils"
  },
  {
    "question": "水難",
    "answer": "すいなん",
    "meaning": "drowning, flood, shipwreck"
  },
  {
    "question": "論戦",
    "answer": "ろんせん",
    "meaning": "verbal dispute"
  },
  {
    "question": "目付ける",
    "answer": "めっける",
    "meaning": "to discover, to find"
  },
  {
    "question": "動物愛護",
    "answer": "どうぶつあいご",
    "meaning": "animal rights, animal welfare, animal protection"
  },
  {
    "question": "金食い虫",
    "answer": "かねくいむし",
    "meaning": "money loser, high-cost, low-return project"
  },
  {
    "question": "用足し",
    "answer": "ようたし",
    "meaning": "running errands, going on errands, (transaction of) business, going about one's business, doing one'"
  },
  {
    "question": "大人買い",
    "answer": "おとながい",
    "meaning": "buying a large amount (esp. of collectible items aimed at kids, such as manga)"
  },
  {
    "question": "押し破る",
    "answer": "おしやぶる",
    "meaning": "to break through"
  },
  {
    "question": "建て替え",
    "answer": "たてかえ",
    "meaning": "rebuilding, reconstruction, re-erection"
  },
  {
    "question": "出掛かる",
    "answer": "でかかる",
    "meaning": "to just appear, to be half out, to be on the tip of one's tongue"
  },
  {
    "question": "縦社会",
    "answer": "たてしゃかい",
    "meaning": "vertically structured society"
  },
  {
    "question": "空箱",
    "answer": "からばこ,あきばこ",
    "meaning": "empty box"
  },
  {
    "question": "施療",
    "answer": "せりょう",
    "meaning": "free medical treatment, gratuitous treatment"
  },
  {
    "question": "阪",
    "answer": "さか",
    "meaning": "slope, incline, hill, milestone, (age) mark"
  },
  {
    "question": "青梅",
    "answer": "あおうめ",
    "meaning": "unripe plum"
  },
  {
    "question": "社殿",
    "answer": "しゃでん",
    "meaning": "(main building of a) Shinto shrine"
  },
  {
    "question": "上靴",
    "answer": "うわぐつ",
    "meaning": "hallway slippers, indoor shoes, overshoes, rubbers, galoshes"
  },
  {
    "question": "刹",
    "answer": "さつ,せつ",
    "meaning": "temple (Buddhist), central pillar of a pagoda, kshetra (realm, country), ksetra"
  },
  {
    "question": "息む",
    "answer": "いきむ",
    "meaning": "to strain (one's stomach), to bear down (during childbirth), to push down"
  },
  {
    "question": "天上界",
    "answer": "てんじょうかい",
    "meaning": "celestial world, heaven"
  },
  {
    "question": "包茎",
    "answer": "ほうけい,ほうきょう",
    "meaning": "phimosis"
  },
  {
    "question": "夜会服",
    "answer": "やかいふく",
    "meaning": "evening dress"
  },
  {
    "question": "添加",
    "answer": "てんか",
    "meaning": "addition, annexing"
  },
  {
    "question": "糸電話",
    "answer": "いとでんわ",
    "meaning": "telephone made from two cans and a piece of string"
  },
  {
    "question": "棚引く",
    "answer": "たなびく",
    "meaning": "to linger, to hover above, to trail, to hang over, to lie over, to flow (e.g. hair in the wind)"
  },
  {
    "question": "親善大使",
    "answer": "しんぜんたいし",
    "meaning": "goodwill ambassador, friendship ambassador"
  },
  {
    "question": "百八",
    "answer": "ひゃくはち",
    "meaning": "108, one hundred and eight, the number of kleshas, worldly thoughts and passions, the sum of 12 mont"
  },
  {
    "question": "旅行記",
    "answer": "りょこうき",
    "meaning": "journal of one's travels"
  },
  {
    "question": "野良仕事",
    "answer": "のらしごと",
    "meaning": "farm work, field labour, field labor"
  },
  {
    "question": "規程",
    "answer": "きてい",
    "meaning": "official regulations, inner rules"
  },
  {
    "question": "レム睡眠",
    "answer": "レムすいみん",
    "meaning": "REM sleep"
  },
  {
    "question": "帰依",
    "answer": "きえ",
    "meaning": "becoming a devout believer, (religious) conversion"
  },
  {
    "question": "正誤",
    "answer": "せいご",
    "meaning": "correct or incorrect, right or wrong, accuracy, correction (of errors)"
  },
  {
    "question": "原書",
    "answer": "げんしょ",
    "meaning": "original document (not a copy or adaptation), book in its original language (esp. a European languag"
  },
  {
    "question": "軽業",
    "answer": "かるわざ",
    "meaning": "acrobatics, risky undertaking"
  },
  {
    "question": "免職",
    "answer": "めんしょく",
    "meaning": "dismissal, sacking, discharge"
  },
  {
    "question": "転戦",
    "answer": "てんせん",
    "meaning": "fighting in numerous battles"
  },
  {
    "question": "民族的",
    "answer": "みんぞくてき",
    "meaning": "ethnic, racial, national"
  },
  {
    "question": "口が重い",
    "answer": "くちがおもい",
    "meaning": "incommunicative, taciturn"
  },
  {
    "question": "象形文字",
    "answer": "しょうけいもじ",
    "meaning": "hieroglyph, hieroglyphic character"
  },
  {
    "question": "社会学",
    "answer": "しゃかいがく",
    "meaning": "sociology"
  },
  {
    "question": "分割払い",
    "answer": "ぶんかつばらい",
    "meaning": "payment by installments, payment by instalments, hire-purchase"
  },
  {
    "question": "沸き返る",
    "answer": "わきかえる",
    "meaning": "to boil up, to seethe, to get excited, to be in an uproar"
  },
  {
    "question": "欠勤",
    "answer": "けっきん",
    "meaning": "absence (from work)"
  },
  {
    "question": "交付",
    "answer": "こうふ",
    "meaning": "delivery, issuance, handing over, granting"
  },
  {
    "question": "箸が進む",
    "answer": "はしがすすむ",
    "meaning": "to eat a lot, appetizing"
  },
  {
    "question": "食通",
    "answer": "しょくつう",
    "meaning": "gourmandism, gourmet, gourmand, foodie"
  },
  {
    "question": "一週",
    "answer": "いっしゅう",
    "meaning": "one week"
  },
  {
    "question": "小話",
    "answer": "こばなし,しょうわ",
    "meaning": "anecdote, brief (comic) story"
  },
  {
    "question": "検事局",
    "answer": "けんじきょく",
    "meaning": "prosecutor's office"
  },
  {
    "question": "名主",
    "answer": "なぬし,みょうしゅ",
    "meaning": "village headman (esp. in the Kanto region), nominal holder of an allocated rice field (ritsuryo syst"
  },
  {
    "question": "大殿",
    "answer": "おとど,おおとの",
    "meaning": "minister (of government), noble, nobleman's residence, current master, father of one's current maste"
  },
  {
    "question": "幹事長",
    "answer": "かんじちょう",
    "meaning": "chief secretary (usu. of a party), secretary-general"
  },
  {
    "question": "脱獄囚",
    "answer": "だつごくしゅう",
    "meaning": "escaped prisoner"
  },
  {
    "question": "竹藪",
    "answer": "たけやぶ",
    "meaning": "bamboo grove"
  },
  {
    "question": "橋脚",
    "answer": "きょうきゃく",
    "meaning": "bridge pier, pontoon bridge"
  },
  {
    "question": "特捜",
    "answer": "とくそう",
    "meaning": "special investigation"
  },
  {
    "question": "天津",
    "answer": "あまつ,てんしん",
    "meaning": "heavenly, imperial, Tianjin (China)"
  },
  {
    "question": "声楽",
    "answer": "せいがく",
    "meaning": "vocal music"
  },
  {
    "question": "鬚",
    "answer": "ひげ",
    "meaning": "moustache, beard, whiskers, whiskers (on a cat, etc.), feelers (on an insect, etc.), (chin) tuft, ex"
  },
  {
    "question": "憂国",
    "answer": "ゆうこく",
    "meaning": "patriotic concern for the future of one's country"
  },
  {
    "question": "大魚",
    "answer": "たいぎょ",
    "meaning": "large fish"
  },
  {
    "question": "脱穀",
    "answer": "だっこく",
    "meaning": "threshing (e.g. rice)"
  },
  {
    "question": "点てる",
    "answer": "たてる",
    "meaning": "to make tea (matcha), to perform the tea ceremony"
  },
  {
    "question": "資",
    "answer": "し",
    "meaning": "funds, capital, material, basis, character, qualities, disposition"
  },
  {
    "question": "超大国",
    "answer": "ちょうたいこく",
    "meaning": "superpower, superstate"
  },
  {
    "question": "純銀",
    "answer": "じゅんぎん",
    "meaning": "pure silver"
  },
  {
    "question": "粘液質",
    "answer": "ねんえきしつ",
    "meaning": "phlegmatic temperament"
  },
  {
    "question": "献花",
    "answer": "けんか",
    "meaning": "flower offering, floral tribute, laying flowers"
  },
  {
    "question": "悔悟",
    "answer": "かいご",
    "meaning": "remorse, repentance"
  },
  {
    "question": "座視",
    "answer": "ざし",
    "meaning": "remaining an idle spectator, looking on unconcernedly (doing nothing)"
  },
  {
    "question": "間奏",
    "answer": "かんそう",
    "meaning": "interlude, intermezzo"
  },
  {
    "question": "洗髪",
    "answer": "せんぱつ,あらいがみ",
    "meaning": "washing one's hair, having a shampoo, freshly washed hair"
  },
  {
    "question": "酔い潰す",
    "answer": "よいつぶす",
    "meaning": "to drink someone down, to drink someone under the table"
  },
  {
    "question": "気鬱",
    "answer": "きうつ",
    "meaning": "gloom, mental depression"
  },
  {
    "question": "将棋の駒",
    "answer": "しょうぎのこま",
    "meaning": "shogi piece"
  },
  {
    "question": "縁続き",
    "answer": "えんつづき",
    "meaning": "relative"
  },
  {
    "question": "婚前交渉",
    "answer": "こんぜんこうしょう",
    "meaning": "premarital sexual relations (intercourse)"
  },
  {
    "question": "画風",
    "answer": "がふう",
    "meaning": "style of painting"
  },
  {
    "question": "入水",
    "answer": "じゅすい,にゅうすい",
    "meaning": "suicide by drowning, drowning oneself, entering the water, hitting the water"
  },
  {
    "question": "在室",
    "answer": "ざいしつ",
    "meaning": "being in one's room (office, etc.)"
  },
  {
    "question": "大躍進",
    "answer": "だいやくしん",
    "meaning": "Great Leap Forward (failed attempt to industrialize China and increase agricultural production, from"
  },
  {
    "question": "論旨",
    "answer": "ろんし",
    "meaning": "point of an argument, drift of an argument"
  },
  {
    "question": "共有財産",
    "answer": "きょうゆうざいさん",
    "meaning": "community property"
  },
  {
    "question": "車止め",
    "answer": "くるまどめ",
    "meaning": "(railway) buffer stop, bumper, bumping post"
  },
  {
    "question": "置き所",
    "answer": "おきどころ",
    "meaning": "place to put things, shed, storage space, place to put oneself"
  },
  {
    "question": "癇癪持ち",
    "answer": "かんしゃくもち",
    "meaning": "hot-tempered person"
  },
  {
    "question": "散らし",
    "answer": "ちらし",
    "meaning": "scattering, leaflets, sushi rice in a box or bowl with a variety of ingredients sprinkled on top, wr"
  },
  {
    "question": "記名",
    "answer": "きめい",
    "meaning": "signature, register, to put one's name on, to sign, stamped name, typed name"
  },
  {
    "question": "零戦",
    "answer": "ゼロせん,れいせん",
    "meaning": "Zero fighter plane"
  },
  {
    "question": "朋",
    "answer": "とも",
    "meaning": "friend, companion, comrade, pal, accompaniment, companion (e.g. book), complement, accessory"
  },
  {
    "question": "審議会",
    "answer": "しんぎかい",
    "meaning": "council (deliberative, consultative), commission of inquiry (enquiry)"
  },
  {
    "question": "飛蝗",
    "answer": "ばった,ひこう,とびばった",
    "meaning": "grasshopper, locust (of superfamily Acridoidea), locust swarming, locust swarm, (swarming) locusts"
  },
  {
    "question": "主教",
    "answer": "しゅきょう",
    "meaning": "bishop (Orthodox, Anglican, etc.)"
  },
  {
    "question": "茶釜",
    "answer": "ちゃがま",
    "meaning": "teakettle (tea ceremony)"
  },
  {
    "question": "廉",
    "answer": "かど,れん",
    "meaning": "charge, grounds, suspicion, cheap, inexpensive, pure, honest, upright"
  },
  {
    "question": "不孝",
    "answer": "ふこう,ふきょう",
    "meaning": "undutifulness to one's parents, lack of filial piety, (the crime of) cursing one's parents, disownin"
  },
  {
    "question": "貧民窟",
    "answer": "ひんみんくつ",
    "meaning": "slums"
  },
  {
    "question": "京浜",
    "answer": "けいひん",
    "meaning": "Tokyo and Yokohama"
  },
  {
    "question": "北岸",
    "answer": "ほくがん",
    "meaning": "north coast, north bank"
  },
  {
    "question": "蘇",
    "answer": "そ",
    "meaning": "condensed milk, Soviet Union"
  },
  {
    "question": "白雲",
    "answer": "しらくも,はくうん",
    "meaning": "white clouds"
  },
  {
    "question": "森林公園",
    "answer": "しんりんこうえん",
    "meaning": "forest park"
  },
  {
    "question": "暗夜",
    "answer": "あんや",
    "meaning": "dark night"
  },
  {
    "question": "昨",
    "answer": "さく",
    "meaning": "last (year), yesterday"
  },
  {
    "question": "簞笥",
    "answer": "たんす",
    "meaning": "chest of drawers, bureau, cabinet, tansu, dresser"
  },
  {
    "question": "元ヤン",
    "answer": "もとヤン",
    "meaning": "reformed delinquent, former delinquent youth"
  },
  {
    "question": "簾",
    "answer": "すだれ,す,れん",
    "meaning": "bamboo screen, rattan blind, bamboo mat (for rolling sushi)"
  },
  {
    "question": "債権者",
    "answer": "さいけんしゃ",
    "meaning": "creditor"
  },
  {
    "question": "縦笛",
    "answer": "たてぶえ",
    "meaning": "end-blown flute (esp. the recorder)"
  },
  {
    "question": "髭剃り",
    "answer": "ひげそり",
    "meaning": "shaving, shaver"
  },
  {
    "question": "縦隊",
    "answer": "じゅうたい",
    "meaning": "column"
  },
  {
    "question": "加害",
    "answer": "かがい",
    "meaning": "assault, violence, damaging (someone)"
  },
  {
    "question": "醜怪",
    "answer": "しゅうかい",
    "meaning": "monstrously ugly, hideous, ugly and bizarre"
  },
  {
    "question": "引き直す",
    "answer": "ひきなおす",
    "meaning": "to redraw (a line), to catch (a cold) again, to consult (a reference) again"
  },
  {
    "question": "電波障害",
    "answer": "でんぱしょうがい",
    "meaning": "electromagnetic interference, radio interference"
  },
  {
    "question": "発泡",
    "answer": "はっぽう",
    "meaning": "foaming"
  },
  {
    "question": "下達",
    "answer": "かたつ,げたつ",
    "meaning": "commanding a subordinate"
  },
  {
    "question": "肘掛",
    "answer": "ひじかけ",
    "meaning": "armrest (of a chair), elbow rest"
  },
  {
    "question": "面長",
    "answer": "おもなが,めんちょう",
    "meaning": "oval-faced, long-faced"
  },
  {
    "question": "冬山",
    "answer": "ふゆやま",
    "meaning": "wintry mountain, mountain that is often climbed during the winter"
  },
  {
    "question": "喧々諤々",
    "answer": "けんけんがくがく",
    "meaning": "tumultuous (with everyone voicing their opinions simultaneously), uproarious"
  },
  {
    "question": "鷲鼻",
    "answer": "わしばな",
    "meaning": "aquiline nose, Roman nose, hook nose"
  },
  {
    "question": "誤用",
    "answer": "ごよう",
    "meaning": "misuse, incorrect use, abuse, malapropism"
  },
  {
    "question": "擦れ違い",
    "answer": "すれちがい",
    "meaning": "passing each other, crossing paths without meeting, (being at) cross purposes, (having) discrepancie"
  },
  {
    "question": "組織立つ",
    "answer": "そしきだつ",
    "meaning": "to have orderly plans, to be systematic"
  },
  {
    "question": "離席",
    "answer": "りせき",
    "meaning": "leaving one's seat"
  },
  {
    "question": "防腐",
    "answer": "ぼうふ",
    "meaning": "preservation from decay, prevention of putrefaction, embalmment, antisepsis"
  },
  {
    "question": "肌理",
    "answer": "きめ,きり",
    "meaning": "texture (e.g. skin, fabric), grain (e.g. wood), detail"
  },
  {
    "question": "汲々",
    "answer": "きゅうきゅう",
    "meaning": "diligent, absorbed (in something)"
  },
  {
    "question": "俯せる",
    "answer": "うつぶせる",
    "meaning": "to lie face-down"
  },
  {
    "question": "詐欺罪",
    "answer": "さぎざい",
    "meaning": "fraud"
  },
  {
    "question": "日用雑貨",
    "answer": "にちようざっか",
    "meaning": "daily necessities, everyday goods"
  },
  {
    "question": "明々後日",
    "answer": "しあさって,みょうみょうごにち",
    "meaning": "in three days' time, two days after tomorrow"
  },
  {
    "question": "騙し騙し",
    "answer": "だましだまし",
    "meaning": "using every trick (in the book)"
  },
  {
    "question": "副菜",
    "answer": "ふくさい",
    "meaning": "side dish (e.g. vegetables, beans, pickles)"
  },
  {
    "question": "身空",
    "answer": "みそら",
    "meaning": "body, one's fortune"
  },
  {
    "question": "苦汁",
    "answer": "にがり,くじゅう",
    "meaning": "bittern, concentrated solution of salts (esp. magnesium chloride) left over after the crystallizatio"
  },
  {
    "question": "狒々",
    "answer": "ひひ",
    "meaning": "baboon, lecher, dirty old man, skirt-chaser"
  },
  {
    "question": "筒井",
    "answer": "つつい",
    "meaning": "round well"
  },
  {
    "question": "七重",
    "answer": "ななえ",
    "meaning": "sevenfold, seven-ply"
  },
  {
    "question": "播磨",
    "answer": "はりま",
    "meaning": "Harima (former province located in the southwestern part of present-day Hyōgo Prefecture)"
  },
  {
    "question": "両替商",
    "answer": "りょうがえしょう",
    "meaning": "money-exchange business"
  },
  {
    "question": "僚友",
    "answer": "りょうゆう",
    "meaning": "colleague, workmate, comrade, coworker"
  },
  {
    "question": "船医",
    "answer": "せんい",
    "meaning": "ship's doctor"
  },
  {
    "question": "懐剣",
    "answer": "かいけん",
    "meaning": "dagger"
  },
  {
    "question": "群島",
    "answer": "ぐんとう",
    "meaning": "island group, archipelago"
  },
  {
    "question": "大黒",
    "answer": "だいこく",
    "meaning": "god of wealth, monk's wife"
  },
  {
    "question": "水運",
    "answer": "すいうん",
    "meaning": "water transportation"
  },
  {
    "question": "打順",
    "answer": "だじゅん",
    "meaning": "batting order"
  },
  {
    "question": "保育所",
    "answer": "ほいくしょ,ほいくじょ",
    "meaning": "nursery school, nursery"
  },
  {
    "question": "浮世絵",
    "answer": "うきよえ",
    "meaning": "ukiyo-e, ukiyoe, Edo-period woodblock print"
  },
  {
    "question": "城郭",
    "answer": "じょうかく",
    "meaning": "fortress, castle, citadel, enclosure, castle walls"
  },
  {
    "question": "碁盤",
    "answer": "ごばん",
    "meaning": "Go board"
  },
  {
    "question": "画伯",
    "answer": "がはく",
    "meaning": "master painter, artist"
  },
  {
    "question": "天地創造",
    "answer": "てんちそうぞう",
    "meaning": "creation (of the universe), the Creation"
  },
  {
    "question": "身籠もる",
    "answer": "みごもる",
    "meaning": "to become pregnant"
  },
  {
    "question": "馬体",
    "answer": "ばたい",
    "meaning": "body of a horse"
  },
  {
    "question": "雨霰",
    "answer": "あめあられ",
    "meaning": "hail (e.g. of bullets), barrage, storm, rain and hail"
  },
  {
    "question": "創刊",
    "answer": "そうかん",
    "meaning": "launching (e.g. newspaper), first issue"
  },
  {
    "question": "定期券",
    "answer": "ていきけん",
    "meaning": "commuter pass, season ticket"
  },
  {
    "question": "反体制",
    "answer": "はんたいせい",
    "meaning": "anti-establishment"
  },
  {
    "question": "偽悪",
    "answer": "ぎあく",
    "meaning": "pretense of evil, pretence of evil"
  },
  {
    "question": "纏まり",
    "answer": "まとまり",
    "meaning": "unity, coherence, consistency, coordination, settlement, conclusion, completion"
  },
  {
    "question": "短文",
    "answer": "たんぶん",
    "meaning": "short sentence, short piece of writing (e.g. passage, article, composition)"
  },
  {
    "question": "薬用",
    "answer": "やくよう",
    "meaning": "medicinal use"
  },
  {
    "question": "清澄",
    "answer": "せいちょう",
    "meaning": "clear, serene"
  },
  {
    "question": "臑",
    "answer": "すね",
    "meaning": "shin, shank, lower leg"
  },
  {
    "question": "相互作用",
    "answer": "そうごさよう",
    "meaning": "interaction"
  },
  {
    "question": "巨大都市",
    "answer": "きょだいとし",
    "meaning": "megalopolis, megacity, supercity"
  },
  {
    "question": "猛攻撃",
    "answer": "もうこうげき",
    "meaning": "fierce attack"
  },
  {
    "question": "塩辛",
    "answer": "しおから",
    "meaning": "shiokara, paste made from salted fermented seafood (squid, fish entrails, etc.)"
  },
  {
    "question": "糖質",
    "answer": "とうしつ",
    "meaning": "sugariness, saccharinity, carbohydrate"
  },
  {
    "question": "葉脈",
    "answer": "ようみゃく",
    "meaning": "veins of a leaf"
  },
  {
    "question": "怠り",
    "answer": "おこたり",
    "meaning": "negligence, carelessness"
  },
  {
    "question": "税込み",
    "answer": "ぜいこみ",
    "meaning": "tax included (e.g. price), before tax (e.g. salary)"
  },
  {
    "question": "生え抜き",
    "answer": "はえぬき",
    "meaning": "native-born, trueborn"
  },
  {
    "question": "乾電池",
    "answer": "かんでんち",
    "meaning": "dry cell, battery"
  },
  {
    "question": "相関図",
    "answer": "そうかんず",
    "meaning": "correlation diagram, correlation chart"
  },
  {
    "question": "前々",
    "answer": "まえまえ,ぜんぜん",
    "meaning": "a long time ago, long before now, (one) before last, two before, two in front (e.g. rows)"
  },
  {
    "question": "羽振り",
    "answer": "はぶり",
    "meaning": "influence, power, flapping of wings"
  },
  {
    "question": "二重奏",
    "answer": "にじゅうそう",
    "meaning": "instrumental duet, instrumental duo"
  },
  {
    "question": "脅かし",
    "answer": "おどかし",
    "meaning": "threat"
  },
  {
    "question": "吉日",
    "answer": "きちじつ,きちにち,きつじつ",
    "meaning": "lucky day, unspecified day of the month (used to obscure the date a letter, invitation, etc. was wri"
  },
  {
    "question": "話し上手",
    "answer": "はなしじょうず",
    "meaning": "being good at conversation, conversationalist, good talker"
  },
  {
    "question": "玄室",
    "answer": "げんしつ",
    "meaning": "burial chamber"
  },
  {
    "question": "橇",
    "answer": "そり,かんじき",
    "meaning": "sleigh, sled, sledge, snowshoes"
  },
  {
    "question": "馬頭",
    "answer": "ばとう",
    "meaning": "Hayagriva, Horsehead (tantric Buddhist deity)"
  },
  {
    "question": "州都",
    "answer": "しゅうと",
    "meaning": "state capital, provincial capital, county town"
  },
  {
    "question": "制御盤",
    "answer": "せいぎょばん",
    "meaning": "control panel, switchbox"
  },
  {
    "question": "発動機",
    "answer": "はつどうき",
    "meaning": "engine"
  },
  {
    "question": "被爆",
    "answer": "ひばく",
    "meaning": "being bombed, being A-bombed, being nuked, being exposed to radiation (from an atomic blast)"
  },
  {
    "question": "般若心経",
    "answer": "はんにゃしんぎょう",
    "meaning": "Heart Sutra"
  },
  {
    "question": "寝椅子",
    "answer": "ねいす",
    "meaning": "sofa, couch, lounge chair"
  },
  {
    "question": "配点",
    "answer": "はいてん",
    "meaning": "allotment (allocation) of marks"
  },
  {
    "question": "船籍",
    "answer": "せんせき",
    "meaning": "ship's nationality, ship's country of registration"
  },
  {
    "question": "弾雨",
    "answer": "だんう",
    "meaning": "hail of bullets"
  },
  {
    "question": "小吉",
    "answer": "しょうきち",
    "meaning": "slightly good luck (as a fortune telling result)"
  },
  {
    "question": "糸巻き",
    "answer": "いとまき",
    "meaning": "spool (of thread), reel, bobbin, tuning peg"
  },
  {
    "question": "括弧",
    "answer": "かっこ",
    "meaning": "brackets, parentheses"
  },
  {
    "question": "生体認証",
    "answer": "せいたいにんしょう",
    "meaning": "biometrics, biometric authentication"
  },
  {
    "question": "差違",
    "answer": "さい",
    "meaning": "difference, disparity, gap"
  },
  {
    "question": "定例会",
    "answer": "ていれいかい",
    "meaning": "regular meeting"
  },
  {
    "question": "香味野菜",
    "answer": "こうみやさい",
    "meaning": "potherb, pot herb"
  },
  {
    "question": "申込書",
    "answer": "もうしこみしょ",
    "meaning": "(written) application, application form"
  },
  {
    "question": "追認",
    "answer": "ついにん",
    "meaning": "ratification, confirmation"
  },
  {
    "question": "看護士",
    "answer": "かんごし",
    "meaning": "(male) nurse"
  },
  {
    "question": "出刃包丁",
    "answer": "でばぼうちょう",
    "meaning": "knife, pointed carver"
  },
  {
    "question": "寝惚け眼",
    "answer": "ねぼけまなこ,ねとぼけまなこ",
    "meaning": "sleepy eyes, drowsy look"
  },
  {
    "question": "持ち金",
    "answer": "もちがね",
    "meaning": "money possessed"
  },
  {
    "question": "長広舌",
    "answer": "ちょうこうぜつ",
    "meaning": "long talk, long-winded speech"
  },
  {
    "question": "敷金",
    "answer": "しききん",
    "meaning": "(security) deposit, caution money"
  },
  {
    "question": "命令形",
    "answer": "めいれいけい",
    "meaning": "imperative form, command"
  },
  {
    "question": "決を採る",
    "answer": "けつをとる",
    "meaning": "to take a vote"
  },
  {
    "question": "熟年",
    "answer": "じゅくねん",
    "meaning": "mature in age and wisdom, middle-aged"
  },
  {
    "question": "菓子折",
    "answer": "かしおり",
    "meaning": "box of cakes"
  },
  {
    "question": "専守防衛",
    "answer": "せんしゅぼうえい",
    "meaning": "nonaggressive defense (policy) (defence)"
  },
  {
    "question": "座り込み",
    "answer": "すわりこみ",
    "meaning": "sit-in (i.e. in protest)"
  },
  {
    "question": "写し出す",
    "answer": "うつしだす",
    "meaning": "to project, to show, to portray, to depict, to describe, to reflect"
  },
  {
    "question": "証拠物件",
    "answer": "しょうこぶっけん",
    "meaning": "evidence, an exhibit"
  },
  {
    "question": "殉ずる",
    "answer": "じゅんずる",
    "meaning": "to sacrifice oneself, to die a martyr"
  },
  {
    "question": "耳に付く",
    "answer": "みみにつく",
    "meaning": "to catch one's attention, to catch one's ear, to be annoying to one's ear"
  },
  {
    "question": "凌ぎ",
    "answer": "しのぎ",
    "meaning": "tiding over"
  },
  {
    "question": "市場価格",
    "answer": "しじょうかかく",
    "meaning": "market price or value"
  },
  {
    "question": "月桂冠",
    "answer": "げっけいかん",
    "meaning": "laurel wreath"
  },
  {
    "question": "白州",
    "answer": "しらす",
    "meaning": "white sandbar, white sandbank, area in a garden or entrance of a house laid with white sand or pebbl"
  },
  {
    "question": "荒神",
    "answer": "こうじん,あらがみ",
    "meaning": "god of a cooking stove, powerful deity (sometimes impetuous), miraculous spirit"
  },
  {
    "question": "株式市場",
    "answer": "かぶしきしじょう",
    "meaning": "stock market"
  },
  {
    "question": "蒼空",
    "answer": "そうくう",
    "meaning": "blue sky"
  },
  {
    "question": "太々しい",
    "answer": "ふてぶてしい",
    "meaning": "impudent, brazen, shameless, bold"
  },
  {
    "question": "鷹の爪",
    "answer": "たかのつめ",
    "meaning": "Gamblea innovans (species of deciduous tree), extremely spicy form of chili pepper, variety of high-"
  },
  {
    "question": "明智",
    "answer": "めいち",
    "meaning": "sagacity, wisdom, intelligence"
  },
  {
    "question": "遺作",
    "answer": "いさく",
    "meaning": "posthumous works"
  },
  {
    "question": "裔",
    "answer": "えい,こはな",
    "meaning": "descendant, scion, lineage"
  },
  {
    "question": "泪",
    "answer": "なみだ",
    "meaning": "tear, tears, lachrymal secretion, sympathy"
  },
  {
    "question": "那覇",
    "answer": "なは",
    "meaning": "Naha (city in Okinawa)"
  },
  {
    "question": "旗下",
    "answer": "きか",
    "meaning": "under the command (of), under the banner (of), influenced (by)"
  },
  {
    "question": "蒸気船",
    "answer": "じょうきせん",
    "meaning": "steamship, steamboat, steamer"
  },
  {
    "question": "集団自殺",
    "answer": "しゅうだんじさつ",
    "meaning": "group suicide, mass suicide, arranged suicide of two or more people"
  },
  {
    "question": "走法",
    "answer": "そうほう",
    "meaning": "running style"
  },
  {
    "question": "大盛",
    "answer": "おおもり",
    "meaning": "large serving, large portion"
  },
  {
    "question": "概論",
    "answer": "がいろん",
    "meaning": "introduction, outline, general remarks"
  },
  {
    "question": "抜き手",
    "answer": "ぬきて,ぬきで",
    "meaning": "overarm stroke (type of traditional Japanese swimming style)"
  },
  {
    "question": "産道",
    "answer": "さんどう",
    "meaning": "birth canal"
  },
  {
    "question": "売上げ",
    "answer": "うりあげ",
    "meaning": "amount sold, sales, proceeds, takings, turnover"
  },
  {
    "question": "発条",
    "answer": "ばね,ぜんまい,はつじょう",
    "meaning": "spring (e.g. coil, leaf), mainspring, power spring"
  },
  {
    "question": "婦",
    "answer": "よめ,ふ",
    "meaning": "wife, bride, (one's) daughter-in-law, married woman, woman, lady"
  },
  {
    "question": "放言",
    "answer": "ほうげん",
    "meaning": "careless remark"
  },
  {
    "question": "心理描写",
    "answer": "しんりびょうしゃ",
    "meaning": "psychological description"
  },
  {
    "question": "生乳",
    "answer": "せいにゅう",
    "meaning": "raw milk"
  },
  {
    "question": "学識",
    "answer": "がくしき",
    "meaning": "scholarship, scientific attainments"
  },
  {
    "question": "差し詰め",
    "answer": "さしずめ,さしづめ",
    "meaning": "after all, in the end, when all's said and done, for the time being, at present"
  },
  {
    "question": "青写真",
    "answer": "あおじゃしん",
    "meaning": "blueprint, cyanotype, blueprint (for the future), plan"
  },
  {
    "question": "侮辱罪",
    "answer": "ぶじょくざい",
    "meaning": "(crime of) defamation (i.e. slander, libel)"
  },
  {
    "question": "隠棲",
    "answer": "いんせい",
    "meaning": "secluded life"
  },
  {
    "question": "下記",
    "answer": "かき",
    "meaning": "the following"
  },
  {
    "question": "沈思黙考",
    "answer": "ちんしもっこう",
    "meaning": "being lost in deep thought"
  },
  {
    "question": "脳幹",
    "answer": "のうかん",
    "meaning": "brain stem"
  },
  {
    "question": "踏み殺す",
    "answer": "ふみころす",
    "meaning": "to trample to death, to kill underfoot"
  },
  {
    "question": "拍車",
    "answer": "はくしゃ",
    "meaning": "(riding) spur"
  },
  {
    "question": "郵便配達",
    "answer": "ゆうびんはいたつ",
    "meaning": "postal delivery, mail delivery, postman, mailman"
  },
  {
    "question": "筆記体",
    "answer": "ひっきたい",
    "meaning": "cursive style"
  },
  {
    "question": "帰着",
    "answer": "きちゃく",
    "meaning": "return, conclusion, reduction"
  },
  {
    "question": "梅雨入り",
    "answer": "つゆいり,ついり",
    "meaning": "entering the rainy season, beginning of the rainy season"
  },
  {
    "question": "世を去る",
    "answer": "よをさる",
    "meaning": "to die, to pass away, to enter the priesthood, to live a secluded life"
  },
  {
    "question": "厭世的",
    "answer": "えんせいてき",
    "meaning": "pessimistic"
  },
  {
    "question": "東奔西走",
    "answer": "とうほんせいそう",
    "meaning": "busying oneself about (something), being on the move, bestirring oneself, on the go, taking an activ"
  },
  {
    "question": "全品",
    "answer": "ぜんぴん",
    "meaning": "all goods"
  },
  {
    "question": "遠近法",
    "answer": "えんきんほう",
    "meaning": "perspective"
  },
  {
    "question": "寝坊助",
    "answer": "ねぼすけ",
    "meaning": "person who oversleeps, sleepyhead"
  },
  {
    "question": "国費",
    "answer": "こくひ",
    "meaning": "national expenditure, government spending, public funds"
  },
  {
    "question": "深謀遠慮",
    "answer": "しんぼうえんりょ",
    "meaning": "far sight and deep design"
  },
  {
    "question": "独り者",
    "answer": "ひとりもの",
    "meaning": "single (i.e. unmarried) person, someone alone"
  },
  {
    "question": "鎮守府",
    "answer": "ちんじゅふ",
    "meaning": "(historical) army base, navy base"
  },
  {
    "question": "寄席",
    "answer": "よせ,よせせき",
    "meaning": "entertainment hall (for rakugo, manzai, magic, music, etc.), vaudeville theater (theatre), music hal"
  },
  {
    "question": "実機",
    "answer": "じっき",
    "meaning": "real machine (as opposed to a model or simulation), actual machine, actual device, real aeroplane, a"
  },
  {
    "question": "擬する",
    "answer": "ぎする",
    "meaning": "to imitate, to copy, to mimic, to enter someone as a candidate, to press (e.g. a weapon against some"
  },
  {
    "question": "空家",
    "answer": "あきや",
    "meaning": "vacant house, unoccupied house"
  },
  {
    "question": "速球",
    "answer": "そっきゅう",
    "meaning": "fastball"
  },
  {
    "question": "悶",
    "answer": "もん",
    "meaning": "agony, anguish"
  },
  {
    "question": "返球",
    "answer": "へんきゅう",
    "meaning": "return toss (e.g. from a catcher to a pitcher)"
  },
  {
    "question": "佐官",
    "answer": "さかん",
    "meaning": "field officer"
  },
  {
    "question": "乱流",
    "answer": "らんりゅう",
    "meaning": "(air) turbulence"
  },
  {
    "question": "半券",
    "answer": "はんけん",
    "meaning": "stub (of a ticket)"
  },
  {
    "question": "バク宙",
    "answer": "バクちゅう",
    "meaning": "backflip, backward somersault"
  },
  {
    "question": "相乗",
    "answer": "そうじょう",
    "meaning": "multiplication, synergism"
  },
  {
    "question": "大英帝国",
    "answer": "だいえいていこく",
    "meaning": "the British Empire"
  },
  {
    "question": "喪主",
    "answer": "もしゅ",
    "meaning": "chief mourner"
  },
  {
    "question": "御守り",
    "answer": "おまもり,おもり",
    "meaning": "charm, amulet, babysitting, babysitter, taking care of, assisting, assistant, helper"
  },
  {
    "question": "正中線",
    "answer": "せいちゅうせん",
    "meaning": "median line"
  },
  {
    "question": "選任",
    "answer": "せんにん",
    "meaning": "nomination (of a person to a position), selection, election, assignment, appointment"
  },
  {
    "question": "増改築",
    "answer": "ぞうかいちく",
    "meaning": "extension and structural alteration of building"
  },
  {
    "question": "小用",
    "answer": "こよう,しょうよう",
    "meaning": "trifling matter, urination, urine"
  },
  {
    "question": "粗品",
    "answer": "そしな,そひん",
    "meaning": "small present, trifling gift, gift given out by companies to customers as a token of gratitude, mark"
  },
  {
    "question": "連泊",
    "answer": "れんぱく",
    "meaning": "staying for two or more nights in a row (e.g. at a hotel)"
  },
  {
    "question": "冊数",
    "answer": "さっすう",
    "meaning": "number of books"
  },
  {
    "question": "対流",
    "answer": "たいりゅう",
    "meaning": "convection"
  },
  {
    "question": "雲霞",
    "answer": "うんか,くもかすみ",
    "meaning": "clouds and haze (fog), disappearing, fleeing"
  },
  {
    "question": "管楽器",
    "answer": "かんがっき",
    "meaning": "wind instrument"
  },
  {
    "question": "開業医",
    "answer": "かいぎょうい",
    "meaning": "private clinician, physician in private practice, general practitioner"
  },
  {
    "question": "機嫌取り",
    "answer": "きげんとり",
    "meaning": "currying favour, being anxious to please, bootlicker"
  },
  {
    "question": "平面的",
    "answer": "へいめんてき",
    "meaning": "planar"
  },
  {
    "question": "衆人",
    "answer": "しゅうじん",
    "meaning": "the people, the public"
  },
  {
    "question": "冷暖房",
    "answer": "れいだんぼう",
    "meaning": "air conditioning and heating"
  },
  {
    "question": "折り畳み",
    "answer": "おりたたみ",
    "meaning": "folding, collapsible, telescopic"
  },
  {
    "question": "活気付く",
    "answer": "かっきづく",
    "meaning": "to become animated, to liven up, to become active"
  },
  {
    "question": "足繁く",
    "answer": "あししげく",
    "meaning": "frequently"
  },
  {
    "question": "持ち家",
    "answer": "もちいえ,もちや",
    "meaning": "one's (own) house"
  },
  {
    "question": "無しには",
    "answer": "なしには",
    "meaning": "without"
  },
  {
    "question": "免じる",
    "answer": "めんじる",
    "meaning": "to dismiss (from a position), to exempt, to excuse from, to forgive"
  },
  {
    "question": "幾日も",
    "answer": "いくにちも",
    "meaning": "for many days, for some days"
  },
  {
    "question": "羅漢",
    "answer": "らかん",
    "meaning": "arhat"
  },
  {
    "question": "蠱",
    "answer": "まじ",
    "meaning": "charmed and cursed, something that bewilders, something that leads one astray, the work of demons"
  },
  {
    "question": "碁石",
    "answer": "ごいし",
    "meaning": "go stone, go piece"
  },
  {
    "question": "上人",
    "answer": "しょうにん",
    "meaning": "holy priest, saint"
  },
  {
    "question": "読書会",
    "answer": "どくしょかい",
    "meaning": "reading circle, reading group, book club"
  },
  {
    "question": "基底",
    "answer": "きてい",
    "meaning": "base, ground, basis"
  },
  {
    "question": "軍政",
    "answer": "ぐんせい",
    "meaning": "military administration, military government, military junta, government affairs relating to the mil"
  },
  {
    "question": "余震",
    "answer": "よしん",
    "meaning": "aftershock"
  },
  {
    "question": "直中",
    "answer": "ただなか",
    "meaning": "middle"
  },
  {
    "question": "内応",
    "answer": "ないおう",
    "meaning": "secret understanding, collusion, betrayal"
  },
  {
    "question": "側壁",
    "answer": "そくへき",
    "meaning": "side wall"
  },
  {
    "question": "放散",
    "answer": "ほうさん",
    "meaning": "radiation, diffusion"
  },
  {
    "question": "風雲",
    "answer": "ふううん,かざぐも,かぜくも",
    "meaning": "winds and clouds, nature, the elements, situation, state of affairs, clouds appearing before the win"
  },
  {
    "question": "逆玉",
    "answer": "ぎゃくたま",
    "meaning": "man who marries a wealthy or upwardly-mobile woman, (male) gold digger"
  },
  {
    "question": "横溢",
    "answer": "おういつ",
    "meaning": "overflowing, inundation"
  },
  {
    "question": "実存",
    "answer": "じつぞん",
    "meaning": "existence"
  },
  {
    "question": "私有",
    "answer": "しゆう",
    "meaning": "private ownership"
  },
  {
    "question": "基準点",
    "answer": "きじゅんてん",
    "meaning": "point of reference, reference point"
  },
  {
    "question": "生理学",
    "answer": "せいりがく",
    "meaning": "physiology"
  },
  {
    "question": "版画",
    "answer": "はんが",
    "meaning": "woodcut, woodblock print, art print"
  },
  {
    "question": "隔世遺伝",
    "answer": "かくせいいでん",
    "meaning": "atavism, throwback, reappearance of an earlier characteristic, skipping a generation, reversion to a"
  },
  {
    "question": "移設",
    "answer": "いせつ",
    "meaning": "relocation (of a facility), moving establishment, to relocate, to move into place, to put into place"
  },
  {
    "question": "政治屋",
    "answer": "せいじや",
    "meaning": "politician (esp. one who works only for their own personal gain)"
  },
  {
    "question": "不世出",
    "answer": "ふせいしゅつ",
    "meaning": "rare, extraordinary, unparalleled, unparallelled"
  },
  {
    "question": "下端",
    "answer": "かたん,したば",
    "meaning": "lower end, bottom edge, lower portion, base surface, soffit"
  },
  {
    "question": "頭分",
    "answer": "かしらぶん",
    "meaning": "boss, leader"
  },
  {
    "question": "地球環境",
    "answer": "ちきゅうかんきょう",
    "meaning": "global environment"
  },
  {
    "question": "民芸品",
    "answer": "みんげいひん",
    "meaning": "(article of) folk craft"
  },
  {
    "question": "町医者",
    "answer": "まちいしゃ",
    "meaning": "physician in private practice, town doctor, doctor who served the townspeople (as opposed to the emp"
  },
  {
    "question": "卸",
    "answer": "おろし",
    "meaning": "dropping, unloading, removing, grated vegetables, fruit, etc., grater, using new tools (or clothes,"
  },
  {
    "question": "信を置く",
    "answer": "しんをおく",
    "meaning": "to put one's trust in"
  },
  {
    "question": "流線形",
    "answer": "りゅうせんけい",
    "meaning": "streamline shape, aerodynamic shape"
  },
  {
    "question": "波状",
    "answer": "はじょう",
    "meaning": "wavelike, in waves, undulation"
  },
  {
    "question": "血統書",
    "answer": "けっとうしょ",
    "meaning": "pedigree document (for animals), pedigree paper"
  },
  {
    "question": "恐れ戦く",
    "answer": "おそれおののく",
    "meaning": "to tremble with fear"
  },
  {
    "question": "混合物",
    "answer": "こんごうぶつ",
    "meaning": "mixture, amalgam"
  },
  {
    "question": "世界経済",
    "answer": "せかいけいざい",
    "meaning": "world economy, international economy"
  },
  {
    "question": "奇々怪々",
    "answer": "ききかいかい",
    "meaning": "very strange, bizarre, weird, mysterious"
  },
  {
    "question": "寝酒",
    "answer": "ねざけ",
    "meaning": "nightcap, a drink before sleeping"
  },
  {
    "question": "直送",
    "answer": "ちょくそう",
    "meaning": "direct delivery"
  },
  {
    "question": "完徹",
    "answer": "かんてつ",
    "meaning": "all nighter, sleepless night"
  },
  {
    "question": "孺子",
    "answer": "じゅし",
    "meaning": "child, young lad, stripling, greenhorn, inexperienced person"
  },
  {
    "question": "糸鋸",
    "answer": "いとのこ",
    "meaning": "fretsaw, coping saw, jigsaw"
  },
  {
    "question": "雲上",
    "answer": "うんじょう,うんしょう",
    "meaning": "above the clouds, the heavens"
  },
  {
    "question": "腸液",
    "answer": "ちょうえき",
    "meaning": "intestinal fluids (juices)"
  },
  {
    "question": "遠眼鏡",
    "answer": "とおめがね,えんがんきょう",
    "meaning": "spectacles for far-sightedness, telescope"
  },
  {
    "question": "麦藁帽子",
    "answer": "むぎわらぼうし",
    "meaning": "straw hat"
  },
  {
    "question": "砲丸",
    "answer": "ほうがん",
    "meaning": "shell, shots, cannon ball"
  },
  {
    "question": "靭帯",
    "answer": "じんたい",
    "meaning": "ligament"
  },
  {
    "question": "臣籍降下",
    "answer": "しんせきこうか",
    "meaning": "(of members of the Imperial family) becoming subjects of the state"
  },
  {
    "question": "抓む",
    "answer": "つむ,つまむ",
    "meaning": "to pick, to pluck, to pinch, to hold (between one's fingers), to pick up (with chopsticks, tweezers,"
  },
  {
    "question": "天地開闢",
    "answer": "てんちかいびゃく",
    "meaning": "creation of heaven and earth"
  },
  {
    "question": "裏町",
    "answer": "うらまち",
    "meaning": "back street, back alley, slums"
  },
  {
    "question": "此岸",
    "answer": "しがん",
    "meaning": "this world, this life"
  },
  {
    "question": "酢飯",
    "answer": "すめし",
    "meaning": "vinegared rice, rice prepared for sushi"
  },
  {
    "question": "巨砲",
    "answer": "きょほう",
    "meaning": "huge gun"
  },
  {
    "question": "デモ隊",
    "answer": "デモたい",
    "meaning": "demonstrators"
  },
  {
    "question": "異星",
    "answer": "いせい",
    "meaning": "different planet, another planet"
  },
  {
    "question": "習作",
    "answer": "しゅうさく",
    "meaning": "(a) study (e.g. in music, art, sculpture, etc.), etude, practice piece"
  },
  {
    "question": "医務",
    "answer": "いむ",
    "meaning": "medical affairs"
  },
  {
    "question": "老犬",
    "answer": "ろうけん",
    "meaning": "old dog"
  },
  {
    "question": "腹式呼吸",
    "answer": "ふくしきこきゅう",
    "meaning": "diaphragmatic breathing, abdominal breathing"
  },
  {
    "question": "流れ矢",
    "answer": "ながれや",
    "meaning": "stray arrow"
  },
  {
    "question": "接ぐ",
    "answer": "つぐ,はぐ",
    "meaning": "to join, to piece together, to set (bones), to graft (onto a tree), to join (cloth, wood, etc.)"
  },
  {
    "question": "英字",
    "answer": "えいじ",
    "meaning": "English letter, alphabetic character"
  },
  {
    "question": "百度",
    "answer": "ひゃくど,ももたび",
    "meaning": "hundred times, hundred degrees, many times"
  },
  {
    "question": "洋酒",
    "answer": "ようしゅ",
    "meaning": "Western wine and spirits, Western liquor"
  },
  {
    "question": "外枠",
    "answer": "そとわく",
    "meaning": "border"
  },
  {
    "question": "室町時代",
    "answer": "むろまちじだい",
    "meaning": "Muromachi period (1333-1573 CE)"
  },
  {
    "question": "脂が乗る",
    "answer": "あぶらがのる",
    "meaning": "to get into the swing of (one's work), to hit one's stride, (for a fish or bird) to put on fat for t"
  },
  {
    "question": "嫉む",
    "answer": "ねたむ,そねむ",
    "meaning": "to be jealous of, to envy, to begrudge"
  },
  {
    "question": "除菌",
    "answer": "じょきん",
    "meaning": "disinfection, sterile filtration"
  },
  {
    "question": "突き合う",
    "answer": "つきあう",
    "meaning": "to poke each other, to jab each other"
  },
  {
    "question": "懸け橋",
    "answer": "かけはし",
    "meaning": "suspension bridge, viaduct, temporary bridge, mediation, go-between"
  },
  {
    "question": "神経過敏",
    "answer": "しんけいかびん",
    "meaning": "oversensitive"
  },
  {
    "question": "安芸",
    "answer": "あき",
    "meaning": "Aki (former province located in the west of present-day Hiroshima Prefecture)"
  },
  {
    "question": "古道",
    "answer": "こどう,ふるみち",
    "meaning": "old road, ancient road, ancient methods, ancient moral teachings, the way of learning"
  },
  {
    "question": "中央銀行",
    "answer": "ちゅうおうぎんこう",
    "meaning": "(a) central bank"
  },
  {
    "question": "糸杉",
    "answer": "いとすぎ",
    "meaning": "cypress (Cupressus sp.)"
  },
  {
    "question": "霊剣",
    "answer": "れいけん",
    "meaning": "sword possessing mystical powers, virtuous sword"
  },
  {
    "question": "砲戦",
    "answer": "ほうせん",
    "meaning": "artillery battle"
  },
  {
    "question": "若殿",
    "answer": "わかとの",
    "meaning": "young lord, successor of one's current lord"
  },
  {
    "question": "紀元",
    "answer": "きげん",
    "meaning": "era, CE (Common Era), AD (Anno Domini)"
  },
  {
    "question": "櫃",
    "answer": "ひつ",
    "meaning": "chest, coffer, rice tub, lidded round, wooden container for cooked rice"
  },
  {
    "question": "御用商人",
    "answer": "ごようしょうにん",
    "meaning": "purveyor (to the government or Imperial Household)"
  },
  {
    "question": "濠",
    "answer": "ほり,ごう",
    "meaning": "moat, fosse, canal, ditch, trench, Australia"
  },
  {
    "question": "馬房",
    "answer": "ばぼう",
    "meaning": "stall (i.e. in a stable)"
  },
  {
    "question": "堪え難い",
    "answer": "たえがたい",
    "meaning": "unbearable, intolerable, unendurable"
  },
  {
    "question": "蕪",
    "answer": "かぶ,かぶら,かぶな",
    "meaning": "turnip (Brassica rapa)"
  },
  {
    "question": "焼き入れ",
    "answer": "やきいれ",
    "meaning": "quenching, hardening, tempering"
  },
  {
    "question": "三人称",
    "answer": "さんにんしょう",
    "meaning": "third person"
  },
  {
    "question": "電鉄",
    "answer": "でんてつ",
    "meaning": "electric railway"
  },
  {
    "question": "灰塵",
    "answer": "かいじん",
    "meaning": "ashes and dust"
  },
  {
    "question": "不朽",
    "answer": "ふきゅう",
    "meaning": "everlasting, immortal, eternal, enduring, undying, imperishable"
  },
  {
    "question": "奴隷解放",
    "answer": "どれいかいほう",
    "meaning": "emancipation of slaves"
  },
  {
    "question": "山彦",
    "answer": "やまびこ",
    "meaning": "echo (esp. one reverberating in the mountains), mountain god, mountain guardian deity"
  },
  {
    "question": "不動明王",
    "answer": "ふどうみょうおう",
    "meaning": "Acala (Wisdom King), Acalanatha, Fudō Myōō (Myō-ō), fierce Buddhist deity"
  },
  {
    "question": "片仮名",
    "answer": "かたかな",
    "meaning": "katakana, angular Japanese syllabary used primarily for loanwords"
  },
  {
    "question": "ピアノ線",
    "answer": "ピアノせん",
    "meaning": "piano wire"
  },
  {
    "question": "煙になる",
    "answer": "けむりになる,けむになる",
    "meaning": "to go up in smoke, to burn down, to be cremated, to vanish into thin air"
  },
  {
    "question": "砂袋",
    "answer": "すなぶくろ",
    "meaning": "sandbag, gizzard"
  },
  {
    "question": "菌類",
    "answer": "きんるい",
    "meaning": "fungus, fungi"
  },
  {
    "question": "駆け込み",
    "answer": "かけこみ",
    "meaning": "running in, rushing into, last-minute rush"
  },
  {
    "question": "蓑虫",
    "answer": "みのむし",
    "meaning": "bagworm, bagworm moth"
  },
  {
    "question": "疑る",
    "answer": "うたぐる",
    "meaning": "to doubt, to distrust, to be suspicious of, to suspect"
  },
  {
    "question": "吉凶",
    "answer": "きっきょう",
    "meaning": "good or bad luck, fortune"
  },
  {
    "question": "聖職",
    "answer": "せいしょく",
    "meaning": "sacred profession, holy orders, vocation, ministry"
  },
  {
    "question": "操業",
    "answer": "そうぎょう",
    "meaning": "operation (of a machine, factory, fishing boat, etc.), work"
  },
  {
    "question": "集音",
    "answer": "しゅうおん",
    "meaning": "sound collection"
  },
  {
    "question": "殿堂入り",
    "answer": "でんどういり",
    "meaning": "being inducted into a hall of fame"
  },
  {
    "question": "常備薬",
    "answer": "じょうびやく",
    "meaning": "household medicine"
  },
  {
    "question": "脱脂綿",
    "answer": "だっしめん",
    "meaning": "absorbent cotton"
  },
  {
    "question": "焼香",
    "answer": "しょうこう",
    "meaning": "burning (offer) incense"
  },
  {
    "question": "宿無し",
    "answer": "やどなし",
    "meaning": "homeless person, vagabond, tramp"
  },
  {
    "question": "角切り",
    "answer": "かくぎり",
    "meaning": "cut into cubes, diced"
  },
  {
    "question": "九分九厘",
    "answer": "くぶくりん",
    "meaning": "ten to one, nine cases out of ten"
  },
  {
    "question": "石器時代",
    "answer": "せっきじだい",
    "meaning": "Stone Age"
  },
  {
    "question": "一時凌ぎ",
    "answer": "いちじしのぎ",
    "meaning": "makeshift, temporary expedient, stopgap measure"
  },
  {
    "question": "致死率",
    "answer": "ちしりつ",
    "meaning": "case fatality rate"
  },
  {
    "question": "粗削り",
    "answer": "あらけずり",
    "meaning": "rough-hewn, incomplete, unrefined, still in the process of being formed"
  },
  {
    "question": "縫い直す",
    "answer": "ぬいなおす",
    "meaning": "to resew, to remake"
  },
  {
    "question": "毎時",
    "answer": "まいじ",
    "meaning": "every hour, hourly"
  },
  {
    "question": "善後策",
    "answer": "ぜんごさく",
    "meaning": "remedial measure, countermeasure, counter-measure, relief measure, remedy"
  },
  {
    "question": "皺くちゃ",
    "answer": "しわくちゃ",
    "meaning": "crumpled, wrinkled, crinkled, creased"
  },
  {
    "question": "週休",
    "answer": "しゅうきゅう",
    "meaning": "weekly holiday"
  },
  {
    "question": "音に聞く",
    "answer": "おとにきく",
    "meaning": "to be widely known, to be famous"
  },
  {
    "question": "足が早い",
    "answer": "あしがはやい",
    "meaning": "to be fast at walking and running, to be quick to spoil (of foodstuffs)"
  },
  {
    "question": "姫宮",
    "answer": "ひめみや",
    "meaning": "princess"
  },
  {
    "question": "音楽堂",
    "answer": "おんがくどう",
    "meaning": "concert hall"
  },
  {
    "question": "詩篇",
    "answer": "しへん",
    "meaning": "book containing a collection of poems, Psalms (book of the Bible)"
  },
  {
    "question": "教務",
    "answer": "きょうむ",
    "meaning": "school affairs, religious affairs"
  },
  {
    "question": "反帝",
    "answer": "はんてい",
    "meaning": "anti-imperialism"
  },
  {
    "question": "諸王",
    "answer": "しょおう",
    "meaning": "various kings, unproclaimed son of the imperial family"
  },
  {
    "question": "北山",
    "answer": "きたやま",
    "meaning": "northern hill"
  },
  {
    "question": "音楽祭",
    "answer": "おんがくさい",
    "meaning": "music festival"
  },
  {
    "question": "帆柱",
    "answer": "ほばしら",
    "meaning": "mast"
  },
  {
    "question": "鍵屋",
    "answer": "かぎや",
    "meaning": "locksmith"
  },
  {
    "question": "営倉",
    "answer": "えいそう",
    "meaning": "guardhouse, detention barracks"
  },
  {
    "question": "風の神",
    "answer": "かぜのかみ",
    "meaning": "god of winds"
  },
  {
    "question": "税務",
    "answer": "ぜいむ",
    "meaning": "taxation business"
  },
  {
    "question": "頒布",
    "answer": "はんぷ",
    "meaning": "distribution, circulation"
  },
  {
    "question": "海鮮料理",
    "answer": "かいせんりょうり",
    "meaning": "cuisine with fresh seafoods"
  },
  {
    "question": "天与",
    "answer": "てんよ",
    "meaning": "godsend, heaven's gift"
  },
  {
    "question": "鎖鎌",
    "answer": "くさりがま",
    "meaning": "sickle and chain (weapon)"
  },
  {
    "question": "軍司令官",
    "answer": "ぐんしれいかん",
    "meaning": "army commander"
  },
  {
    "question": "木皿",
    "answer": "きざら",
    "meaning": "wooden plate"
  },
  {
    "question": "五目",
    "answer": "ごもく",
    "meaning": "mixture of ingredients (originally five), mixture of minced vegetables, fish, and meat, mixed in a s"
  },
  {
    "question": "時限装置",
    "answer": "じげんそうち",
    "meaning": "timing device"
  },
  {
    "question": "退会",
    "answer": "たいかい",
    "meaning": "withdrawal from a group, resignation, secession, unsubscribing (mailing list, etc.)"
  },
  {
    "question": "陶製",
    "answer": "とうせい",
    "meaning": "ceramics"
  },
  {
    "question": "詰め将棋",
    "answer": "つめしょうぎ",
    "meaning": "chess problem, composed shogi problem"
  },
  {
    "question": "路線バス",
    "answer": "ろせんバス",
    "meaning": "bus on a regular route, fixed-route bus, transit bus"
  },
  {
    "question": "配電盤",
    "answer": "はいでんばん",
    "meaning": "distributing board (panel), switchboard"
  },
  {
    "question": "鶏卵",
    "answer": "けいらん",
    "meaning": "hen's egg"
  },
  {
    "question": "熟語",
    "answer": "じゅくご",
    "meaning": "kanji compound, idiom, idiomatic phrase"
  },
  {
    "question": "脳外科",
    "answer": "のうげか",
    "meaning": "brain surgery"
  },
  {
    "question": "爆速",
    "answer": "ばくそく",
    "meaning": "detonation velocity, velocity of detonation, VOD, extreme speed, explosive speed"
  },
  {
    "question": "無趣味",
    "answer": "むしゅみ",
    "meaning": "lacking of flair or refinement, lacking interests or hobbies, vulgarity, dull, prosaic"
  },
  {
    "question": "弱体",
    "answer": "じゃくたい",
    "meaning": "weak (organization, organisation)"
  },
  {
    "question": "誤謬",
    "answer": "ごびゅう",
    "meaning": "mistake, error, fallacy"
  },
  {
    "question": "悪習",
    "answer": "あくしゅう",
    "meaning": "bad habit, bad custom, evil practice, vice"
  },
  {
    "question": "瞬く間",
    "answer": "またたくま",
    "meaning": "brief moment, blink of an eye (time span)"
  },
  {
    "question": "値千金",
    "answer": "あたいせんきん",
    "meaning": "priceless, invaluable"
  },
  {
    "question": "ふん縛る",
    "answer": "ふんじばる",
    "meaning": "to tie fast, to arrest"
  },
  {
    "question": "飯の種",
    "answer": "めしのたね",
    "meaning": "means of making a living, source of income, bread and butter, livelihood"
  },
  {
    "question": "小松菜",
    "answer": "こまつな",
    "meaning": "Japanese mustard spinach (Brassica rapa var. perviridis)"
  },
  {
    "question": "二重構造",
    "answer": "にじゅうこうぞう",
    "meaning": "dual structure, double structure"
  },
  {
    "question": "選る",
    "answer": "よる,える,すぐる",
    "meaning": "to choose, to select"
  },
  {
    "question": "行動派",
    "answer": "こうどうは",
    "meaning": "active people, doers, people who get things done"
  },
  {
    "question": "霊神",
    "answer": "",
    "meaning": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "与圧",
    "answer": "よあつ",
    "meaning": "pressurization, pressurisation"
  },
  {
    "question": "葦原",
    "answer": "あしはら,あしわら,よしわら",
    "meaning": "reed bed"
  },
  {
    "question": "紬",
    "answer": "つむぎ",
    "meaning": "pongee, soft thin cloth woven from raw silk"
  },
  {
    "question": "僚機",
    "answer": "りょうき",
    "meaning": "consort plane"
  },
  {
    "question": "大聖",
    "answer": "たいせい,だいしょう",
    "meaning": "great sage, Buddha, high-ranked bodhisattva"
  },
  {
    "question": "准",
    "answer": "じゅん",
    "meaning": "semi-, quasi-, associate"
  },
  {
    "question": "士族",
    "answer": "しぞく",
    "meaning": "family or person with samurai ancestors"
  },
  {
    "question": "乗り組む",
    "answer": "のりくむ",
    "meaning": "to get on aboard, to join a ship"
  },
  {
    "question": "駅長",
    "answer": "えきちょう",
    "meaning": "station master"
  },
  {
    "question": "薄墨",
    "answer": "うすずみ",
    "meaning": "thin or diluted ink"
  },
  {
    "question": "反撥",
    "answer": "はんぱつ",
    "meaning": "opposition, rebellion, revolt, resistance, backlash, refusal, rebounding, recoiling, repulsion, rall"
  },
  {
    "question": "尋",
    "answer": "ひろ,じん",
    "meaning": "fathom"
  },
  {
    "question": "鉗子",
    "answer": "かんし",
    "meaning": "forceps"
  },
  {
    "question": "奥座敷",
    "answer": "おくざしき",
    "meaning": "inner parlor, inner parlour, salon, living room"
  },
  {
    "question": "線画",
    "answer": "せんが",
    "meaning": "line drawing"
  },
  {
    "question": "原子爆弾",
    "answer": "げんしばくだん",
    "meaning": "atomic bomb, A-bomb"
  },
  {
    "question": "迫撃",
    "answer": "はくげき",
    "meaning": "close attack"
  },
  {
    "question": "通行手形",
    "answer": "つうこうてがた",
    "meaning": "permit (to pass, enter, etc.), pass"
  },
  {
    "question": "名匠",
    "answer": "めいしょう",
    "meaning": "master craftsman, skillful worker"
  },
  {
    "question": "四駆",
    "answer": "よんく",
    "meaning": "four-wheel drive"
  },
  {
    "question": "闘犬",
    "answer": "とうけん",
    "meaning": "dogfight, dogfighting, fighting dog"
  },
  {
    "question": "石塀",
    "answer": "いしべい",
    "meaning": "stone wall"
  },
  {
    "question": "亜音速",
    "answer": "あおんそく",
    "meaning": "subsonic speed"
  },
  {
    "question": "憂愁",
    "answer": "ゆうしゅう",
    "meaning": "melancholy, gloom, grief"
  },
  {
    "question": "朱塗り",
    "answer": "しゅぬり",
    "meaning": "painting something vermillion, lacquering something vermillion, vermillion-lacquered object"
  },
  {
    "question": "大噓",
    "answer": "おおうそ",
    "meaning": "outrageous lie, outright lie"
  },
  {
    "question": "労役",
    "answer": "ろうえき",
    "meaning": "work, labor, labour, toil"
  },
  {
    "question": "走り抜く",
    "answer": "はしりぬく",
    "meaning": "to outrun, to run through to the end"
  },
  {
    "question": "息の下",
    "answer": "いきのした",
    "meaning": "gasp"
  },
  {
    "question": "鉄条網",
    "answer": "てつじょうもう",
    "meaning": "(barbed) wire entanglements"
  },
  {
    "question": "退官",
    "answer": "たいかん",
    "meaning": "retirement from office"
  },
  {
    "question": "差し戻す",
    "answer": "さしもどす",
    "meaning": "to send back, to refer back"
  },
  {
    "question": "惣菜パン",
    "answer": "そうざいパン",
    "meaning": "dressed bread, bread to which something has been added (sandwich, pirogi, etc.), stuffed bread (roll"
  },
  {
    "question": "戦陣",
    "answer": "せんじん",
    "meaning": "battle array, battle formation, battlefield"
  },
  {
    "question": "奇態",
    "answer": "きたい",
    "meaning": "strange, curious, odd"
  },
  {
    "question": "業務命令",
    "answer": "ぎょうむめいれい",
    "meaning": "order (to an employee from management)"
  },
  {
    "question": "甘辛",
    "answer": "あまから",
    "meaning": "sweetness and saltiness, salted and sweetened taste"
  },
  {
    "question": "敏",
    "answer": "びん",
    "meaning": "quick, nimble, agile, sharp, smart, clever"
  },
  {
    "question": "道路標識",
    "answer": "どうろひょうしき",
    "meaning": "road sign, signpost"
  },
  {
    "question": "変節",
    "answer": "へんせつ",
    "meaning": "betrayal, defection, treachery, apostasy"
  },
  {
    "question": "吸収合併",
    "answer": "きゅうしゅうがっぺい",
    "meaning": "merger, takeover"
  },
  {
    "question": "屋根瓦",
    "answer": "やねがわら",
    "meaning": "roof tile"
  },
  {
    "question": "知能指数",
    "answer": "ちのうしすう",
    "meaning": "intelligence quotient, IQ"
  },
  {
    "question": "具体化",
    "answer": "ぐたいか",
    "meaning": "embodiment, materialization, actualization, realization, taking form, taking shape"
  },
  {
    "question": "上積み",
    "answer": "うわづみ",
    "meaning": "deck cargo, upper layer of goods, extra, to pile on top of"
  },
  {
    "question": "不夜城",
    "answer": "ふやじょう",
    "meaning": "nightless gay quarters, nightless city"
  },
  {
    "question": "目覚しい",
    "answer": "めざましい",
    "meaning": "remarkable, striking, brilliant, splendid, spectacular, wonderful"
  },
  {
    "question": "不首尾",
    "answer": "ふしゅび",
    "meaning": "failure, poor result, disfavour, disfavor, unpopularity"
  },
  {
    "question": "折り込む",
    "answer": "おりこむ",
    "meaning": "to fold inside"
  },
  {
    "question": "拝読",
    "answer": "はいどく",
    "meaning": "reading"
  },
  {
    "question": "朝寝",
    "answer": "あさね",
    "meaning": "sleeping late in the morning"
  },
  {
    "question": "跳ね返り",
    "answer": "はねかえり",
    "meaning": "rebounding, recovery, repercussions, tomboy, rashness, incautiousness"
  },
  {
    "question": "風花",
    "answer": "かざばな,かざはな",
    "meaning": "flurry of snow in a clear sky, winter wind which brings scattered snowflakes or raindrops, skin erup"
  },
  {
    "question": "矢張り",
    "answer": "やはり",
    "meaning": "too, also, likewise, either, still, as before, even so, either way, nonetheless, in any event, all t"
  },
  {
    "question": "助産師",
    "answer": "じょさんし",
    "meaning": "midwife"
  },
  {
    "question": "画商",
    "answer": "がしょう",
    "meaning": "picture dealer, commercial art gallery"
  },
  {
    "question": "灰色熊",
    "answer": "はいいろぐま",
    "meaning": "grizzly bear (Ursus arctos horribilis)"
  },
  {
    "question": "念写",
    "answer": "ねんしゃ,ねんず",
    "meaning": "spirit photography, psychic photography, thoughtography"
  },
  {
    "question": "鬼殺し",
    "answer": "おにころし,おにごろし",
    "meaning": "strong sake, firewater, rotgut"
  },
  {
    "question": "継嗣",
    "answer": "けいし",
    "meaning": "successor, heir, heiress"
  },
  {
    "question": "殿軍",
    "answer": "でんぐん",
    "meaning": "rear guard"
  },
  {
    "question": "相転移",
    "answer": "そうてんい",
    "meaning": "phase transition, phase change, phase transformation"
  },
  {
    "question": "充塡",
    "answer": "じゅうてん",
    "meaning": "filling (up), replenishing, filling in (tooth), loading (gun with ammunition, camera with film, etc."
  },
  {
    "question": "売場",
    "answer": "うりば",
    "meaning": "selling area, counter, section, department, sales floor, favorable time to sell, good time to sell"
  },
  {
    "question": "講和条約",
    "answer": "こうわじょうやく",
    "meaning": "peace treaty"
  },
  {
    "question": "独立宣言",
    "answer": "どくりつせんげん",
    "meaning": "declaration of independence"
  },
  {
    "question": "繊手",
    "answer": "せんしゅ",
    "meaning": "slender hand"
  },
  {
    "question": "指遣い",
    "answer": "ゆびづかい",
    "meaning": "fingering (of a musical instrument)"
  },
  {
    "question": "早産",
    "answer": "そうざん",
    "meaning": "premature birth"
  },
  {
    "question": "給湯",
    "answer": "きゅうとう",
    "meaning": "hot-water supply"
  },
  {
    "question": "自閉",
    "answer": "じへい",
    "meaning": "social withdrawal (in schizophrenia), autosynnoia, social isolation, autism"
  },
  {
    "question": "隠れん坊",
    "answer": "かくれんぼ,かくれんぼう",
    "meaning": "hide-and-seek (game), hide-and-go-seek"
  },
  {
    "question": "戦傷",
    "answer": "せんしょう",
    "meaning": "war wound"
  },
  {
    "question": "眼孔",
    "answer": "がんこう",
    "meaning": "eye socket"
  },
  {
    "question": "友チョコ",
    "answer": "ともチョコ",
    "meaning": "chocolate given to a friend (on Valentine's day)"
  },
  {
    "question": "幾何学",
    "answer": "きかがく",
    "meaning": "geometry"
  },
  {
    "question": "位する",
    "answer": "くらいする",
    "meaning": "to rank (as), to occupy (a position), to be located (in), to be situated"
  },
  {
    "question": "造型",
    "answer": "ぞうけい",
    "meaning": "molding, moulding, shaping, modelling (i.e. plastic arts), modeling"
  },
  {
    "question": "原隊",
    "answer": "げんたい",
    "meaning": "one's home unit"
  },
  {
    "question": "竣工",
    "answer": "しゅんこう",
    "meaning": "completion of construction"
  },
  {
    "question": "天衣無縫",
    "answer": "てんいむほう",
    "meaning": "perfect beauty with no trace of artifice, flawless"
  },
  {
    "question": "陣取り",
    "answer": "じんとり",
    "meaning": "children's game in which the aim is to occupy the other's home base, taking a place, securing a posi"
  },
  {
    "question": "粒々",
    "answer": "つぶつぶ",
    "meaning": "grains, lumps, granulated, lumpy, bumpiness"
  },
  {
    "question": "渇",
    "answer": "かつ",
    "meaning": "thirst"
  },
  {
    "question": "気運",
    "answer": "きうん",
    "meaning": "trend, tendency, momentum"
  },
  {
    "question": "細密",
    "answer": "さいみつ",
    "meaning": "detailed knowledge, finely detailed"
  },
  {
    "question": "食物繊維",
    "answer": "しょくもつせんい",
    "meaning": "dietary fiber, dietary fibre"
  },
  {
    "question": "昼行灯",
    "answer": "ひるあんどん",
    "meaning": "dunce, blockhead, inattentive person, (a) lantern at noon"
  },
  {
    "question": "透かし",
    "answer": "すかし",
    "meaning": "watermark (in a stamp, banknote, etc.), openwork (engraving, carving, etc.)"
  },
  {
    "question": "内弁慶",
    "answer": "うちべんけい",
    "meaning": "someone haughty and boastful at home but meek and reserved outside, being a lion at home and a mouse"
  },
  {
    "question": "涼み",
    "answer": "すずみ",
    "meaning": "cooling oneself, enjoying the cool air"
  },
  {
    "question": "脈を取る",
    "answer": "みゃくをとる",
    "meaning": "to take someone's pulse"
  },
  {
    "question": "べた惚れ",
    "answer": "べたぼれ",
    "meaning": "(falling) deeply in love"
  },
  {
    "question": "賛否",
    "answer": "さんぴ",
    "meaning": "yes and no, for and against"
  },
  {
    "question": "円熟",
    "answer": "えんじゅく",
    "meaning": "ripeness, mellowness, maturity, perfection"
  },
  {
    "question": "本位",
    "answer": "ほんい",
    "meaning": "standard, basis, principle"
  },
  {
    "question": "火箸",
    "answer": "ひばし,こじ",
    "meaning": "long metal chopsticks (for handling charcoal, esp. in a brazier), fire tongs, tongs (esp. for incens"
  },
  {
    "question": "博愛主義",
    "answer": "はくあいしゅぎ",
    "meaning": "philanthropism"
  },
  {
    "question": "鉱員",
    "answer": "こういん",
    "meaning": "miner"
  },
  {
    "question": "荷駄",
    "answer": "にだ",
    "meaning": "pack, horseload"
  },
  {
    "question": "定命",
    "answer": "じょうみょう,ていめい",
    "meaning": "one's predestined length of life, destiny, fate"
  },
  {
    "question": "雨期",
    "answer": "うき",
    "meaning": "rainy season"
  },
  {
    "question": "補給基地",
    "answer": "ほきゅうきち",
    "meaning": "supply base, storage depot"
  },
  {
    "question": "噺",
    "answer": "はなし",
    "meaning": "topic, subject, rumor, talk, hearsay, tale, story, fable, circumstances, particulars"
  },
  {
    "question": "秘蹟",
    "answer": "ひせき",
    "meaning": "sacrament"
  },
  {
    "question": "弓弦",
    "answer": "ゆみづる,ゆづる,ゆづら",
    "meaning": "bowstring"
  },
  {
    "question": "石英",
    "answer": "せきえい",
    "meaning": "quartz"
  },
  {
    "question": "国際会議",
    "answer": "こくさいかいぎ",
    "meaning": "international conference"
  },
  {
    "question": "築地",
    "answer": "ついじ,つきじ",
    "meaning": "mud wall with a roof, roofed mud wall, reclaimed land"
  },
  {
    "question": "金融機関",
    "answer": "きんゆうきかん",
    "meaning": "financial institutions, banking facilities"
  },
  {
    "question": "貝柱",
    "answer": "かいばしら",
    "meaning": "adductor muscle, adductor muscle of a bivalve (e.g. scallop, etc.)"
  },
  {
    "question": "腸詰め",
    "answer": "ちょうづめ",
    "meaning": "sausage"
  },
  {
    "question": "白熊",
    "answer": "しろくま,はぐま",
    "meaning": "polar bear (Ursus maritimus), yak tail hair"
  },
  {
    "question": "乳鉢",
    "answer": "にゅうばち,にゅうはち",
    "meaning": "mortar"
  },
  {
    "question": "自爆テロ",
    "answer": "じばくテロ",
    "meaning": "(terrorist) suicide bombing"
  },
  {
    "question": "協同",
    "answer": "きょうどう",
    "meaning": "doing together (as equals), sharing, common (land, etc.), joint (statement, etc.), cooperation, co-o"
  },
  {
    "question": "引出し",
    "answer": "ひきだし",
    "meaning": "drawer, withdrawal (of money from an account), variety of knowledge and experience useful for handli"
  },
  {
    "question": "叙述",
    "answer": "じょじゅつ",
    "meaning": "description"
  },
  {
    "question": "甘酢",
    "answer": "あまず",
    "meaning": "sweet vinegar"
  },
  {
    "question": "紙風船",
    "answer": "かみふうせん",
    "meaning": "paper balloon"
  },
  {
    "question": "貯水槽",
    "answer": "ちょすいそう",
    "meaning": "water tank"
  },
  {
    "question": "縦縞",
    "answer": "たてじま",
    "meaning": "vertical stripes, striped fabric"
  },
  {
    "question": "小社",
    "answer": "しょうしゃ",
    "meaning": "(our) company, (my) company, small company, small shrine"
  },
  {
    "question": "洗車",
    "answer": "せんしゃ",
    "meaning": "car washing"
  },
  {
    "question": "思い遣り",
    "answer": "おもいやり",
    "meaning": "consideration, thoughtfulness, sympathy, compassion, feeling, kindness, understanding, regard, kindh"
  },
  {
    "question": "哺乳瓶",
    "answer": "ほにゅうびん",
    "meaning": "baby bottle"
  },
  {
    "question": "共同経営",
    "answer": "きょうどうけいえい",
    "meaning": "joint management"
  },
  {
    "question": "舞台劇",
    "answer": "ぶたいげき",
    "meaning": "stage play"
  },
  {
    "question": "召使う",
    "answer": "めしつかう",
    "meaning": "to employ, to hire (a servant)"
  },
  {
    "question": "失調",
    "answer": "しっちょう",
    "meaning": "lack of harmony, lack of balance, lack of coordination, malfunction, ataxia"
  },
  {
    "question": "商用",
    "answer": "しょうよう",
    "meaning": "on business, for business, business purpose"
  },
  {
    "question": "瑕",
    "answer": "きず",
    "meaning": "wound, injury, cut, gash, bruise, scratch, scrape, scar, chip, crack, nick, flaw, defect, weakness,"
  },
  {
    "question": "就労",
    "answer": "しゅうろう",
    "meaning": "working, being employed, being hired"
  },
  {
    "question": "汗腺",
    "answer": "かんせん",
    "meaning": "sweat gland"
  },
  {
    "question": "抜け抜け",
    "answer": "ぬけぬけ",
    "meaning": "freely, impudently, brazenly, shamelessly, however one wishes"
  },
  {
    "question": "古狸",
    "answer": "ふるだぬき",
    "meaning": "old badger, veteran, oldtimer, schemer, old fox"
  },
  {
    "question": "非常手段",
    "answer": "ひじょうしゅだん",
    "meaning": "emergency measures"
  },
  {
    "question": "鬼嫁",
    "answer": "おによめ",
    "meaning": "cruel wife, termagant wife, wife from hell"
  },
  {
    "question": "介添え",
    "answer": "かいぞえ",
    "meaning": "helper, assistant, second"
  },
  {
    "question": "出鼻",
    "answer": "でばな,ではな",
    "meaning": "projecting part (of a headland, etc.), moment of departure, (on the) point of going out, outset, sta"
  },
  {
    "question": "歯抜け",
    "answer": "はぬけ",
    "meaning": "having missing teeth, toothlessness"
  },
  {
    "question": "参考文献",
    "answer": "さんこうぶんけん",
    "meaning": "works cited, references"
  },
  {
    "question": "熱射病",
    "answer": "ねっしゃびょう",
    "meaning": "heatstroke"
  },
  {
    "question": "愛の鞭",
    "answer": "あいのむち",
    "meaning": "(lesson in) tough love"
  },
  {
    "question": "畳み込む",
    "answer": "たたみこむ",
    "meaning": "to fold in, to bear deep in mind, to follow up"
  },
  {
    "question": "引き潮",
    "answer": "ひきしお",
    "meaning": "ebb tide"
  },
  {
    "question": "居住性",
    "answer": "きょじゅうせい",
    "meaning": "liveability, livability"
  },
  {
    "question": "厳に",
    "answer": "げんに",
    "meaning": "strictly, severely, rigidly"
  },
  {
    "question": "寿退社",
    "answer": "ことぶきたいしゃ",
    "meaning": "resigning from a company on marriage (of a woman)"
  },
  {
    "question": "行政機関",
    "answer": "ぎょうせいきかん",
    "meaning": "administrative organ, administrative body"
  },
  {
    "question": "天分",
    "answer": "てんぶん",
    "meaning": "one's nature, talents, destiny, mission, sphere of activity"
  },
  {
    "question": "先例",
    "answer": "せんれい",
    "meaning": "precedent"
  },
  {
    "question": "白眼視",
    "answer": "はくがんし",
    "meaning": "looking coldly on, looking upon disapprovingly, frowning on"
  },
  {
    "question": "表面張力",
    "answer": "ひょうめんちょうりょく",
    "meaning": "surface tension"
  },
  {
    "question": "化学薬品",
    "answer": "かがくやくひん",
    "meaning": "chemicals"
  },
  {
    "question": "盛り沢山",
    "answer": "もりだくさん",
    "meaning": "many, varied, all sorts, crowded, large (e.g. helping)"
  },
  {
    "question": "賃",
    "answer": "ちん",
    "meaning": "hire (charge), rent, charge, fare, fee, freight, wages, payment"
  },
  {
    "question": "見忘れる",
    "answer": "みわすれる",
    "meaning": "to forget, to fail to recognize, to fail to recognise"
  },
  {
    "question": "太鼓持ち",
    "answer": "たいこもち",
    "meaning": "professional jester, professional entertainer, comedian, buffoon, flatterer, sycophant, brown-noser"
  },
  {
    "question": "私信",
    "answer": "ししん",
    "meaning": "private message"
  },
  {
    "question": "辛勝",
    "answer": "しんしょう",
    "meaning": "narrow victory"
  },
  {
    "question": "淫具",
    "answer": "いんぐ",
    "meaning": "dildo"
  },
  {
    "question": "東ドイツ",
    "answer": "ひがしドイツ",
    "meaning": "East Germany (1949-1990), German Democratic Republic"
  },
  {
    "question": "韓",
    "answer": "から",
    "meaning": "China (sometimes also used in ref. to Korea or other foreign countries)"
  },
  {
    "question": "石盤",
    "answer": "せきばん",
    "meaning": "slate, stone slab"
  },
  {
    "question": "采",
    "answer": "さい,さえ",
    "meaning": "dice, die, baton (of command)"
  },
  {
    "question": "坑夫",
    "answer": "こうふ",
    "meaning": "miner"
  },
  {
    "question": "車輛",
    "answer": "しゃりょう",
    "meaning": "rolling stock, railroad cars, wheeled vehicles"
  },
  {
    "question": "共感覚",
    "answer": "きょうかんかく",
    "meaning": "synesthesia (synaesthesia)"
  },
  {
    "question": "お受験",
    "answer": "おじゅけん",
    "meaning": "competitive entrance examinations for prestigious kindergartens and elementary schools"
  },
  {
    "question": "三塁",
    "answer": "さんるい",
    "meaning": "third base"
  },
  {
    "question": "芍薬",
    "answer": "しゃくやく",
    "meaning": "Chinese peony (Paeonia lactiflora)"
  },
  {
    "question": "総務省",
    "answer": "そうむしょう",
    "meaning": "Ministry of Internal Affairs and Communications"
  },
  {
    "question": "国債",
    "answer": "こくさい",
    "meaning": "national debt, national securities, government bonds, government securities"
  },
  {
    "question": "軍功",
    "answer": "ぐんこう",
    "meaning": "meritorious war service"
  },
  {
    "question": "二等兵",
    "answer": "にとうへい",
    "meaning": "private (e-1) (US)"
  },
  {
    "question": "基板",
    "answer": "きばん",
    "meaning": "substrate, (computer) circuit board"
  },
  {
    "question": "戦術家",
    "answer": "せんじゅつか",
    "meaning": "tactician, strategist"
  },
  {
    "question": "鉄腕",
    "answer": "てつわん",
    "meaning": "strong arm"
  },
  {
    "question": "莢",
    "answer": "さや",
    "meaning": "shell (e.g. of a pea), pod, hull"
  },
  {
    "question": "石灰岩",
    "answer": "せっかいがん",
    "meaning": "limestone"
  },
  {
    "question": "原油",
    "answer": "げんゆ",
    "meaning": "crude oil"
  },
  {
    "question": "重工業",
    "answer": "じゅうこうぎょう",
    "meaning": "heavy industry"
  },
  {
    "question": "感染源",
    "answer": "かんせんげん",
    "meaning": "source of infection"
  },
  {
    "question": "小勢",
    "answer": "こぜい",
    "meaning": "a small force"
  },
  {
    "question": "応援歌",
    "answer": "おうえんか",
    "meaning": "cheering song, supporters' song"
  },
  {
    "question": "連作",
    "answer": "れんさく",
    "meaning": "planting a field with the same crop each year, repeated cultivation, monocropping, collaborative lit"
  },
  {
    "question": "火山灰",
    "answer": "かざんばい",
    "meaning": "volcanic ash"
  },
  {
    "question": "礼賛",
    "answer": "らいさん",
    "meaning": "praise, worship, adoration, glorification"
  },
  {
    "question": "大吟醸",
    "answer": "だいぎんじょう",
    "meaning": "top-quality sake brewed from rice grains milled to 50% of weight or less"
  },
  {
    "question": "機械油",
    "answer": "きかいあぶら,きかいゆ",
    "meaning": "machine oil"
  },
  {
    "question": "成田空港",
    "answer": "",
    "meaning": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "漁場",
    "answer": "ぎょじょう,ぎょば,りょうば",
    "meaning": "fishing grounds, permitted fishing zone"
  },
  {
    "question": "断面図",
    "answer": "だんめんず",
    "meaning": "cross-section view"
  },
  {
    "question": "類人猿",
    "answer": "るいじんえん",
    "meaning": "anthropoid ape, anthropoid, ape"
  },
  {
    "question": "銘菓",
    "answer": "めいか",
    "meaning": "excellent sweet, confection of an established name"
  },
  {
    "question": "身包み",
    "answer": "みぐるみ",
    "meaning": "all one has, all one's possessions"
  },
  {
    "question": "不用",
    "answer": "ふよう",
    "meaning": "disused, unused, useless, wasteful, of no use"
  },
  {
    "question": "紛らす",
    "answer": "まぎらす",
    "meaning": "to divert (e.g. one's mind), to distract, to relieve (e.g. boredom), to conceal (e.g. one's sorrow w"
  },
  {
    "question": "畑作",
    "answer": "はたさく",
    "meaning": "dry field farming, dry field crop"
  },
  {
    "question": "先祖伝来",
    "answer": "せんぞでんらい",
    "meaning": "inherited, family (heirloom), ancestral"
  },
  {
    "question": "植え込む",
    "answer": "うえこむ",
    "meaning": "to plant, to insert"
  },
  {
    "question": "釣り餌",
    "answer": "つりえ,つりえさ",
    "meaning": "bait (for fishing)"
  },
  {
    "question": "写り",
    "answer": "うつり",
    "meaning": "projection, reflection, image, reception (e.g. TV), picture quality, match, harmony"
  },
  {
    "question": "吝か",
    "answer": "やぶさか",
    "meaning": "reluctant, hesitant"
  },
  {
    "question": "水玉模様",
    "answer": "みずたまもよう",
    "meaning": "polka dots"
  },
  {
    "question": "平米",
    "answer": "へいべい",
    "meaning": "square metre, square meter"
  },
  {
    "question": "調子外れ",
    "answer": "ちょうしはずれ",
    "meaning": "discord, disharmony, false note, being out of tune"
  },
  {
    "question": "分け目",
    "answer": "わけめ",
    "meaning": "dividing line, parting (of the hair), partition, crisis"
  },
  {
    "question": "擲る",
    "answer": "なぐる",
    "meaning": "to strike, to hit, to beat, to punch"
  },
  {
    "question": "肉が付く",
    "answer": "ししがつく,にくがつく",
    "meaning": "to gain (put on) weight"
  },
  {
    "question": "一幅",
    "answer": "いっぷく,ひとはば,ひとの",
    "meaning": "(a) scroll, cloth width, single breadth (cloth measurement, 30-38 cm)"
  },
  {
    "question": "臆面",
    "answer": "おくめん",
    "meaning": "shy face"
  },
  {
    "question": "槐",
    "answer": "えんじゅ",
    "meaning": "Japanese pagoda tree (Sophora japonica)"
  },
  {
    "question": "香車",
    "answer": "きょうしゃ",
    "meaning": "lance"
  },
  {
    "question": "星図",
    "answer": "せいず",
    "meaning": "star map"
  },
  {
    "question": "凜々",
    "answer": "りんりん",
    "meaning": "severe, intense, awe-inspiring, commanding, biting, bitter (cold), piercing, frigid"
  },
  {
    "question": "相剋",
    "answer": "そうこく",
    "meaning": "rivalry"
  },
  {
    "question": "舵輪",
    "answer": "だりん",
    "meaning": "helm, (ship's) steering wheel"
  },
  {
    "question": "玉璽",
    "answer": "ぎょくじ",
    "meaning": "sovereign's seal"
  },
  {
    "question": "内弟子",
    "answer": "うちでし",
    "meaning": "private pupil, apprentice"
  },
  {
    "question": "両性具有",
    "answer": "りょうせいぐゆう",
    "meaning": "androgynous, hermaphroditic"
  },
  {
    "question": "首脳会議",
    "answer": "しゅのうかいぎ",
    "meaning": "summit meeting, top-level conference"
  },
  {
    "question": "鍼",
    "answer": "はり",
    "meaning": "(acupuncture) needle, acupuncture"
  },
  {
    "question": "属領",
    "answer": "ぞくりょう",
    "meaning": "possession, dependency, territory, dominion"
  },
  {
    "question": "垂れ耳",
    "answer": "たれみみ",
    "meaning": "lop-eared"
  },
  {
    "question": "首狩り",
    "answer": "くびかり,くびがり",
    "meaning": "headhunting, collecting the heads of dead enemies as trophies"
  },
  {
    "question": "拉げる",
    "answer": "ひしゃげる,へしゃげる,ひしげる",
    "meaning": "to be crushed, to be squashed (flat), to be discouraged"
  },
  {
    "question": "飯盒",
    "answer": "はんごう",
    "meaning": "(soldier's) cooking utensils, mess kit, outdoor (camping) cooking utensils"
  },
  {
    "question": "灰褐色",
    "answer": "はいかっしょく",
    "meaning": "grey-brown, gray-brown, dun"
  },
  {
    "question": "免罪",
    "answer": "めんざい",
    "meaning": "acquittal, pardon, papal indulgence"
  },
  {
    "question": "疾病",
    "answer": "しっぺい",
    "meaning": "illness, disease"
  },
  {
    "question": "利率",
    "answer": "りりつ",
    "meaning": "interest rate"
  },
  {
    "question": "人差指",
    "answer": "ひとさしゆび",
    "meaning": "index finger, forefinger"
  },
  {
    "question": "五輪",
    "answer": "ごりん",
    "meaning": "Olympic rings, Olympics"
  },
  {
    "question": "福神漬け",
    "answer": "ふくじんづけ",
    "meaning": "sliced vegetables pickled in soy sauce"
  },
  {
    "question": "客分",
    "answer": "きゃくぶん",
    "meaning": "treatment as a guest, guest"
  },
  {
    "question": "木切れ",
    "answer": "きぎれ",
    "meaning": "piece of wood (cut from a larger piece), chip of wood, block of wood"
  },
  {
    "question": "空咳",
    "answer": "からせき,からぜき",
    "meaning": "dry cough, hacking cough, intentional cough (i.e. to get someone's attention)"
  },
  {
    "question": "海溝",
    "answer": "かいこう",
    "meaning": "ocean trench, deep"
  },
  {
    "question": "縒る",
    "answer": "よる",
    "meaning": "to twist (yarn), to lay (rope)"
  },
  {
    "question": "試用",
    "answer": "しよう",
    "meaning": "trial, experimental use"
  },
  {
    "question": "算定",
    "answer": "さんてい",
    "meaning": "calculation, estimation, computation"
  },
  {
    "question": "置時計",
    "answer": "おきどけい",
    "meaning": "clock to be placed on tables, bookshelves, etc. (as opposed to a watch)"
  },
  {
    "question": "春菊",
    "answer": "しゅんぎく",
    "meaning": "edible chrysanthemum (Chrysanthemum coronarium), crown daisy, garland chrysanthemum"
  },
  {
    "question": "風采",
    "answer": "ふうさい",
    "meaning": "appearance, air, mien, getup"
  },
  {
    "question": "思い煩う",
    "answer": "おもいわずらう",
    "meaning": "to worry about, to be vexed"
  },
  {
    "question": "豪壮",
    "answer": "ごうそう",
    "meaning": "splendour, splendor, magnificence, grandeur"
  },
  {
    "question": "呵々大笑",
    "answer": "かかたいしょう",
    "meaning": "laughing a ringing laugh, having a hearty laugh, roaring with laughter"
  },
  {
    "question": "侘び",
    "answer": "わび",
    "meaning": "taste for the simple and quiet, rustic simplicity, austere refinement, wabi, enjoyment of a quiet li"
  },
  {
    "question": "鬼才",
    "answer": "きさい",
    "meaning": "wizard, genius, remarkable talent, exceptional ability"
  },
  {
    "question": "化学的",
    "answer": "かがくてき",
    "meaning": "chemical"
  },
  {
    "question": "近視",
    "answer": "きんし",
    "meaning": "myopia, shortsightedness, nearsightedness"
  },
  {
    "question": "湿らす",
    "answer": "しめらす",
    "meaning": "to dampen, to moisten"
  },
  {
    "question": "一癖",
    "answer": "ひとくせ",
    "meaning": "trait, peculiarity, idiosyncrasy"
  },
  {
    "question": "裸一貫",
    "answer": "はだかいっかん",
    "meaning": "having nothing except one's body, having empty pockets, being penniless"
  },
  {
    "question": "迷惑千万",
    "answer": "めいわくせんばん",
    "meaning": "great nuisance, extremely annoying, quite embarrassing"
  },
  {
    "question": "手洗",
    "answer": "てあらい",
    "meaning": "washing one's hands, water (or basin, etc.) for washing one's hands, restroom, lavatory, toilet, han"
  },
  {
    "question": "鴻",
    "answer": "ひしくい,おおとり",
    "meaning": "bean goose (Anser fabalis), large bird, peng (in Chinese mythology, giant bird said to transform fro"
  },
  {
    "question": "十号",
    "answer": "じゅうごう",
    "meaning": "ten epithets (of Buddha)"
  },
  {
    "question": "桑田",
    "answer": "そうでん",
    "meaning": "mulberry plantation"
  },
  {
    "question": "金将",
    "answer": "きんしょう",
    "meaning": "gold general"
  },
  {
    "question": "冬月",
    "answer": "とうげつ",
    "meaning": "winter, winter season, winter moon"
  },
  {
    "question": "欧",
    "answer": "おう",
    "meaning": "Europe"
  },
  {
    "question": "撫する",
    "answer": "ぶする",
    "meaning": "to stroke, to caress"
  },
  {
    "question": "推進器",
    "answer": "すいしんき",
    "meaning": "propeller"
  },
  {
    "question": "助監督",
    "answer": "じょかんとく",
    "meaning": "assistant director (in taking professional movies)"
  },
  {
    "question": "義勇",
    "answer": "ぎゆう",
    "meaning": "heroism, loyalty and courage"
  },
  {
    "question": "水盤",
    "answer": "すいばん",
    "meaning": "shallow bowl for displaying flowers, bonsai, etc."
  },
  {
    "question": "東岸",
    "answer": "とうがん",
    "meaning": "eastern coast, east bank"
  },
  {
    "question": "軍歌",
    "answer": "ぐんか",
    "meaning": "war song"
  },
  {
    "question": "讃美歌",
    "answer": "さんびか",
    "meaning": "hymn, hymnal"
  },
  {
    "question": "あがり症",
    "answer": "あがりしょう",
    "meaning": "stage fright, social anxiety disorder, social phobia"
  },
  {
    "question": "比叡山",
    "answer": "ひえいざん",
    "meaning": "Mt. Hiei (in Kyoto)"
  },
  {
    "question": "黄褐色",
    "answer": "おうかっしょく",
    "meaning": "yellowish-brown"
  },
  {
    "question": "百花繚乱",
    "answer": "ひゃっかりょうらん",
    "meaning": "a gathering of many beautiful women (talented people), simultaneous emergence of many talents and ac"
  },
  {
    "question": "枝道",
    "answer": "えだみち",
    "meaning": "branch road, byroad, side street, digression"
  },
  {
    "question": "秘密裡",
    "answer": "ひみつり",
    "meaning": "behind closed doors, behind-the-scenes, (under the veil of) secrecy"
  },
  {
    "question": "皆伝",
    "answer": "かいでん",
    "meaning": "initiation into an art or discipline"
  },
  {
    "question": "初段",
    "answer": "しょだん",
    "meaning": "first rank in the senior class (in martial arts, go, etc.), lowest rank, one dan"
  },
  {
    "question": "山河",
    "answer": "さんが",
    "meaning": "mountains and rivers, natural surroundings"
  },
  {
    "question": "骨董屋",
    "answer": "こっとうや",
    "meaning": "antique store"
  },
  {
    "question": "リーグ戦",
    "answer": "リーグせん",
    "meaning": "league match"
  },
  {
    "question": "東進",
    "answer": "とうしん",
    "meaning": "proceeding east"
  },
  {
    "question": "誅殺",
    "answer": "ちゅうさつ",
    "meaning": "execution of a criminal"
  },
  {
    "question": "強攻",
    "answer": "きょうこう",
    "meaning": "forced attack, risk-taking attack, aggressive attack"
  },
  {
    "question": "相関",
    "answer": "そうかん",
    "meaning": "correlation, interrelation"
  },
  {
    "question": "機銃掃射",
    "answer": "きじゅうそうしゃ",
    "meaning": "machine-gun fire"
  },
  {
    "question": "男系",
    "answer": "だんけい",
    "meaning": "male lineage"
  },
  {
    "question": "真黒",
    "answer": "まっくろ",
    "meaning": "pitch black"
  },
  {
    "question": "巡航速度",
    "answer": "じゅんこうそくど",
    "meaning": "cruising speed"
  },
  {
    "question": "刃毀れ",
    "answer": "はこぼれ",
    "meaning": "nick in a blade (sword, knife), chip in a blade"
  },
  {
    "question": "屍を晒す",
    "answer": "しかばねをさらす",
    "meaning": "to die on the battlefield"
  },
  {
    "question": "含有量",
    "answer": "がんゆうりょう",
    "meaning": "content (of a mineral, etc.)"
  },
  {
    "question": "身代",
    "answer": "しんだい",
    "meaning": "fortune, property"
  },
  {
    "question": "飲用",
    "answer": "いんよう",
    "meaning": "drinking"
  },
  {
    "question": "一本化",
    "answer": "いっぽんか",
    "meaning": "unification, centralization, integration, drawing things together, working out a common policy, cons"
  },
  {
    "question": "鼻緒",
    "answer": "はなお",
    "meaning": "sandal strap, geta strap"
  },
  {
    "question": "寛ぎ",
    "answer": "くつろぎ",
    "meaning": "ease, relaxation, comfort, unwinding"
  },
  {
    "question": "筆圧",
    "answer": "ひつあつ",
    "meaning": "strength of a brushstroke"
  },
  {
    "question": "薄雲",
    "answer": "うすぐも",
    "meaning": "thin clouds"
  },
  {
    "question": "傲る",
    "answer": "おごる",
    "meaning": "to give (someone) a treat, to be extravagant, to live luxuriously, to be proud, to be haughty"
  },
  {
    "question": "込み合う",
    "answer": "こみあう",
    "meaning": "to be crowded, to be packed, to be jammed"
  },
  {
    "question": "寝首",
    "answer": "ねくび",
    "meaning": "head of a sleeping person"
  },
  {
    "question": "採択",
    "answer": "さいたく",
    "meaning": "adoption, selection, choice"
  },
  {
    "question": "供花",
    "answer": "きょうか,くげ,くうげ",
    "meaning": "offering of flowers (at shrine, grave, etc.), floral tribute"
  },
  {
    "question": "山人",
    "answer": "やまびと,さんじん",
    "meaning": "mountain folk, hermit, mountain wizard, word used as part of a pseudonym by artists, writers, etc."
  },
  {
    "question": "翻案",
    "answer": "ほんあん",
    "meaning": "adaptation (of a novel, play, etc.)"
  },
  {
    "question": "同位",
    "answer": "どうい",
    "meaning": "the same rank, the same digit"
  },
  {
    "question": "視座",
    "answer": "しざ",
    "meaning": "vantage point, viewpoint, standpoint, outlook"
  },
  {
    "question": "隷従",
    "answer": "れいじゅう",
    "meaning": "slavery"
  },
  {
    "question": "篩",
    "answer": "ふるい",
    "meaning": "sieve, sifter, screen, screening (jobs, candidates, etc.)"
  },
  {
    "question": "第六天",
    "answer": "だいろくてん",
    "meaning": "sixth heaven (of the desire realm)"
  },
  {
    "question": "髷",
    "answer": "まげ",
    "meaning": "bun (hairstyle), chignon, topknot"
  },
  {
    "question": "育毛剤",
    "answer": "いくもうざい",
    "meaning": "hair growth formula, hair growth agent"
  },
  {
    "question": "滝行",
    "answer": "たきぎょう",
    "meaning": "meditating while sitting under a waterfall (Buddhist practice)"
  },
  {
    "question": "高僧",
    "answer": "こうそう",
    "meaning": "high priest, highly-ranked priest, virtuous priest, priest of great sanctity and learning"
  },
  {
    "question": "伸張",
    "answer": "しんちょう",
    "meaning": "expansion, extension, elongation, stretching, uncompression"
  },
  {
    "question": "草色",
    "answer": "くさいろ",
    "meaning": "dark green"
  },
  {
    "question": "窓外",
    "answer": "そうがい",
    "meaning": "outside a window"
  },
  {
    "question": "高天原",
    "answer": "たかまがはら",
    "meaning": "the heavens"
  },
  {
    "question": "喘鳴",
    "answer": "ぜんめい",
    "meaning": "stridor, wheezing, noisy breathing"
  },
  {
    "question": "預金通帳",
    "answer": "よきんつうちょう",
    "meaning": "(deposit) passbook, bankbook"
  },
  {
    "question": "樹林",
    "answer": "じゅりん",
    "meaning": "forest"
  },
  {
    "question": "進度",
    "answer": "しんど",
    "meaning": "progress"
  },
  {
    "question": "湿す",
    "answer": "しめす",
    "meaning": "to wet, to moisten, to dampen"
  },
  {
    "question": "金属光沢",
    "answer": "きんぞくこうたく",
    "meaning": "metallic lustre, metallic luster"
  },
  {
    "question": "手習い",
    "answer": "てならい",
    "meaning": "practice writing with a brush, study, learning"
  },
  {
    "question": "知将",
    "answer": "ちしょう",
    "meaning": "skilled manager, resourceful general"
  },
  {
    "question": "春雨",
    "answer": "しゅんう,はるさめ",
    "meaning": "gentle spring rain, thin noodles made from bean starch (or potato starch)"
  },
  {
    "question": "寸刻",
    "answer": "すんこく",
    "meaning": "moment"
  },
  {
    "question": "収蔵",
    "answer": "しゅうぞう",
    "meaning": "garnering, collection"
  },
  {
    "question": "明々白々",
    "answer": "めいめいはくはく",
    "meaning": "clearly evident, quite obvious, as clear as day, beyond any doubt, strikingly apparent"
  },
  {
    "question": "手技",
    "answer": "しゅぎ,てわざ",
    "meaning": "skill involving the hands, craft, hand throwing technique (judo)"
  },
  {
    "question": "差し替え",
    "answer": "さしかえ",
    "meaning": "replacement"
  },
  {
    "question": "台形",
    "answer": "だいけい",
    "meaning": "trapezium, trapezoid"
  },
  {
    "question": "温野菜",
    "answer": "おんやさい",
    "meaning": "heated vegetables, warm vegetables"
  },
  {
    "question": "世相",
    "answer": "せそう",
    "meaning": "social conditions, phase of life, (sign of) the times, state of society"
  },
  {
    "question": "袋の鼠",
    "answer": "ふくろのねずみ",
    "meaning": "rat in a trap, trapped rat, rat in a bag"
  },
  {
    "question": "無宗教",
    "answer": "むしゅうきょう",
    "meaning": "irreligion, lack of religion, unbelief"
  },
  {
    "question": "経済面",
    "answer": "けいざいめん",
    "meaning": "financial page (of newspaper), financial aspects, economic front"
  },
  {
    "question": "差っ引く",
    "answer": "さっぴく",
    "meaning": "to deduct, to take away"
  },
  {
    "question": "御代",
    "answer": "みよ,おだい",
    "meaning": "(imperial) reign, period, charge (e.g. admission, menu item), cost, price"
  },
  {
    "question": "七宝",
    "answer": "しっぽう,しちほう",
    "meaning": "the seven treasures (gold, silver, pearls, agate, crystal, coral, lapis lazuli), cloisonne ware, shi"
  },
  {
    "question": "野菊",
    "answer": "のぎく",
    "meaning": "wild chrysanthemum, aster"
  },
  {
    "question": "畿内",
    "answer": "きない",
    "meaning": "territories in the vicinity of the capital and under direct imperial rule, (in Japanese history) the"
  },
  {
    "question": "区長",
    "answer": "くちょう",
    "meaning": "head of a ward, mayor of a ward, chief administrator of a ward"
  },
  {
    "question": "棋譜",
    "answer": "きふ",
    "meaning": "record of a game of go, shogi, chess, etc."
  },
  {
    "question": "重版",
    "answer": "じゅうはん",
    "meaning": "second edition, additional printing"
  },
  {
    "question": "湖沼",
    "answer": "こしょう",
    "meaning": "lake, marsh, wetland, inland waters"
  },
  {
    "question": "船名",
    "answer": "せんめい",
    "meaning": "name of a vessel"
  },
  {
    "question": "埴輪",
    "answer": "はにわ",
    "meaning": "haniwa, hollow unglazed terracotta figure from the Kofun period"
  },
  {
    "question": "馬屋",
    "answer": "うまや",
    "meaning": "stable, barn"
  },
  {
    "question": "クラス会",
    "answer": "クラスかい",
    "meaning": "class reunion"
  },
  {
    "question": "黒酢",
    "answer": "くろず",
    "meaning": "black vinegar, usu. produced from unpolished rice, charred kelp or shiitake mushrooms ground and mix"
  },
  {
    "question": "松林",
    "answer": "まつばやし",
    "meaning": "pine forest"
  },
  {
    "question": "別冊",
    "answer": "べっさつ",
    "meaning": "separate volume, extra issue, supplement, additional volume, supplementary volume"
  },
  {
    "question": "米屋",
    "answer": "こめや",
    "meaning": "rice shop, rice dealer"
  },
  {
    "question": "建屋",
    "answer": "たてや",
    "meaning": "structure for housing heavy machinery"
  },
  {
    "question": "明敏",
    "answer": "めいびん",
    "meaning": "intelligence, discernment"
  },
  {
    "question": "製図",
    "answer": "せいず",
    "meaning": "drafting, drawing"
  },
  {
    "question": "注文書",
    "answer": "ちゅうもんしょ",
    "meaning": "written order, order form"
  },
  {
    "question": "原稿料",
    "answer": "げんこうりょう",
    "meaning": "manuscript fee, payment for a piece of writing"
  },
  {
    "question": "固有種",
    "answer": "こゆうしゅ",
    "meaning": "endemic species"
  },
  {
    "question": "大書",
    "answer": "たいしょ",
    "meaning": "writing in large letters"
  },
  {
    "question": "木造り",
    "answer": "きづくり",
    "meaning": "wood construction, woodworking, gardener"
  },
  {
    "question": "同着",
    "answer": "どうちゃく",
    "meaning": "arriving at the same moment"
  },
  {
    "question": "機知",
    "answer": "きち",
    "meaning": "wit, resources, tact"
  },
  {
    "question": "停車場",
    "answer": "ていしゃじょう,ていしゃば",
    "meaning": "railway station, generic term for rail yards, junctions, railway stations, etc."
  },
  {
    "question": "学究",
    "answer": "がっきゅう",
    "meaning": "scholar, student"
  },
  {
    "question": "鉢巻",
    "answer": "はちまき",
    "meaning": "headband"
  },
  {
    "question": "迷妄",
    "answer": "めいもう",
    "meaning": "illusion, fallacy, delusion"
  },
  {
    "question": "知り抜く",
    "answer": "しりぬく",
    "meaning": "to know thoroughly"
  },
  {
    "question": "赤煉瓦",
    "answer": "あかれんが",
    "meaning": "red brick"
  },
  {
    "question": "古流",
    "answer": "こりゅう",
    "meaning": "old manners, old style, old school (of art)"
  },
  {
    "question": "自浄作用",
    "answer": "じじょうさよう",
    "meaning": "autopurificatory activity (in the natural world)"
  },
  {
    "question": "単機",
    "answer": "たんき",
    "meaning": "lone plane"
  },
  {
    "question": "遠投",
    "answer": "えんとう",
    "meaning": "long throw"
  },
  {
    "question": "剛性",
    "answer": "ごうせい",
    "meaning": "hardness, rigidity"
  },
  {
    "question": "回転運動",
    "answer": "かいてんうんどう",
    "meaning": "gyration"
  },
  {
    "question": "縦列",
    "answer": "じゅうれつ",
    "meaning": "column, file, (vertical) line"
  },
  {
    "question": "順列",
    "answer": "じゅんれつ",
    "meaning": "permutation"
  },
  {
    "question": "平和裏",
    "answer": "へいわり",
    "meaning": "peaceable, peaceful"
  },
  {
    "question": "喫緊",
    "answer": "きっきん",
    "meaning": "urgent, pressing, exigent"
  },
  {
    "question": "借る",
    "answer": "かる",
    "meaning": "to borrow, to have a loan, to rent, to hire"
  },
  {
    "question": "地下組織",
    "answer": "ちかそしき",
    "meaning": "underground organization, underground organisation"
  },
  {
    "question": "酒席",
    "answer": "しゅせき",
    "meaning": "drinking party"
  },
  {
    "question": "買い溜め",
    "answer": "かいだめ",
    "meaning": "stocking up on, hoarding"
  },
  {
    "question": "口前",
    "answer": "くちまえ",
    "meaning": "way of speaking, profession"
  },
  {
    "question": "水入り",
    "answer": "みずいり",
    "meaning": "break granted to wrestlers engaged in a prolonged bout"
  },
  {
    "question": "職歴",
    "answer": "しょくれき",
    "meaning": "work experience, work history"
  },
  {
    "question": "一本勝負",
    "answer": "いっぽんしょうぶ",
    "meaning": "one-game match"
  },
  {
    "question": "春めく",
    "answer": "はるめく",
    "meaning": "to become spring-like, to show signs of spring"
  },
  {
    "question": "間の子",
    "answer": "あいのこ",
    "meaning": "person of mixed parentage, crossbreed, Eurasian, mulatto, hybrid"
  },
  {
    "question": "無駄金",
    "answer": "むだがね",
    "meaning": "wasted money"
  },
  {
    "question": "腹具合",
    "answer": "はらぐあい",
    "meaning": "condition of one's stomach"
  },
  {
    "question": "咎め立て",
    "answer": "とがめだて",
    "meaning": "fault-finding, carping"
  },
  {
    "question": "心が通う",
    "answer": "こころがかよう",
    "meaning": "to understand each other well, to relate to, to strike a sympathetic chord"
  },
  {
    "question": "飛び出し",
    "answer": "とびだし",
    "meaning": "something that leaps or thrusts out"
  },
  {
    "question": "天狼",
    "answer": "てんろう",
    "meaning": "Sirius (star in the constellation Canis Major), Alpha Canis Majoris, the Dog Star"
  },
  {
    "question": "八幡宮",
    "answer": "はちまんぐう",
    "meaning": "Shrine of the God of War"
  },
  {
    "question": "守り袋",
    "answer": "まもりぶくろ",
    "meaning": "small pouch containing a paper charm or talisman"
  },
  {
    "question": "取締役会",
    "answer": "とりしまりやくかい",
    "meaning": "board of directors, board of directors' meeting"
  },
  {
    "question": "屈伏",
    "answer": "くっぷく",
    "meaning": "yielding, submission, surrender, giving way, succumbing"
  },
  {
    "question": "春秋",
    "answer": "しゅんじゅう,はるあき",
    "meaning": "spring and autumn, spring and fall, years, age, The Spring and Autumn Annals, The Chronicles of Lu,"
  },
  {
    "question": "磔刑",
    "answer": "たっけい,たくけい,はりつけ",
    "meaning": "crucifixion, execution by tying a victim to a post and stabbing with spears"
  },
  {
    "question": "炭坑",
    "answer": "たんこう",
    "meaning": "coal mine, coal pit"
  },
  {
    "question": "色街",
    "answer": "いろまち",
    "meaning": "red-light district"
  },
  {
    "question": "不治",
    "answer": "ふじ,ふち",
    "meaning": "incurability"
  },
  {
    "question": "鴨居",
    "answer": "かもい",
    "meaning": "lintel (esp. one with grooves for sliding doors)"
  },
  {
    "question": "略取",
    "answer": "りゃくしゅ",
    "meaning": "abduction, kidnapping"
  },
  {
    "question": "摺り足",
    "answer": "すりあし",
    "meaning": "sliding feet, shuffling (one's feet), moving legs forward with feet never leaving the ground (exerci"
  },
  {
    "question": "圧力鍋",
    "answer": "あつりょくなべ",
    "meaning": "pressure cooker"
  },
  {
    "question": "売上金",
    "answer": "うりあげきん",
    "meaning": "proceeds"
  },
  {
    "question": "実効支配",
    "answer": "じっこうしはい",
    "meaning": "effective control (over territory), working control"
  },
  {
    "question": "見返る",
    "answer": "みかえる",
    "meaning": "to look back"
  },
  {
    "question": "形骸",
    "answer": "けいがい",
    "meaning": "ruin, wreck, mere skeleton, framework"
  },
  {
    "question": "運送業",
    "answer": "うんそうぎょう",
    "meaning": "forwarding or transportation industry"
  },
  {
    "question": "賢しら",
    "answer": "さかしら",
    "meaning": "impertinent"
  },
  {
    "question": "東日本",
    "answer": "ひがしにほん,ひがしにっぽん",
    "meaning": "eastern Japan, Japan east of the Itoigawa-Shizuoka Tectonic Line, i.e. east of the Chūbu region"
  },
  {
    "question": "告別式",
    "answer": "こくべつしき",
    "meaning": "funeral service, memorial service, farewell ceremony (e.g. for a retiree)"
  },
  {
    "question": "年輩",
    "answer": "ねんぱい",
    "meaning": "elderly, age, years"
  },
  {
    "question": "国語辞典",
    "answer": "こくごじてん",
    "meaning": "Japanese-language dictionary, dictionary of a national language"
  },
  {
    "question": "総掛かり",
    "answer": "そうがかり",
    "meaning": "in a body, concentrated force, combined efforts"
  },
  {
    "question": "調子付く",
    "answer": "ちょうしづく",
    "meaning": "to warm up to, to become enthusiastic about, to be elated"
  },
  {
    "question": "辛め",
    "answer": "からめ",
    "meaning": "hottish, salty, somewhat hot, kind of salty, on the dry side, strict, harsh"
  },
  {
    "question": "終う",
    "answer": "しまう",
    "meaning": "to finish, to stop, to end, to put an end to, to bring to a close, to close (a business, etc.), to c"
  },
  {
    "question": "呉越同舟",
    "answer": "ごえつどうしゅう",
    "meaning": "bitter enemies in the same boat, rivals finding themselves together by chance"
  },
  {
    "question": "延いては",
    "answer": "ひいては",
    "meaning": "not only ... but also, in addition to, consequently"
  },
  {
    "question": "修辞",
    "answer": "しゅうじ",
    "meaning": "figure of speech, rhetorical flourish"
  },
  {
    "question": "写メる",
    "answer": "しゃメる",
    "meaning": "to take a photo with a mobile phone, to email a photo taken with a mobile phone"
  },
  {
    "question": "膝を崩す",
    "answer": "ひざをくずす",
    "meaning": "to sit at ease"
  },
  {
    "question": "整形手術",
    "answer": "せいけいしゅじゅつ",
    "meaning": "orthopedic surgery, plastic surgery"
  },
  {
    "question": "気が多い",
    "answer": "きがおおい",
    "meaning": "fickle, inconstant, capricious, having many romantic interests"
  },
  {
    "question": "軽業師",
    "answer": "かるわざし",
    "meaning": "acrobat"
  },
  {
    "question": "皮下脂肪",
    "answer": "ひかしぼう",
    "meaning": "subcutaneous fat"
  },
  {
    "question": "荒行",
    "answer": "あらぎょう",
    "meaning": "asceticism"
  },
  {
    "question": "健康食品",
    "answer": "けんこうしょくひん",
    "meaning": "health foods"
  },
  {
    "question": "初舞台",
    "answer": "はつぶたい",
    "meaning": "debut, initial stage appearance"
  },
  {
    "question": "動物実験",
    "answer": "どうぶつじっけん",
    "meaning": "experiments using animals, in-vivo testing, animal testing"
  },
  {
    "question": "口煩い",
    "answer": "くちうるさい",
    "meaning": "nagging, faultfinding, carping, captious"
  },
  {
    "question": "立体感",
    "answer": "りったいかん",
    "meaning": "feeling of solidity, three-dimensionality, drawing highlights"
  },
  {
    "question": "祝い酒",
    "answer": "いわいざけ",
    "meaning": "celebratory drink, celebratory spirits, holiday cheer"
  },
  {
    "question": "泡立ち",
    "answer": "あわだち",
    "meaning": "foaming, frothing, lathering"
  },
  {
    "question": "北半球",
    "answer": "きたはんきゅう",
    "meaning": "northern hemisphere"
  },
  {
    "question": "未開発",
    "answer": "みかいはつ",
    "meaning": "undeveloped (countries), backward, unentered"
  },
  {
    "question": "ヘビー級",
    "answer": "ヘビーきゅう",
    "meaning": "heavyweight (esp. boxing), heavyweight division"
  },
  {
    "question": "神機",
    "answer": "しんき",
    "meaning": "miraculous deed, unmeasurable resourcefulness"
  },
  {
    "question": "上帝",
    "answer": "じょうてい,しょうてい",
    "meaning": "Shangdi (creator deity in Chinese folk religion), God (in Christianity)"
  },
  {
    "question": "投資銀行",
    "answer": "とうしぎんこう",
    "meaning": "investment bank"
  },
  {
    "question": "特待",
    "answer": "とくたい",
    "meaning": "special treatment, priority"
  },
  {
    "question": "速射砲",
    "answer": "そくしゃほう",
    "meaning": "rapid-fire gun or cannon, talking rapidly, barrage of words or questions"
  },
  {
    "question": "朝鮮半島",
    "answer": "ちょうせんはんとう",
    "meaning": "Korean peninsula"
  },
  {
    "question": "白亜紀",
    "answer": "はくあき",
    "meaning": "Cretaceous Period"
  },
  {
    "question": "反戦",
    "answer": "はんせん",
    "meaning": "anti-war"
  },
  {
    "question": "女郎蜘蛛",
    "answer": "じょろうぐも",
    "meaning": "Nephila clavata (an Oriental species of golden orb-weaving spider), Argiope amoena (an Oriental spec"
  },
  {
    "question": "生き餌",
    "answer": "いきえ",
    "meaning": "live bait"
  },
  {
    "question": "遷移",
    "answer": "せんい",
    "meaning": "transition (esp. in scientific contexts)"
  },
  {
    "question": "胎盤",
    "answer": "たいばん",
    "meaning": "placenta, afterbirth"
  },
  {
    "question": "観測所",
    "answer": "かんそくじょ",
    "meaning": "observatory, observation post"
  },
  {
    "question": "大女",
    "answer": "おおおんな,だいじょ",
    "meaning": "huge woman, giantess, grown-up woman, adult woman"
  },
  {
    "question": "悪阻",
    "answer": "つわり,おそ",
    "meaning": "morning sickness, hyperemesis gravidarum"
  },
  {
    "question": "古民家",
    "answer": "こみんか",
    "meaning": "old Japanese-style house"
  },
  {
    "question": "奥付",
    "answer": "おくづけ",
    "meaning": "colophon (at the end of a book), imprint, publication information"
  },
  {
    "question": "十人並み",
    "answer": "じゅうにんなみ",
    "meaning": "being average (capacity, looks) (as good as anyone), mediocrity"
  },
  {
    "question": "燗",
    "answer": "かん",
    "meaning": "warming up sake, warmed sake"
  },
  {
    "question": "減圧",
    "answer": "げんあつ",
    "meaning": "decompression"
  },
  {
    "question": "金庫番",
    "answer": "きんこばん",
    "meaning": "person who holds the purse strings, person who minds the cash, safe keeper, treasurer"
  },
  {
    "question": "回覧",
    "answer": "かいらん",
    "meaning": "circulation (esp. documents), sending round"
  },
  {
    "question": "終に",
    "answer": "ついに",
    "meaning": "finally, at last, in the end, after all, never (happened)"
  },
  {
    "question": "現住所",
    "answer": "げんじゅうしょ",
    "meaning": "(present) address"
  },
  {
    "question": "鄙びる",
    "answer": "ひなびる",
    "meaning": "to become rustic, to be countrified"
  },
  {
    "question": "山陰",
    "answer": "やまかげ,さんいん",
    "meaning": "place in the shade of a mountain, shelter of the mountains, mountain recess"
  },
  {
    "question": "伐る",
    "answer": "きる",
    "meaning": "to cut down (e.g. trees)"
  },
  {
    "question": "金縁",
    "answer": "きんぶち",
    "meaning": "gilded edges or rims"
  },
  {
    "question": "修飾",
    "answer": "しゅうしょく",
    "meaning": "ornamentation, embellishment, decoration, adornment, polish up (writing), modification, qualificatio"
  },
  {
    "question": "妙手",
    "answer": "みょうしゅ",
    "meaning": "spectacular move (chess, shogi, etc.), brilliant move, expert, virtuoso, master"
  },
  {
    "question": "吸い込み",
    "answer": "すいこみ",
    "meaning": "drawing, suction, intake"
  },
  {
    "question": "独り相撲",
    "answer": "ひとりずもう",
    "meaning": "fighting (tilting at) windmills, working oneself up even though there really isn't anything to fight"
  },
  {
    "question": "健啖家",
    "answer": "けんたんか",
    "meaning": "glutton, gormandizer, gormandiser"
  },
  {
    "question": "教え諭す",
    "answer": "おしえさとす",
    "meaning": "to give guidance, to explain clearly, to admonish, to preach"
  },
  {
    "question": "再評価",
    "answer": "さいひょうか",
    "meaning": "reassessment, reappraisal, reevaluation, revaluation"
  },
  {
    "question": "既成",
    "answer": "きせい",
    "meaning": "established, existing, accomplished, accepted, completed"
  },
  {
    "question": "闘将",
    "answer": "とうしょう",
    "meaning": "brave leader"
  },
  {
    "question": "砲艦",
    "answer": "ほうかん",
    "meaning": "gunboat"
  },
  {
    "question": "末世",
    "answer": "まっせ,まっせい",
    "meaning": "degenerate age, corrupt word, age of the decline of Buddhism, latter days of the law"
  },
  {
    "question": "地霊",
    "answer": "ちれい",
    "meaning": "spirit residing in the ground"
  },
  {
    "question": "鏑矢",
    "answer": "かぶらや",
    "meaning": "arrow with a whistle attached, whistling arrow used to signal the start of battle"
  },
  {
    "question": "排煙",
    "answer": "はいえん",
    "meaning": "smoke (dispersal)"
  },
  {
    "question": "生き人形",
    "answer": "いきにんぎょう",
    "meaning": "lifelike doll"
  },
  {
    "question": "棒倒し",
    "answer": "ぼうたおし",
    "meaning": "game in which the object is to topple the opposing team's pole"
  },
  {
    "question": "曼荼羅",
    "answer": "まんだら,マンダラ",
    "meaning": "mandala"
  },
  {
    "question": "婦長",
    "answer": "ふちょう",
    "meaning": "head nurse"
  },
  {
    "question": "採掘権",
    "answer": "さいくつけん",
    "meaning": "mining rights"
  },
  {
    "question": "墓碑銘",
    "answer": "ぼひめい",
    "meaning": "epitaph, inscription on a tombstone"
  },
  {
    "question": "祈禱",
    "answer": "きとう",
    "meaning": "prayer, grace (at meals), exorcism"
  },
  {
    "question": "竜田揚げ",
    "answer": "たつたあげ",
    "meaning": "dish of fish or meat flavoured with soy sauce, mirin, etc., coated with starch and then deep-fried"
  },
  {
    "question": "追討",
    "answer": "ついとう",
    "meaning": "tracking down and killing, punitive expedition"
  },
  {
    "question": "銃砲",
    "answer": "じゅうほう",
    "meaning": "guns, firearms"
  },
  {
    "question": "長押し",
    "answer": "ながおし",
    "meaning": "long press (of a button)"
  },
  {
    "question": "遊弋",
    "answer": "ゆうよく",
    "meaning": "cruising, patrolling"
  },
  {
    "question": "賦活",
    "answer": "ふかつ",
    "meaning": "activation, invigoration, stimulation"
  },
  {
    "question": "玉砂利",
    "answer": "たまじゃり",
    "meaning": "gravel"
  },
  {
    "question": "藩主",
    "answer": "はんしゅ",
    "meaning": "feudal lord, daimyo"
  },
  {
    "question": "銅板",
    "answer": "どうばん",
    "meaning": "sheet copper"
  },
  {
    "question": "頻りに",
    "answer": "しきりに",
    "meaning": "frequently, repeatedly, often, incessantly, constantly, strongly, eagerly"
  },
  {
    "question": "細君",
    "answer": "さいくん",
    "meaning": "one's wife, wife (of somebody below the speaker in rank)"
  },
  {
    "question": "被造物",
    "answer": "ひぞうぶつ",
    "meaning": "something created (e.g. by the gods), creature"
  },
  {
    "question": "升",
    "answer": "ます,しょう",
    "meaning": "measuring container, measure, box (seating at a theatre, etc.), square on a grid, cell of a grid, sh"
  },
  {
    "question": "干し魚",
    "answer": "ほしうお,ほしいお",
    "meaning": "dried fish, stockfish"
  },
  {
    "question": "理知",
    "answer": "りち",
    "meaning": "intellect, intelligence"
  },
  {
    "question": "質的",
    "answer": "しつてき",
    "meaning": "qualitative"
  },
  {
    "question": "直向き",
    "answer": "ひたむき",
    "meaning": "earnest, single-minded"
  },
  {
    "question": "経営権",
    "answer": "けいえいけん",
    "meaning": "right of management"
  },
  {
    "question": "遊技",
    "answer": "ゆうぎ",
    "meaning": "games, pastimes"
  },
  {
    "question": "刈り入れ",
    "answer": "かりいれ",
    "meaning": "harvest"
  },
  {
    "question": "水出し",
    "answer": "みずだし",
    "meaning": "infusing in cold water (coffee, tea, etc.)"
  },
  {
    "question": "尾翼",
    "answer": "びよく",
    "meaning": "tail (of an aircraft), empennage, tail assembly"
  },
  {
    "question": "刷く",
    "answer": "はく",
    "meaning": "to daub, to brush, to touch up"
  },
  {
    "question": "銅色",
    "answer": "どうしょく",
    "meaning": "bronze or copper (color, colour)"
  },
  {
    "question": "風説",
    "answer": "ふうせつ",
    "meaning": "rumor, rumour, gossip, hearsay"
  },
  {
    "question": "卑俗",
    "answer": "ひぞく",
    "meaning": "vulgar, coarse, low"
  },
  {
    "question": "音声認識",
    "answer": "おんせいにんしき",
    "meaning": "voice recognition, speech recognition"
  },
  {
    "question": "解熱",
    "answer": "げねつ",
    "meaning": "lowering a fever, alleviation of fever"
  },
  {
    "question": "昏々",
    "answer": "こんこん",
    "meaning": "fast asleep, dead to the world"
  },
  {
    "question": "膝関節",
    "answer": "しつかんせつ",
    "meaning": "knee joint"
  },
  {
    "question": "遊覧",
    "answer": "ゆうらん",
    "meaning": "sightseeing"
  },
  {
    "question": "素泊まり",
    "answer": "すどまり",
    "meaning": "staying overnight without meals"
  },
  {
    "question": "足代",
    "answer": "あしだい",
    "meaning": "transportation expenses, travel expenses, fare (train, taxi, etc.)"
  },
  {
    "question": "一挙",
    "answer": "いっきょ",
    "meaning": "one effort, one action"
  },
  {
    "question": "独立独歩",
    "answer": "どくりつどっぽ",
    "meaning": "self-reliance, self-help"
  },
  {
    "question": "店屋",
    "answer": "みせや",
    "meaning": "store, shop"
  },
  {
    "question": "一家団欒",
    "answer": "いっかだんらん",
    "meaning": "happy family get-together"
  },
  {
    "question": "延べ",
    "answer": "のべ",
    "meaning": "futures, credit (buying), stretching, total (preceding counter, unit, etc.), aggregate, gross"
  },
  {
    "question": "常態化",
    "answer": "じょうたいか",
    "meaning": "normalization (of a social problem, of a situation, etc.)"
  },
  {
    "question": "功労",
    "answer": "こうろう",
    "meaning": "meritorious deed, services"
  },
  {
    "question": "野狐",
    "answer": "のぎつね,やこ",
    "meaning": "wild fox, mythical fox spirit capable of possessing people"
  },
  {
    "question": "若宮",
    "answer": "わかみや",
    "meaning": "young imperial prince, child of the imperial family, shrine dedicated to a child of the god of the m"
  },
  {
    "question": "七曜",
    "answer": "しちよう",
    "meaning": "the seven luminaries (sun, moon, Mercury, Venus, Mars, Jupiter and Saturn), the seven days of the we"
  },
  {
    "question": "大主教",
    "answer": "だいしゅきょう",
    "meaning": "archbishop (Orthodox, Anglican, etc.)"
  },
  {
    "question": "釣具",
    "answer": "つりぐ",
    "meaning": "fishing gear, fishing tackle"
  },
  {
    "question": "総監督",
    "answer": "そうかんとく",
    "meaning": "general manager, general superintendent, general director (of a film, etc.)"
  },
  {
    "question": "大祭",
    "answer": "たいさい",
    "meaning": "grand festival"
  },
  {
    "question": "黒豚",
    "answer": "くろぶた",
    "meaning": "Berkshire pig"
  },
  {
    "question": "法務大臣",
    "answer": "ほうむだいじん",
    "meaning": "Minister of Justice"
  },
  {
    "question": "砲座",
    "answer": "ほうざ",
    "meaning": "gun platform"
  },
  {
    "question": "夜回り",
    "answer": "よまわり",
    "meaning": "night watch, night watchman"
  },
  {
    "question": "文箱",
    "answer": "ふばこ,ふみばこ",
    "meaning": "box for letters and papers, box used to carry or deliver letters"
  },
  {
    "question": "窄む",
    "answer": "すぼむ,つぼむ",
    "meaning": "to get narrower, to contract, to close (of flowers), to shut"
  },
  {
    "question": "嗾ける",
    "answer": "けしかける",
    "meaning": "to instigate, to incite, to spur on, to set (e.g. a dog after someone)"
  },
  {
    "question": "論功行賞",
    "answer": "ろんこうこうしょう",
    "meaning": "conferral of honors (honours), according to merits"
  },
  {
    "question": "夜行列車",
    "answer": "やこうれっしゃ",
    "meaning": "night train"
  },
  {
    "question": "晦ます",
    "answer": "くらます",
    "meaning": "to conceal (oneself), to hide, to abscond, to deceive, to dissemble, to fool"
  },
  {
    "question": "下絵",
    "answer": "したえ",
    "meaning": "rough sketch, cartoon, design"
  },
  {
    "question": "毛氈",
    "answer": "もうせん",
    "meaning": "carpet, rug (esp. felt)"
  },
  {
    "question": "両極",
    "answer": "りょうきょく",
    "meaning": "both extremities, North and South Poles, positive and negative poles"
  },
  {
    "question": "最深",
    "answer": "さいしん",
    "meaning": "deepest"
  },
  {
    "question": "稲刈り",
    "answer": "いねかり",
    "meaning": "rice reaping, rice harvesting"
  },
  {
    "question": "山師",
    "answer": "やまし",
    "meaning": "speculator, adventurer, imposter, prospector"
  },
  {
    "question": "叙する",
    "answer": "じょする",
    "meaning": "to relate, to narrate, to describe, to confer (a rank)"
  },
  {
    "question": "女人禁制",
    "answer": "にょにんきんせい,にょにんきんぜい",
    "meaning": "prohibition on women entering (usu. for religious reasons), no female admission"
  },
  {
    "question": "共依存",
    "answer": "きょういぞん",
    "meaning": "codependence"
  },
  {
    "question": "化学式",
    "answer": "かがくしき",
    "meaning": "chemical formula"
  },
  {
    "question": "大喝",
    "answer": "だいかつ",
    "meaning": "shouting in a thunderous voice"
  },
  {
    "question": "光り物",
    "answer": "ひかりもの",
    "meaning": "luminous body (e.g. of a shooting star), bright metal, sliced fish with the silver skin left on (iwa"
  },
  {
    "question": "商品券",
    "answer": "しょうひんけん",
    "meaning": "gift certificate"
  },
  {
    "question": "井戸端",
    "answer": "いどばた",
    "meaning": "side of well"
  },
  {
    "question": "炊飯",
    "answer": "すいはん",
    "meaning": "rice cooking, boiling rice"
  },
  {
    "question": "請負",
    "answer": "うけおい",
    "meaning": "contract (for work), contracting, undertaking"
  },
  {
    "question": "定点",
    "answer": "ていてん",
    "meaning": "fixed point"
  },
  {
    "question": "脂質",
    "answer": "ししつ",
    "meaning": "lipid, fats, adipose"
  },
  {
    "question": "残念会",
    "answer": "ざんねんかい",
    "meaning": "consolation party (held after failure or defeat)"
  },
  {
    "question": "内鍵",
    "answer": "うちかぎ",
    "meaning": "internal lock"
  },
  {
    "question": "学名",
    "answer": "がくめい",
    "meaning": "scientific name (of a species), binomial name, Latin name, academic reputation"
  },
  {
    "question": "途方",
    "answer": "とほう",
    "meaning": "way, destination, reason"
  },
  {
    "question": "両刀",
    "answer": "りょうとう",
    "meaning": "two swords, being skilled in two fields, (an) expert in two fields, liking both alcohol and sweets,"
  },
  {
    "question": "癇",
    "answer": "かん",
    "meaning": "temper, nerves"
  },
  {
    "question": "悪口雑言",
    "answer": "あっこうぞうごん",
    "meaning": "all kinds of malicious gossip, heaping verbal abuse (on), cursing and swearing (words)"
  },
  {
    "question": "平屋建て",
    "answer": "ひらやだて",
    "meaning": "single-storied house, single-storied building"
  },
  {
    "question": "大受け",
    "answer": "おおうけ",
    "meaning": "big hit, great success"
  },
  {
    "question": "巻き込み",
    "answer": "まきこみ",
    "meaning": "makikomi (judo throw), vehicle accident involving a turn (e.g. when a car turns and hits a bicycle t"
  },
  {
    "question": "洗い立て",
    "answer": "あらいたて",
    "meaning": "freshly washed"
  },
  {
    "question": "一乗",
    "answer": "いちじょう",
    "meaning": "ekayana (doctrine that only one teaching, usu. the Lotus Sutra, can lead to enlightenment)"
  },
  {
    "question": "雪月花",
    "answer": "せつげつか,せつげっか",
    "meaning": "snow, moon, and flowers, beauty of the four seasons (from a poem by Bai Juyi)"
  },
  {
    "question": "小猫",
    "answer": "こねこ",
    "meaning": "kitten, small cat"
  },
  {
    "question": "地母神",
    "answer": "じぼしん,ちぼしん",
    "meaning": "mother goddess, earth goddess"
  },
  {
    "question": "華厳",
    "answer": "けごん",
    "meaning": "avatamsa (flower adornment, as a metaphor for becoming a buddha), Avatamska sutra, Kegon (sect of Bu"
  },
  {
    "question": "月下美人",
    "answer": "げっかびじん",
    "meaning": "Dutchman's pipe cactus (Epiphyllum oxypetalum), night-blooming cereus, queen of the night"
  },
  {
    "question": "連峰",
    "answer": "れんぽう",
    "meaning": "mountain range"
  },
  {
    "question": "鋼製",
    "answer": "こうせい",
    "meaning": "made of steel"
  },
  {
    "question": "胸甲",
    "answer": "きょうこう",
    "meaning": "sternum, breastplate, plastron"
  },
  {
    "question": "高崎",
    "answer": "たかさき",
    "meaning": "Takasaki (city in Gunma)"
  },
  {
    "question": "雪煙",
    "answer": "ゆきけむり",
    "meaning": "spray of snow (smoke-like)"
  },
  {
    "question": "退艦",
    "answer": "たいかん",
    "meaning": "leaving a warship, abandoning ship, retirement from a naval post, retirement from captaincy (of a na"
  },
  {
    "question": "能力主義",
    "answer": "のうりょくしゅぎ",
    "meaning": "meritocracy, merit system"
  },
  {
    "question": "捏ね回す",
    "answer": "こねまわす",
    "meaning": "to knead, to mix, to complicate, to turn into a mess"
  },
  {
    "question": "狂熱",
    "answer": "きょうねつ",
    "meaning": "extreme passion, wild enthusiasm"
  },
  {
    "question": "活版印刷",
    "answer": "かっぱんいんさつ",
    "meaning": "letterpress printing, moveable type printing"
  },
  {
    "question": "川柳",
    "answer": "せんりゅう,かわやなぎ,かわやぎ",
    "meaning": "senryū, comic haiku, humorous seventeen-mora poem, riverside willow (esp. rosegold pussy willow, Sal"
  },
  {
    "question": "蒲焼き",
    "answer": "かばやき",
    "meaning": "loach or eel dipped and broiled in soy-based sauce"
  },
  {
    "question": "復刻",
    "answer": "ふっこく",
    "meaning": "republication, reissue, reprinting, reproduction"
  },
  {
    "question": "上面",
    "answer": "うわつら,じょうめん",
    "meaning": "surface, appearances, exterior, top (side)"
  },
  {
    "question": "皇位",
    "answer": "こうい",
    "meaning": "imperial throne"
  },
  {
    "question": "上奏",
    "answer": "じょうそう",
    "meaning": "report to the throne"
  },
  {
    "question": "統治権",
    "answer": "とうちけん",
    "meaning": "sovereignty"
  },
  {
    "question": "遺伝情報",
    "answer": "いでんじょうほう",
    "meaning": "genetic information"
  },
  {
    "question": "肥る",
    "answer": "ふとる",
    "meaning": "to put on weight, to gain weight, to grow fat, to get stout"
  },
  {
    "question": "犇めく",
    "answer": "ひしめく",
    "meaning": "to clamour, to crowd, to jostle"
  },
  {
    "question": "顰めっ面",
    "answer": "しかめっつら",
    "meaning": "frown, scowl, grimace"
  },
  {
    "question": "例題",
    "answer": "れいだい",
    "meaning": "example, exercise (for the reader)"
  },
  {
    "question": "陣中",
    "answer": "じんちゅう",
    "meaning": "in camp, at the front"
  },
  {
    "question": "来春",
    "answer": "らいしゅん,らいはる",
    "meaning": "next spring"
  },
  {
    "question": "拇印",
    "answer": "ぼいん",
    "meaning": "thumb print"
  },
  {
    "question": "言明",
    "answer": "げんめい",
    "meaning": "declaration, statement, assertion"
  },
  {
    "question": "煎茶",
    "answer": "せんちゃ",
    "meaning": "green tea, green leaf tea, non-powdered tea (as opposed to matcha), medium-grade green tea"
  },
  {
    "question": "収賄",
    "answer": "しゅうわい",
    "meaning": "accepting bribes, corruption, graft"
  },
  {
    "question": "耳当て",
    "answer": "みみあて",
    "meaning": "earmuffs"
  },
  {
    "question": "胸毛",
    "answer": "むなげ",
    "meaning": "chest hair, breast down"
  },
  {
    "question": "一巡り",
    "answer": "ひとめぐり",
    "meaning": "a round, a turn, going around, making a round, first anniversary of a person's death"
  },
  {
    "question": "透け透け",
    "answer": "すけすけ",
    "meaning": "see-through, sheer"
  },
  {
    "question": "踏み絵",
    "answer": "ふみえ",
    "meaning": "fumi-e, fumie, tablet bearing Christian images, on which Edo-period authorities forced suspected Chr"
  },
  {
    "question": "幾日か",
    "answer": "いくにちか",
    "meaning": "some days, several days"
  },
  {
    "question": "店屋物",
    "answer": "てんやもの",
    "meaning": "take-out (food)"
  },
  {
    "question": "宿命的",
    "answer": "しゅくめいてき",
    "meaning": "fateful, predestined"
  },
  {
    "question": "蛍光塗料",
    "answer": "けいこうとりょう",
    "meaning": "fluorescent paint"
  },
  {
    "question": "堆い",
    "answer": "うずたかい",
    "meaning": "piled up high, in a heap"
  },
  {
    "question": "小腸",
    "answer": "しょうちょう",
    "meaning": "small intestine"
  },
  {
    "question": "貨幣価値",
    "answer": "かへいかち",
    "meaning": "currency value"
  },
  {
    "question": "腕白",
    "answer": "わんぱく",
    "meaning": "naughty, mischievous, unruly"
  },
  {
    "question": "湯豆腐",
    "answer": "ゆどうふ",
    "meaning": "boiled tofu"
  },
  {
    "question": "国際電話",
    "answer": "こくさいでんわ",
    "meaning": "international phone call"
  },
  {
    "question": "年期",
    "answer": "ねんき",
    "meaning": "period of an apprentice's contract (usu. ten years), apprenticeship, indentureship, indenture, one-y"
  },
  {
    "question": "常套",
    "answer": "じょうとう",
    "meaning": "conventionality, triteness"
  },
  {
    "question": "公布",
    "answer": "こうふ",
    "meaning": "official proclamation, announcement, promulgation (e.g. of regulations)"
  },
  {
    "question": "世俗的",
    "answer": "せぞくてき",
    "meaning": "worldly, secular"
  },
  {
    "question": "罷り通る",
    "answer": "まかりとおる",
    "meaning": "to go unpunished, to be tolerated, to be allowed, to be overlooked"
  },
  {
    "question": "思い余る",
    "answer": "おもいあまる",
    "meaning": "to not know how to act or what to do, to be at a loss"
  },
  {
    "question": "何のその",
    "answer": "なんのその",
    "meaning": "nothing special, no big deal, doesn't matter"
  },
  {
    "question": "拾い出す",
    "answer": "ひろいだす",
    "meaning": "to single out, to select"
  },
  {
    "question": "力尽く",
    "answer": "ちからずく,ちからづく",
    "meaning": "(brute) force, using all one's might"
  },
  {
    "question": "無病息災",
    "answer": "むびょうそくさい",
    "meaning": "sound health"
  },
  {
    "question": "野趣",
    "answer": "やしゅ",
    "meaning": "rural beauty, rusticity, rustic beauty"
  },
  {
    "question": "仮面夫婦",
    "answer": "かめんふうふ",
    "meaning": "couple who only go through the motions of being husband and wife"
  },
  {
    "question": "新都",
    "answer": "しんと",
    "meaning": "new capital"
  },
  {
    "question": "朴",
    "answer": "えのき,ほお,ほおがしわ",
    "meaning": "Japanese hackberry (Celtis sinensis var. japonica), Chinese nettle tree, Japanese bigleaf magnolia ("
  },
  {
    "question": "大津",
    "answer": "おおつ",
    "meaning": "Ōtsu (city in Shiga)"
  },
  {
    "question": "廃鉱",
    "answer": "はいこう",
    "meaning": "abandoned mine, disused mine"
  },
  {
    "question": "秋雨",
    "answer": "あきさめ,しゅうう",
    "meaning": "autumn rain, fall rain"
  },
  {
    "question": "厚生省",
    "answer": "こうせいしょう",
    "meaning": "Ministry of Health and Welfare (now Ministry of Health, Labour and Welfare)"
  },
  {
    "question": "本星",
    "answer": "ほんぼし",
    "meaning": "real culprit"
  },
  {
    "question": "貴種",
    "answer": "きしゅ",
    "meaning": "noble birth"
  },
  {
    "question": "船縁",
    "answer": "ふなべり",
    "meaning": "side of a boat, gunwale"
  },
  {
    "question": "無間",
    "answer": "むけん,むげん",
    "meaning": "ceaselessness, incessancy, the Avici hell"
  },
  {
    "question": "具える",
    "answer": "そなえる",
    "meaning": "to furnish with, to equip with, to provide, to install, to prepare for, to make preparations for, to"
  },
  {
    "question": "火縄",
    "answer": "ひなわ",
    "meaning": "fuse, cord"
  },
  {
    "question": "競",
    "answer": "くら,せり",
    "meaning": "contest, match, competing, competition, auction"
  },
  {
    "question": "大便",
    "answer": "だいべん",
    "meaning": "feces, excrement, shit"
  },
  {
    "question": "打ち水",
    "answer": "うちみず",
    "meaning": "sprinkling water (to keep down dust, cool pavements, etc.)"
  },
  {
    "question": "衆議院",
    "answer": "しゅうぎいん",
    "meaning": "House of Representatives (lower house of the National Diet of Japan)"
  },
  {
    "question": "行者",
    "answer": "ぎょうじゃ,あんじゃ",
    "meaning": "ascetic, pilgrim, devotee, temple helper"
  },
  {
    "question": "船主",
    "answer": "せんしゅ,ふなぬし",
    "meaning": "shipowner"
  },
  {
    "question": "鉄兜",
    "answer": "てつかぶと",
    "meaning": "steel helmet"
  },
  {
    "question": "生け簀",
    "answer": "いけす",
    "meaning": "fish pen, holding pond, fish tank, live well, live-box"
  },
  {
    "question": "昼餉",
    "answer": "ひるげ",
    "meaning": "lunch, midday meal, food served at a tea party (tea ceremony)"
  },
  {
    "question": "素麺",
    "answer": "そうめん",
    "meaning": "fine white noodles"
  },
  {
    "question": "討ち入り",
    "answer": "うちいり",
    "meaning": "raid"
  },
  {
    "question": "戸籍謄本",
    "answer": "こせきとうほん",
    "meaning": "official copy of the family register"
  },
  {
    "question": "探険",
    "answer": "たんけん",
    "meaning": "exploration, expedition"
  },
  {
    "question": "性向",
    "answer": "せいこう",
    "meaning": "inclination, tendency, nature, character"
  },
  {
    "question": "太字",
    "answer": "ふとじ",
    "meaning": "boldface, bold-type, thick characters"
  },
  {
    "question": "敷布団",
    "answer": "しきぶとん",
    "meaning": "futon (laid on the floor), (Japanese) mattress, underquilt, sleeping mat"
  },
  {
    "question": "娘御",
    "answer": "むすめご",
    "meaning": "girl, young (unmarried) woman"
  },
  {
    "question": "ちょび髭",
    "answer": "ちょびひげ",
    "meaning": "small mustache, short mustache"
  },
  {
    "question": "泣き伏す",
    "answer": "なきふす",
    "meaning": "to break down crying"
  },
  {
    "question": "家屋敷",
    "answer": "いえやしき",
    "meaning": "estate, homestead, house and land (it stands on), messuage"
  },
  {
    "question": "行き合う",
    "answer": "いきあう,ゆきあう",
    "meaning": "to meet somebody by chance, to happen upon"
  },
  {
    "question": "生活雑貨",
    "answer": "せいかつざっか",
    "meaning": "daily necessities, goods for everyday life"
  },
  {
    "question": "天稟",
    "answer": "てんぴん",
    "meaning": "natural talents"
  },
  {
    "question": "熟",
    "answer": "つくづく,つくつく",
    "meaning": "deeply, keenly, severely, completely, utterly, intently, carefully, closely, attentively"
  },
  {
    "question": "解剖学",
    "answer": "かいぼうがく",
    "meaning": "anatomy"
  },
  {
    "question": "良妻",
    "answer": "りょうさい",
    "meaning": "good wife"
  },
  {
    "question": "脳挫傷",
    "answer": "のうざしょう",
    "meaning": "cerebral contusion"
  },
  {
    "question": "予算案",
    "answer": "よさんあん",
    "meaning": "draft budget"
  },
  {
    "question": "造成",
    "answer": "ぞうせい",
    "meaning": "development (of land), preparation (e.g. of ground for housing), reclamation, creation"
  },
  {
    "question": "座高",
    "answer": "ざこう",
    "meaning": "one's sitting height"
  },
  {
    "question": "実姉",
    "answer": "じっし",
    "meaning": "biological older sister, real elder sister"
  },
  {
    "question": "奉ずる",
    "answer": "ほうずる",
    "meaning": "to present, to dedicate, to obey, to follow, to believe in, to serve, to proudly bear"
  },
  {
    "question": "一徹",
    "answer": "いってつ",
    "meaning": "obstinate, stubborn, inflexible"
  },
  {
    "question": "生食",
    "answer": "せいしょく,なましょく",
    "meaning": "eating something raw"
  },
  {
    "question": "爪を研ぐ",
    "answer": "つめをとぐ",
    "meaning": "to sharpen one's claws"
  },
  {
    "question": "続け様",
    "answer": "つづけざま,つづけさま",
    "meaning": "successive, consecutive, back-to-back, one after another"
  },
  {
    "question": "恒久",
    "answer": "こうきゅう",
    "meaning": "permanence, perpetuity"
  },
  {
    "question": "馬鹿面",
    "answer": "ばかづら",
    "meaning": "foolish face, stupid look on one's face"
  },
  {
    "question": "年俸",
    "answer": "ねんぽう",
    "meaning": "annual salary"
  },
  {
    "question": "人が好い",
    "answer": "ひとがよい",
    "meaning": "generous, soft-hearted, having a good personality"
  },
  {
    "question": "名が通る",
    "answer": "ながとおる",
    "meaning": "to be well-known, to be famous"
  },
  {
    "question": "降雨",
    "answer": "こうう",
    "meaning": "rainfall, rain"
  },
  {
    "question": "引かす",
    "answer": "ひかす",
    "meaning": "to redeem debts (e.g. of a geisha)"
  },
  {
    "question": "大命",
    "answer": "たいめい",
    "meaning": "imperial command, royal command"
  },
  {
    "question": "背理",
    "answer": "はいり",
    "meaning": "absurdity, irrationality"
  },
  {
    "question": "晋",
    "answer": "しん",
    "meaning": "Jin dynasty (China, 265-420), Chin dynasty"
  },
  {
    "question": "未納",
    "answer": "みのう",
    "meaning": "payment default, overdue on a payment"
  },
  {
    "question": "女王蟻",
    "answer": "じょおうあり",
    "meaning": "queen ant"
  },
  {
    "question": "小父さん",
    "answer": "おじさん",
    "meaning": "uncle, old man, mister, manybar goatfish (Parupeneus multifasciatus)"
  },
  {
    "question": "紺青",
    "answer": "こんじょう",
    "meaning": "Prussian blue, deep blue, dark blue, ultramarine"
  },
  {
    "question": "総和",
    "answer": "そうわ",
    "meaning": "sum total, summation"
  },
  {
    "question": "東照宮",
    "answer": "とうしょうぐう",
    "meaning": "Toshogu Shrine"
  },
  {
    "question": "敵船",
    "answer": "てきせん",
    "meaning": "enemy ship, enemy vessel"
  },
  {
    "question": "牡鹿",
    "answer": "おじか,おしか,おか",
    "meaning": "buck (male deer)"
  },
  {
    "question": "驢馬",
    "answer": "ろば",
    "meaning": "donkey, ass"
  },
  {
    "question": "太巻き",
    "answer": "ふとまき",
    "meaning": "futomaki, thick roll of makizushi, rolling something thickly, something rolled thickly (a cigar, etc"
  },
  {
    "question": "水生",
    "answer": "すいせい",
    "meaning": "aquatic (life), living in the water"
  },
  {
    "question": "霹靂",
    "answer": "へきれき",
    "meaning": "thunder, thunderclap"
  },
  {
    "question": "卑語",
    "answer": "ひご",
    "meaning": "vulgar expression, vulgarism"
  },
  {
    "question": "農道",
    "answer": "のうどう",
    "meaning": "farm road"
  },
  {
    "question": "妖女",
    "answer": "ようじょ",
    "meaning": "enchantress, vamp"
  },
  {
    "question": "編曲",
    "answer": "へんきょく",
    "meaning": "arrangement, to arrange, to orchestrate"
  },
  {
    "question": "蠟",
    "answer": "",
    "meaning": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "髯",
    "answer": "ひげ",
    "meaning": "moustache, beard, whiskers, whiskers (on a cat, etc.), feelers (on an insect, etc.), (chin) tuft, ex"
  },
  {
    "question": "古墳",
    "answer": "こふん",
    "meaning": "ancient burial mound, barrow, tumulus"
  },
  {
    "question": "仮想敵国",
    "answer": "かそうてきこく",
    "meaning": "hypothetical or imaginary enemy"
  },
  {
    "question": "山際",
    "answer": "やまぎわ",
    "meaning": "mountain ridge, near a mountain"
  },
  {
    "question": "彫金",
    "answer": "ちょうきん",
    "meaning": "chasing, metal carving, metal engraving"
  },
  {
    "question": "保釈金",
    "answer": "ほしゃくきん",
    "meaning": "bail (money)"
  },
  {
    "question": "別れ別れ",
    "answer": "わかれわかれ",
    "meaning": "separate"
  },
  {
    "question": "契約社員",
    "answer": "けいやくしゃいん",
    "meaning": "contract employee"
  },
  {
    "question": "小火",
    "answer": "ぼや,しょうか",
    "meaning": "small fire"
  },
  {
    "question": "大願",
    "answer": "たいがん",
    "meaning": "ambition, the Buddha's great vow (to save all people)"
  },
  {
    "question": "考え深い",
    "answer": "かんがえぶかい",
    "meaning": "thoughtful, deep-thinking"
  },
  {
    "question": "度合",
    "answer": "どあい",
    "meaning": "degree, extent"
  },
  {
    "question": "絹織物",
    "answer": "きぬおりもの",
    "meaning": "silk goods"
  },
  {
    "question": "催涙ガス",
    "answer": "さいるいガス",
    "meaning": "tear gas"
  },
  {
    "question": "短足",
    "answer": "たんそく",
    "meaning": "short-legged"
  },
  {
    "question": "浮き世",
    "answer": "うきよ",
    "meaning": "fleeting life, this transient world, floating world, sad world, world of grief and worry, the world"
  },
  {
    "question": "頸骨",
    "answer": "けいこつ",
    "meaning": "neckbones"
  },
  {
    "question": "阿る",
    "answer": "おもねる",
    "meaning": "to flatter, to play up to, to fawn on, to pander to, to cater to"
  },
  {
    "question": "就業時間",
    "answer": "しゅうぎょうじかん",
    "meaning": "work hours"
  },
  {
    "question": "他店",
    "answer": "たてん",
    "meaning": "another shop, store, or firm"
  },
  {
    "question": "惰眠",
    "answer": "だみん",
    "meaning": "idle slumber, indolence, inactivity"
  },
  {
    "question": "肥溜め",
    "answer": "こえだめ",
    "meaning": "tank for holding excreta (often used for fertilizer) (fertiliser), night soil vat or reservoir, cess"
  },
  {
    "question": "軽重",
    "answer": "けいじゅう,けいちょう",
    "meaning": "relative weight, lightness and heaviness, relative importance, gravity"
  },
  {
    "question": "急先鋒",
    "answer": "きゅうせんぽう",
    "meaning": "van (of a movement), vanguard, forefront"
  },
  {
    "question": "黄金比",
    "answer": "おうごんひ",
    "meaning": "golden ratio (approx. 1.6180339887)"
  },
  {
    "question": "牛歩",
    "answer": "ぎゅうほ",
    "meaning": "snail's pace, slow progress"
  },
  {
    "question": "返送",
    "answer": "へんそう",
    "meaning": "sending back, return to sender"
  },
  {
    "question": "蛋白質",
    "answer": "たんぱくしつ",
    "meaning": "protein"
  },
  {
    "question": "身構え",
    "answer": "みがまえ",
    "meaning": "posture, attitude"
  },
  {
    "question": "暴投",
    "answer": "ぼうとう",
    "meaning": "wild pitch"
  },
  {
    "question": "朝来",
    "answer": "ちょうらい",
    "meaning": "ever since morning"
  },
  {
    "question": "君付け",
    "answer": "くんづけ",
    "meaning": "use of the familiar address 'kun', treating someone with familiarity"
  },
  {
    "question": "座興",
    "answer": "ざきょう",
    "meaning": "entertainment (at a party), amusement, fun, trick"
  },
  {
    "question": "五里霧中",
    "answer": "ごりむちゅう",
    "meaning": "totally at a loss, lose one's bearings, in a maze, in a fog, all at sea, up in the air, mystified, b"
  },
  {
    "question": "取り置く",
    "answer": "とりおく",
    "meaning": "to set aside, to keep in reserve, to hold on to, to preserve, to save, to put in, to lay in, to stas"
  },
  {
    "question": "原始時代",
    "answer": "げんしじだい",
    "meaning": "primitive times"
  },
  {
    "question": "は行",
    "answer": "はぎょう",
    "meaning": "the 'ha' column of the Japanese syllabary table (ha, hi, fu, he, ho)"
  },
  {
    "question": "仕返す",
    "answer": "しかえす",
    "meaning": "to take revenge, to retaliate, to do over again, to redo, to start over"
  },
  {
    "question": "平易",
    "answer": "へいい",
    "meaning": "easy, simple, plain"
  },
  {
    "question": "接続詞",
    "answer": "せつぞくし",
    "meaning": "conjunction"
  },
  {
    "question": "台所事情",
    "answer": "だいどころじじょう",
    "meaning": "financial situation"
  },
  {
    "question": "那須",
    "answer": "",
    "meaning": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "学童",
    "answer": "がくどう",
    "meaning": "school child, pupil"
  },
  {
    "question": "賤",
    "answer": "しず,せん",
    "meaning": "lowly person, lowliness, I"
  },
  {
    "question": "蒔絵",
    "answer": "まきえ",
    "meaning": "gold or silver lacquer, lacquer decoration sprinkled with metal powder"
  },
  {
    "question": "愛猫",
    "answer": "あいびょう",
    "meaning": "pet cat, beloved cat, ailurophilia, fondness for cats"
  },
  {
    "question": "憲章",
    "answer": "けんしょう",
    "meaning": "charter"
  },
  {
    "question": "行李",
    "answer": "こうり",
    "meaning": "portmanteau, wicker trunk, luggage, baggage"
  },
  {
    "question": "地虫",
    "answer": "じむし",
    "meaning": "scarabaeid beetle grub, any insect (or worm, etc.) that lives in soil"
  },
  {
    "question": "速記",
    "answer": "そっき",
    "meaning": "shorthand, stenography"
  },
  {
    "question": "官服",
    "answer": "かんぷく",
    "meaning": "official uniform, official dress"
  },
  {
    "question": "匂い袋",
    "answer": "においぶくろ",
    "meaning": "scent bag, sachet, scent gland"
  },
  {
    "question": "刺し身",
    "answer": "さしみ",
    "meaning": "sashimi (raw sliced fish, shellfish or crustaceans)"
  },
  {
    "question": "呻吟",
    "answer": "しんぎん",
    "meaning": "moaning, groaning"
  },
  {
    "question": "鉄器",
    "answer": "てっき",
    "meaning": "ironware"
  },
  {
    "question": "仕来り",
    "answer": "しきたり",
    "meaning": "custom, convention, tradition, mores, conventional practice"
  },
  {
    "question": "拘置",
    "answer": "こうち",
    "meaning": "detention, confinement, arrest"
  },
  {
    "question": "怖気立つ",
    "answer": "おぞけだつ,おじけだつ,こわけたつ",
    "meaning": "to be horrified, to be filled with trepidation, to shake with fright, to yield to terror"
  },
  {
    "question": "儘",
    "answer": "まま,まんま",
    "meaning": "as it is, as one likes, because, as, condition, state"
  },
  {
    "question": "賞与",
    "answer": "しょうよ",
    "meaning": "bonus, reward, prize"
  },
  {
    "question": "兆す",
    "answer": "きざす",
    "meaning": "to show signs, to have symptoms, to give indications (of), to bud, to germinate, to sprout"
  },
  {
    "question": "埋め立て",
    "answer": "うめたて",
    "meaning": "land reclamation"
  },
  {
    "question": "留置",
    "answer": "りゅうち",
    "meaning": "detention (usu. during investigation), imprisonment, poundage, custody"
  },
  {
    "question": "付け合せ",
    "answer": "つけあわせ",
    "meaning": "garnish (e.g. vegetables with a meat dish), trimmings, fixings, relish"
  },
  {
    "question": "勲功",
    "answer": "くんこう",
    "meaning": "merits, distinguished services"
  },
  {
    "question": "金魚の糞",
    "answer": "きんぎょのふん",
    "meaning": "person who just tags along, hanger-on, person who follows someone around like a shadow, clingy perso"
  },
  {
    "question": "囃子",
    "answer": "はやし",
    "meaning": "accompaniment for traditional performances (noh, kabuki, etc.), orchestra, band"
  },
  {
    "question": "対案",
    "answer": "たいあん",
    "meaning": "counter-proposal, counter-suggestion"
  },
  {
    "question": "宅配ピザ",
    "answer": "たくはいピザ",
    "meaning": "delivery pizza, home-delivered pizza"
  },
  {
    "question": "煮魚",
    "answer": "にざかな",
    "meaning": "fish simmered with soy sauce (and sugar)"
  },
  {
    "question": "差し出口",
    "answer": "さしでぐち",
    "meaning": "uncalled-for or impertinent remark"
  },
  {
    "question": "今更感",
    "answer": "いまさらかん",
    "meaning": "feeling that something has come too late"
  },
  {
    "question": "二重底",
    "answer": "にじゅうぞこ",
    "meaning": "bottom, double sole"
  },
  {
    "question": "二次的",
    "answer": "にじてき",
    "meaning": "secondary"
  },
  {
    "question": "外形",
    "answer": "がいけい",
    "meaning": "externals, external form"
  },
  {
    "question": "購読",
    "answer": "こうどく",
    "meaning": "buying and reading (book, magazine, etc.), subscribing (incl. free subscriptions), taking (e.g. news"
  },
  {
    "question": "次週",
    "answer": "じしゅう",
    "meaning": "next week"
  },
  {
    "question": "元旦那",
    "answer": "もとだんな",
    "meaning": "ex-husband, former husband"
  },
  {
    "question": "米俵",
    "answer": "こめだわら",
    "meaning": "bag of rice"
  },
  {
    "question": "民謡",
    "answer": "みんよう",
    "meaning": "folk song, popular song"
  },
  {
    "question": "提起",
    "answer": "ていき",
    "meaning": "raising (a question), bringing up (a problem), instituting (a lawsuit), filing (a claim), submitting"
  },
  {
    "question": "職人芸",
    "answer": "しょくにんげい",
    "meaning": "craftsmanship, artisanship"
  },
  {
    "question": "救急病院",
    "answer": "きゅうきゅうびょういん",
    "meaning": "emergency hospital"
  },
  {
    "question": "食が細い",
    "answer": "しょくがほそい",
    "meaning": "eating only a little, having a small appetite"
  },
  {
    "question": "鶫",
    "answer": "つぐみ",
    "meaning": "thrush (esp. the dusky thrush, Turdus naumanni)"
  },
  {
    "question": "剝離",
    "answer": "はくり",
    "meaning": "detachment, coming off, peeling off, exfoliation, (flow) separation"
  },
  {
    "question": "飛行士",
    "answer": "ひこうし",
    "meaning": "pilot"
  },
  {
    "question": "巨樹",
    "answer": "きょじゅ",
    "meaning": "giant tree"
  },
  {
    "question": "高峰",
    "answer": "こうほう",
    "meaning": "high mountain, lofty peak"
  },
  {
    "question": "剝き出す",
    "answer": "むきだす",
    "meaning": "to show, to bare (the teeth)"
  },
  {
    "question": "粘菌",
    "answer": "ねんきん",
    "meaning": "myxomycete, slime mold"
  },
  {
    "question": "高跳び",
    "answer": "たかとび",
    "meaning": "high jump"
  },
  {
    "question": "旧体制",
    "answer": "きゅうたいせい",
    "meaning": "old regime"
  },
  {
    "question": "断頭",
    "answer": "だんとう",
    "meaning": "beheading, decapitation"
  },
  {
    "question": "吃る",
    "answer": "どもる",
    "meaning": "to stammer, to stutter"
  },
  {
    "question": "貨車",
    "answer": "かしゃ",
    "meaning": "freight car, van"
  },
  {
    "question": "九官鳥",
    "answer": "きゅうかんちょう",
    "meaning": "common hill mynah (Gracula religiosa), hill myna, myna bird"
  },
  {
    "question": "芸大",
    "answer": "げいだい",
    "meaning": "university of arts, arts college"
  },
  {
    "question": "検疫",
    "answer": "けんえき",
    "meaning": "quarantine, medical inspection"
  },
  {
    "question": "柳に風",
    "answer": "やなぎにかぜ",
    "meaning": "handling things without making waves, taking in one's stride"
  },
  {
    "question": "管理棟",
    "answer": "かんりとう",
    "meaning": "administrative building"
  },
  {
    "question": "叢",
    "answer": "くさむら,むら,そう",
    "meaning": "the grass, grassy place (esp. with long dense grass), gathering, plexus, rete"
  },
  {
    "question": "開票",
    "answer": "かいひょう",
    "meaning": "counting ballots, tally (of votes)"
  },
  {
    "question": "溜め池",
    "answer": "ためいけ",
    "meaning": "reservoir, pond"
  },
  {
    "question": "多元",
    "answer": "たげん",
    "meaning": "pluralism, diversity"
  },
  {
    "question": "破水",
    "answer": "はすい",
    "meaning": "water breaking (during pregnancy)"
  },
  {
    "question": "雷管",
    "answer": "らいかん",
    "meaning": "detonator, percussion cap"
  },
  {
    "question": "拝礼",
    "answer": "はいれい",
    "meaning": "worship"
  },
  {
    "question": "冷製",
    "answer": "れいせい",
    "meaning": "cold dish (e.g. at a restaurant)"
  },
  {
    "question": "遊軍",
    "answer": "ゆうぐん",
    "meaning": "reserve corps, flying squadron"
  },
  {
    "question": "惨禍",
    "answer": "さんか",
    "meaning": "calamity"
  },
  {
    "question": "贈答",
    "answer": "ぞうとう",
    "meaning": "exchange of presents"
  },
  {
    "question": "発布",
    "answer": "はっぷ",
    "meaning": "proclamation, promulgation"
  },
  {
    "question": "軍事同盟",
    "answer": "ぐんじどうめい",
    "meaning": "military alliance"
  },
  {
    "question": "処方箋",
    "answer": "しょほうせん",
    "meaning": "prescription"
  },
  {
    "question": "急進的",
    "answer": "きゅうしんてき",
    "meaning": "radical"
  },
  {
    "question": "避妊薬",
    "answer": "ひにんやく",
    "meaning": "a contraceptive"
  },
  {
    "question": "私心",
    "answer": "ししん",
    "meaning": "selfishness, selfish motive"
  },
  {
    "question": "二枚貝",
    "answer": "にまいがい",
    "meaning": "bivalve"
  },
  {
    "question": "非暴力",
    "answer": "ひぼうりょく",
    "meaning": "nonviolence, non-violence"
  },
  {
    "question": "活況",
    "answer": "かっきょう",
    "meaning": "activity, briskness, prosperity"
  },
  {
    "question": "慈善団体",
    "answer": "じぜんだんたい",
    "meaning": "charitable organization, charitable institution, charity"
  },
  {
    "question": "瘡蓋",
    "answer": "かさぶた",
    "meaning": "scab, crust"
  },
  {
    "question": "節電",
    "answer": "せつでん",
    "meaning": "conservation of electricity, brownout"
  },
  {
    "question": "借り手",
    "answer": "かりて",
    "meaning": "borrower, debtor, tenant"
  },
  {
    "question": "選挙権",
    "answer": "せんきょけん",
    "meaning": "suffrage, the right to vote"
  },
  {
    "question": "爛漫",
    "answer": "らんまん",
    "meaning": "glorious, luxuriant, splendid, in full bloom, in full glory"
  },
  {
    "question": "所在無い",
    "answer": "しょざいない",
    "meaning": "bored, having nothing to do, idle"
  },
  {
    "question": "音感",
    "answer": "おんかん",
    "meaning": "sense of sound, sense of pitch"
  },
  {
    "question": "鼾",
    "answer": "いびき",
    "meaning": "snoring, snore"
  },
  {
    "question": "金言",
    "answer": "きんげん",
    "meaning": "wise saying, maxim"
  },
  {
    "question": "心付け",
    "answer": "こころづけ",
    "meaning": "gratuity, tip"
  },
  {
    "question": "情け深い",
    "answer": "なさけぶかい",
    "meaning": "tender-hearted, compassionate, charitable, good-hearted"
  },
  {
    "question": "死出の旅",
    "answer": "しでのたび",
    "meaning": "one's last journey, the journey to the other world, death"
  },
  {
    "question": "必修科目",
    "answer": "ひっしゅうかもく",
    "meaning": "compulsory subject, required subject"
  },
  {
    "question": "笑かす",
    "answer": "わらかす",
    "meaning": "to make laugh, to set to laughing"
  },
  {
    "question": "実録",
    "answer": "じつろく",
    "meaning": "authentic account"
  },
  {
    "question": "浮き浮き",
    "answer": "うきうき",
    "meaning": "cheerfully, buoyantly, happily, in high spirits"
  },
  {
    "question": "安普請",
    "answer": "やすぶしん",
    "meaning": "cheap structure (e.g. of houses)"
  },
  {
    "question": "不特定",
    "answer": "ふとくてい",
    "meaning": "unspecified, random, indefinite"
  },
  {
    "question": "馬耳東風",
    "answer": "ばじとうふう",
    "meaning": "utter indifference, talking to the wall, praying to deaf ears"
  },
  {
    "question": "無記名",
    "answer": "むきめい",
    "meaning": "unsigned, unregistered"
  },
  {
    "question": "健忘症",
    "answer": "けんぼうしょう",
    "meaning": "amnesia, loss of memory"
  },
  {
    "question": "角行",
    "answer": "かくぎょう,かっこう,かくこう",
    "meaning": "bishop"
  },
  {
    "question": "門閥",
    "answer": "もんばつ",
    "meaning": "lineage, pedigree, good family"
  },
  {
    "question": "羽子板",
    "answer": "はごいた",
    "meaning": "battledore (early form of badminton racket)"
  },
  {
    "question": "野太刀",
    "answer": "のだち",
    "meaning": "extra-long sword"
  },
  {
    "question": "将帥",
    "answer": "しょうすい",
    "meaning": "commander"
  },
  {
    "question": "嘱託",
    "answer": "しょくたく",
    "meaning": "commission, entrusting with (work), part-time employee, temporary work"
  },
  {
    "question": "当世",
    "answer": "とうせい",
    "meaning": "present-day, nowadays"
  },
  {
    "question": "立法",
    "answer": "りっぽう",
    "meaning": "legislation, lawmaking"
  },
  {
    "question": "細菌兵器",
    "answer": "さいきんへいき",
    "meaning": "bacteriological weapon"
  },
  {
    "question": "自邸",
    "answer": "じてい",
    "meaning": "one's residence"
  },
  {
    "question": "前哨",
    "answer": "ぜんしょう",
    "meaning": "outpost"
  },
  {
    "question": "煤煙",
    "answer": "ばいえん",
    "meaning": "dirty smoke, soot and smoke"
  },
  {
    "question": "大葉",
    "answer": "おおば",
    "meaning": "beefsteak plant, perilla"
  },
  {
    "question": "体細胞",
    "answer": "たいさいぼう",
    "meaning": "somatic cell"
  },
  {
    "question": "濁点",
    "answer": "だくてん",
    "meaning": "dakuten, diacritic kana mark that turns an unvoiced consonant into a voiced consonant"
  },
  {
    "question": "走力",
    "answer": "そうりょく",
    "meaning": "running ability"
  },
  {
    "question": "前生",
    "answer": "ぜんしょう",
    "meaning": "previous existence"
  },
  {
    "question": "尾っぽ",
    "answer": "おっぽ",
    "meaning": "tail"
  },
  {
    "question": "動体",
    "answer": "どうたい",
    "meaning": "moving body"
  },
  {
    "question": "功名",
    "answer": "こうみょう,こうめい",
    "meaning": "great achievement, glorious deed, (gaining) fame, (earning) distinction"
  },
  {
    "question": "突っ張り",
    "answer": "つっぱり",
    "meaning": "prop, strut, support, brace, bar, becoming taut, tightness, stiffness, cramp, thrust, slapping attac"
  },
  {
    "question": "矢文",
    "answer": "やぶみ",
    "meaning": "letter affixed to an arrow"
  },
  {
    "question": "戦災",
    "answer": "せんさい",
    "meaning": "war damage"
  },
  {
    "question": "続投",
    "answer": "ぞくとう",
    "meaning": "continuing to pitch"
  },
  {
    "question": "自然発火",
    "answer": "しぜんはっか",
    "meaning": "spontaneous combustion"
  },
  {
    "question": "押印",
    "answer": "おういん",
    "meaning": "affixing one's seal"
  },
  {
    "question": "説話",
    "answer": "せつわ",
    "meaning": "tale, narrative"
  },
  {
    "question": "使途",
    "answer": "しと",
    "meaning": "purpose for which money is spent, the way money is spent, how goods are used"
  },
  {
    "question": "栄枯盛衰",
    "answer": "えいこせいすい",
    "meaning": "ups and downs of life, vicissitudes of fortune"
  },
  {
    "question": "重職",
    "answer": "じゅうしょく",
    "meaning": "responsible position"
  },
  {
    "question": "政治活動",
    "answer": "せいじかつどう",
    "meaning": "political activity"
  },
  {
    "question": "用量",
    "answer": "ようりょう",
    "meaning": "dose"
  },
  {
    "question": "私立大学",
    "answer": "しりつだいがく",
    "meaning": "private university"
  },
  {
    "question": "突き出し",
    "answer": "つきだし",
    "meaning": "protrusion, projection, hors d'oeuvre, appetizer, snack (served with a drink), frontal thrust out (w"
  },
  {
    "question": "水拭き",
    "answer": "みずぶき",
    "meaning": "wiping with a damp cloth"
  },
  {
    "question": "佃",
    "answer": "つくだ,てん",
    "meaning": "cultivated rice field"
  },
  {
    "question": "金工",
    "answer": "きんこう",
    "meaning": "metalwork, metalsmith, goldsmith"
  },
  {
    "question": "請負人",
    "answer": "うけおいにん",
    "meaning": "contractor"
  },
  {
    "question": "惣",
    "answer": "そう",
    "meaning": "rural local self-government (Muromachi period)"
  },
  {
    "question": "高瀬",
    "answer": "たかせ",
    "meaning": "shallow river, shallows, flatboat, river boat"
  },
  {
    "question": "技倆",
    "answer": "ぎりょう",
    "meaning": "ability, competency, talent, skill, capacity"
  },
  {
    "question": "胸壁",
    "answer": "きょうへき",
    "meaning": "breastwork, parapet, fortress, chest wall"
  },
  {
    "question": "八段",
    "answer": "はったん",
    "meaning": "twilled fabric"
  },
  {
    "question": "絵コンテ",
    "answer": "えコンテ",
    "meaning": "storyboard (film, television), design for a series of movie scenes"
  },
  {
    "question": "蜀",
    "answer": "しょく",
    "meaning": "Sichuan (province in China), Shu, Shu Han, kingdom in China during the Three Kingdoms era (221-263),"
  },
  {
    "question": "気息",
    "answer": "きそく",
    "meaning": "breathing, breath"
  },
  {
    "question": "引金",
    "answer": "ひきがね",
    "meaning": "trigger (of a gun, etc.), trigger (for something), immediate cause"
  },
  {
    "question": "火気",
    "answer": "かき,かっき,ほけ",
    "meaning": "fire, trace of fire, heat of fire, force of a fire"
  },
  {
    "question": "艦砲",
    "answer": "かんぽう",
    "meaning": "ship's guns"
  },
  {
    "question": "下火",
    "answer": "したび",
    "meaning": "burning low, waning, declining"
  },
  {
    "question": "親和",
    "answer": "しんわ",
    "meaning": "friendship, fellowship"
  },
  {
    "question": "天意",
    "answer": "てんい",
    "meaning": "divine will, providence"
  },
  {
    "question": "頗る",
    "answer": "すこぶる,そこぶる",
    "meaning": "extremely, very much"
  },
  {
    "question": "瓶詰",
    "answer": "びんづめ",
    "meaning": "bottling, bottled"
  },
  {
    "question": "岩風呂",
    "answer": "いわぶろ",
    "meaning": "bathtub or onsen made of (or surrounded by) rocks"
  },
  {
    "question": "満ち潮",
    "answer": "みちしお",
    "meaning": "high tide, high water, full tide"
  },
  {
    "question": "練磨",
    "answer": "れんま",
    "meaning": "training, practice, practising, cultivation"
  },
  {
    "question": "運休",
    "answer": "うんきゅう",
    "meaning": "suspension (of a transportation service), cancellation, stoppage"
  },
  {
    "question": "賜わる",
    "answer": "たまわる",
    "meaning": "to be given, to be granted, to be honored with, to be honoured with, to give, to bestow, to confer,"
  },
  {
    "question": "盗塁",
    "answer": "とうるい",
    "meaning": "base stealing, steal, stolen base"
  },
  {
    "question": "豪雪",
    "answer": "ごうせつ",
    "meaning": "tremendous snowfall, heavy snow"
  },
  {
    "question": "高気圧",
    "answer": "こうきあつ",
    "meaning": "high (atmospheric) pressure, high-pressure system, anticyclone"
  },
  {
    "question": "枯草",
    "answer": "かれくさ,こそう",
    "meaning": "dry grass, dead grass, hay, withered grass"
  },
  {
    "question": "昆布茶",
    "answer": "こぶちゃ,こんぶちゃ",
    "meaning": "kelp tea"
  },
  {
    "question": "臓器移植",
    "answer": "ぞうきいしょく",
    "meaning": "organ transplant"
  },
  {
    "question": "諮る",
    "answer": "はかる",
    "meaning": "to consult with, to discuss, to confer, to deliberate"
  },
  {
    "question": "探訪",
    "answer": "たんぼう",
    "meaning": "searching, hunting for news story, journalist"
  },
  {
    "question": "手付金",
    "answer": "てつけきん",
    "meaning": "deposit, earnest payment, earnest money"
  },
  {
    "question": "洋梨",
    "answer": "ようなし",
    "meaning": "European pear (Pyrus communis)"
  },
  {
    "question": "中心線",
    "answer": "ちゅうしんせん",
    "meaning": "centre line, center line, central line"
  },
  {
    "question": "祝砲",
    "answer": "しゅくほう",
    "meaning": "salute of guns"
  },
  {
    "question": "欠場",
    "answer": "けつじょう",
    "meaning": "absence, not taking part"
  },
  {
    "question": "求刑",
    "answer": "きゅうけい",
    "meaning": "recommended sentence, prosecution's demand for punishment"
  },
  {
    "question": "通年",
    "answer": "つうねん",
    "meaning": "all year, year round"
  },
  {
    "question": "都会人",
    "answer": "とかいじん",
    "meaning": "city dweller"
  },
  {
    "question": "割り出し",
    "answer": "わりだし",
    "meaning": "upper-arm force out"
  },
  {
    "question": "闘病",
    "answer": "とうびょう",
    "meaning": "fighting against an illness"
  },
  {
    "question": "年中行事",
    "answer": "ねんちゅうぎょうじ,ねんじゅうぎょうじ,ねんぢゅうぎょうじ",
    "meaning": "annual function, annual event"
  },
  {
    "question": "明々",
    "answer": "あかあか",
    "meaning": "brightly lit, brightly lighted, lit up, lighted up"
  },
  {
    "question": "日照",
    "answer": "にっしょう",
    "meaning": "sunlight"
  },
  {
    "question": "胸苦しい",
    "answer": "むなぐるしい",
    "meaning": "(feeling of) tightness in the chest"
  },
  {
    "question": "質疑",
    "answer": "しつぎ",
    "meaning": "question, interpellation"
  },
  {
    "question": "足蹴り",
    "answer": "あしげり",
    "meaning": "kicking (an opponent)"
  },
  {
    "question": "祝勝",
    "answer": "しゅくしょう",
    "meaning": "victory celebration"
  },
  {
    "question": "半休",
    "answer": "はんきゅう",
    "meaning": "half-holiday, taking half of the day off"
  },
  {
    "question": "紙媒体",
    "answer": "かみばいたい",
    "meaning": "paper medium, print medium (as opposed to other media)"
  },
  {
    "question": "型落ち",
    "answer": "かたおち",
    "meaning": "old model (of an appliance, etc.), becoming outdated, drop (type of metal casting defect)"
  },
  {
    "question": "外国産",
    "answer": "がいこくさん",
    "meaning": "foreign (product, esp. agricultural), of foreign manufacture"
  },
  {
    "question": "住環境",
    "answer": "じゅうかんきょう",
    "meaning": "living environment, habitat"
  },
  {
    "question": "別条",
    "answer": "べつじょう",
    "meaning": "something unusual, something wrong, mishap, accident, serious condition (e.g. after an injury), diff"
  },
  {
    "question": "繰り上げ",
    "answer": "くりあげ",
    "meaning": "upward move, advance"
  },
  {
    "question": "死者の書",
    "answer": "ししゃのしょ",
    "meaning": "Book of the Dead (ancient Egypt)"
  },
  {
    "question": "星祭",
    "answer": "ほしまつり",
    "meaning": "Star Festival (held in July or August), Tanabata"
  },
  {
    "question": "沃野",
    "answer": "よくや",
    "meaning": "fertile fields or plain"
  },
  {
    "question": "景勝",
    "answer": "けいしょう",
    "meaning": "picturesque scenery, place of scenic beauty"
  },
  {
    "question": "蝦蟇",
    "answer": "がまがえる,がま,かま",
    "meaning": "toad (esp. the Japanese toad, Bufo japonicus)"
  },
  {
    "question": "暗黒大陸",
    "answer": "あんこくたいりく",
    "meaning": "Dark Continent (i.e. Africa)"
  },
  {
    "question": "跫音",
    "answer": "あしおと,きょうおん",
    "meaning": "sound of footsteps, sense or sign that something is approaching"
  },
  {
    "question": "漉く",
    "answer": "すく",
    "meaning": "to comb (out), to card, to untangle (hair), to make something (e.g. paper) from wet, pulpy material"
  },
  {
    "question": "貴兄",
    "answer": "きけい",
    "meaning": "you"
  },
  {
    "question": "物見台",
    "answer": "ものみだい",
    "meaning": "observation platform, lookout platform"
  },
  {
    "question": "永田町",
    "answer": "ながたちょう",
    "meaning": "Nagata-chō (Japan's political center; equiv. of Downing Street)"
  },
  {
    "question": "山伏",
    "answer": "やまぶし",
    "meaning": "itinerant Buddhist monk, practitioner of Shugendō"
  },
  {
    "question": "兇悪",
    "answer": "きょうあく",
    "meaning": "atrocious, fiendish, brutal, villainous"
  },
  {
    "question": "卒業制作",
    "answer": "そつぎょうせいさく",
    "meaning": "art project which is done in place of a graduation thesis at a college of arts"
  },
  {
    "question": "株主総会",
    "answer": "かぶぬしそうかい",
    "meaning": "general meeting of stockholders"
  },
  {
    "question": "夕暮",
    "answer": "ゆうぐれ",
    "meaning": "evening, dusk, twilight"
  },
  {
    "question": "米袋",
    "answer": "こめぶくろ",
    "meaning": "rice bag"
  },
  {
    "question": "備前",
    "answer": "びぜん",
    "meaning": "Bizen (former province located in the southeast of present-day Okayama Prefecture)"
  },
  {
    "question": "空地",
    "answer": "あきち,くうち",
    "meaning": "vacant land, unoccupied ground, empty lot"
  },
  {
    "question": "婦人会",
    "answer": "ふじんかい",
    "meaning": "women's group, women's association"
  },
  {
    "question": "焦慮",
    "answer": "しょうりょ",
    "meaning": "impatience, worry"
  },
  {
    "question": "載",
    "answer": "さい",
    "meaning": "10^44, hundred tredecillion"
  },
  {
    "question": "搾乳",
    "answer": "さくにゅう",
    "meaning": "milking (a cow)"
  },
  {
    "question": "川下り",
    "answer": "かわくだり",
    "meaning": "going downstream (in a boat)"
  },
  {
    "question": "噴流",
    "answer": "ふんりゅう",
    "meaning": "jet (of water)"
  },
  {
    "question": "出入",
    "answer": "しゅつにゅう",
    "meaning": "in and out, income and expenses, free associations, run of the house"
  },
  {
    "question": "接種",
    "answer": "せっしゅ",
    "meaning": "inoculation, vaccination"
  },
  {
    "question": "紀行",
    "answer": "きこう",
    "meaning": "traveller's journal, traveler's journal, travelogue"
  },
  {
    "question": "厳戒",
    "answer": "げんかい",
    "meaning": "strict guard"
  },
  {
    "question": "恙無い",
    "answer": "つつがない",
    "meaning": "well, in good health, safe, free from accident"
  },
  {
    "question": "受精卵",
    "answer": "じゅせいらん",
    "meaning": "fertilized egg, fertilised egg"
  },
  {
    "question": "冬枯れ",
    "answer": "ふゆがれ",
    "meaning": "wintry desolation, poor business conditions"
  },
  {
    "question": "塗す",
    "answer": "まぶす",
    "meaning": "to cover (smear, sprinkle) (with)"
  },
  {
    "question": "有意",
    "answer": "ゆうい",
    "meaning": "significant, meaningful, intentional, volitional"
  },
  {
    "question": "再生産",
    "answer": "さいせいさん",
    "meaning": "reproduction"
  },
  {
    "question": "栄養学",
    "answer": "えいようがく",
    "meaning": "dietetics, nutritional science"
  },
  {
    "question": "体脂肪",
    "answer": "たいしぼう",
    "meaning": "body fat, somatic fat"
  },
  {
    "question": "誹る",
    "answer": "そしる",
    "meaning": "to slander, to libel, to criticize, to criticise"
  },
  {
    "question": "不履行",
    "answer": "ふりこう",
    "meaning": "default, nonperformance"
  },
  {
    "question": "野外活動",
    "answer": "やがいかつどう",
    "meaning": "outdoor activity"
  },
  {
    "question": "対義語",
    "answer": "たいぎご",
    "meaning": "antonym"
  },
  {
    "question": "月謝",
    "answer": "げっしゃ",
    "meaning": "monthly tuition fee"
  },
  {
    "question": "社会制度",
    "answer": "しゃかいせいど",
    "meaning": "social system"
  },
  {
    "question": "俎上",
    "answer": "そじょう",
    "meaning": "on the chopping board"
  },
  {
    "question": "祭日",
    "answer": "さいじつ",
    "meaning": "national holiday, festival day"
  },
  {
    "question": "忍び入る",
    "answer": "しのびいる",
    "meaning": "to steal or sneak or slip into"
  },
  {
    "question": "名を取る",
    "answer": "なをとる",
    "meaning": "to become famous"
  },
  {
    "question": "両成敗",
    "answer": "りょうせいばい",
    "meaning": "two guilty parties tried and punished together"
  },
  {
    "question": "服毒",
    "answer": "ふくどく",
    "meaning": "taking poison"
  },
  {
    "question": "焼け焦げ",
    "answer": "やけこげ",
    "meaning": "burn hole, scorch"
  },
  {
    "question": "避難指示",
    "answer": "ひなんしじ",
    "meaning": "evacuation order, evacuation notice"
  },
  {
    "question": "矍鑠",
    "answer": "かくしゃく",
    "meaning": "vigorous (in old age), hale and hearty"
  },
  {
    "question": "貯え",
    "answer": "たくわえ",
    "meaning": "store, reserve, stock, savings"
  },
  {
    "question": "逢坂",
    "answer": "",
    "meaning": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "夕月",
    "answer": "ゆうづき",
    "meaning": "the evening moon"
  },
  {
    "question": "城市",
    "answer": "じょうし",
    "meaning": "castle town, fortified town"
  },
  {
    "question": "兵部",
    "answer": "へいぶ",
    "meaning": "Ministry of War (Tang-dynasty China)"
  },
  {
    "question": "甲種",
    "answer": "こうしゅ",
    "meaning": "A-grade, first-class"
  },
  {
    "question": "魔笛",
    "answer": "まてき",
    "meaning": "magic flute, The Magic Flute (by Mozart)"
  },
  {
    "question": "垓",
    "answer": "がい",
    "meaning": "10^20, 100,000,000,000,000,000,000, hundred quintillion"
  },
  {
    "question": "樹氷",
    "answer": "じゅひょう",
    "meaning": "frost covered trees"
  },
  {
    "question": "聖誕祭",
    "answer": "せいたんさい",
    "meaning": "Christmas, holy birthday"
  },
  {
    "question": "鳥小屋",
    "answer": "とりごや",
    "meaning": "aviary, henhouse, chicken house"
  },
  {
    "question": "大道",
    "answer": "だいどう,たいどう",
    "meaning": "main street, avenue"
  },
  {
    "question": "廓",
    "answer": "くるわ,かく",
    "meaning": "district, quarter, enclosure, area enclosed by earthwork, red-light district, wide and empty"
  },
  {
    "question": "霊山",
    "answer": "れいざん",
    "meaning": "sacred mountain"
  },
  {
    "question": "仔馬",
    "answer": "こうま",
    "meaning": "small horse, pony, foal, colt, filly"
  },
  {
    "question": "鉄道網",
    "answer": "てつどうもう",
    "meaning": "railroad network, railroad system"
  },
  {
    "question": "廻し",
    "answer": "まわし",
    "meaning": "mawashi, belt, loincloth, mantle, cape, gang rape"
  },
  {
    "question": "夕凪",
    "answer": "ゆうなぎ",
    "meaning": "evening calm"
  },
  {
    "question": "艤装",
    "answer": "ぎそう",
    "meaning": "outfitting (of a ship), rigging, (ship's) outfit, fittings, equipment"
  },
  {
    "question": "天皇陛下",
    "answer": "てんのうへいか",
    "meaning": "His Majesty the Emperor"
  },
  {
    "question": "業務提携",
    "answer": "ぎょうむていけい",
    "meaning": "business partnership"
  },
  {
    "question": "野人",
    "answer": "やじん",
    "meaning": "rustic, country bumpkin, countryfolk, ruffian, unrefined person, non-politician, non-government pers"
  },
  {
    "question": "引換券",
    "answer": "ひきかえけん",
    "meaning": "exchange ticket, claim tag, coupon"
  },
  {
    "question": "空気入れ",
    "answer": "くうきいれ",
    "meaning": "air pump, bicycle pump"
  },
  {
    "question": "夜釣り",
    "answer": "よづり",
    "meaning": "night angling, night fishing"
  },
  {
    "question": "絵物語",
    "answer": "えものがたり",
    "meaning": "illustrated story"
  },
  {
    "question": "異境",
    "answer": "いきょう",
    "meaning": "foreign country, foreign land, strange land, far-off land"
  },
  {
    "question": "馬身",
    "answer": "ばしん",
    "meaning": "horse's length"
  },
  {
    "question": "語録",
    "answer": "ごろく",
    "meaning": "analects, sayings"
  },
  {
    "question": "無国籍",
    "answer": "むこくせき",
    "meaning": "statelessness, stateless"
  },
  {
    "question": "静穏",
    "answer": "せいおん",
    "meaning": "tranquility, tranquillity, calmness, serenity, quietness"
  },
  {
    "question": "渾然",
    "answer": "こんぜん",
    "meaning": "whole, entire, harmonious, well-rounded"
  },
  {
    "question": "装飾的",
    "answer": "そうしょくてき",
    "meaning": "decorative"
  },
  {
    "question": "美白",
    "answer": "びはく",
    "meaning": "prevention of sun-related skin damage, whitening (skin, teeth, etc.)"
  },
  {
    "question": "句読点",
    "answer": "くとうてん",
    "meaning": "punctuation mark"
  },
  {
    "question": "便意",
    "answer": "べんい",
    "meaning": "call of nature, urge to urinate or defecate (esp. to defecate)"
  },
  {
    "question": "蒙る",
    "answer": "こうむる",
    "meaning": "to suffer, to receive (kindness, rebuke, support), to sustain (damage)"
  },
  {
    "question": "板切れ",
    "answer": "いたきれ",
    "meaning": "scrap lumber, piece of wood"
  },
  {
    "question": "排尿",
    "answer": "はいにょう",
    "meaning": "urination, micturition"
  },
  {
    "question": "軍用機",
    "answer": "ぐんようき",
    "meaning": "military aircraft"
  },
  {
    "question": "三輪車",
    "answer": "さんりんしゃ",
    "meaning": "three wheeled vehicle (tricycle, motorcycle, etc.), three wheeler"
  },
  {
    "question": "誤診",
    "answer": "ごしん",
    "meaning": "wrong diagnosis, misdiagnosis"
  },
  {
    "question": "筆先",
    "answer": "ふでさき",
    "meaning": "tip of brush"
  },
  {
    "question": "臙脂",
    "answer": "えんじ",
    "meaning": "dark-red pigment, rouge, dark red, deep red, cochineal"
  },
  {
    "question": "峻烈",
    "answer": "しゅんれつ",
    "meaning": "severe, harsh, rigorous, trenchant, scathing, sharp, incisive, cutting"
  },
  {
    "question": "放課",
    "answer": "ほうか",
    "meaning": "dismissal of class (at the end of the day), recess (at school), break"
  },
  {
    "question": "取扱",
    "answer": "とりあつかい",
    "meaning": "treatment, service, handling, management"
  },
  {
    "question": "沈降",
    "answer": "ちんこう",
    "meaning": "sedimentation, subsidence, precipitation, sinking, settling, submerging"
  },
  {
    "question": "密通",
    "answer": "みっつう",
    "meaning": "adultery, misconduct, intrigue, criminal connection"
  },
  {
    "question": "平皿",
    "answer": "ひらざら",
    "meaning": "flat dish"
  },
  {
    "question": "馬鹿高い",
    "answer": "ばかたかい",
    "meaning": "ridiculously expensive, stupidly expensive"
  },
  {
    "question": "熱冷まし",
    "answer": "ねつさまし",
    "meaning": "medicine for reducing fever, antifebrile, antipyretic, febrifuge"
  },
  {
    "question": "何時かは",
    "answer": "いつかは",
    "meaning": "sooner or later, in due time, in due course"
  },
  {
    "question": "後転",
    "answer": "こうてん",
    "meaning": "backward somersault, backward roll"
  },
  {
    "question": "満漢全席",
    "answer": "まんかんぜんせき",
    "meaning": "Manchu-Han Imperial Feast, three-day feast of Chinese delicacies held during the Qing dynasty"
  },
  {
    "question": "気管支",
    "answer": "きかんし",
    "meaning": "bronchial tube"
  },
  {
    "question": "髣髴",
    "answer": "ほうふつ",
    "meaning": "(bearing a) close resemblance, vivid reminder (e.g. of the past), dim, faint, vague, blurred"
  },
  {
    "question": "馬鹿丁寧",
    "answer": "ばかていねい",
    "meaning": "overly polite, excessively polite, polite to a fault"
  },
  {
    "question": "増刷",
    "answer": "ぞうさつ",
    "meaning": "additional printing (esp. of books, etc.), additional run"
  },
  {
    "question": "慰安",
    "answer": "いあん",
    "meaning": "solace, relaxation"
  },
  {
    "question": "途切れ",
    "answer": "とぎれ",
    "meaning": "break, pause, interruption, intermission"
  },
  {
    "question": "同姓",
    "answer": "どうせい",
    "meaning": "same surname"
  },
  {
    "question": "実費",
    "answer": "じっぴ",
    "meaning": "actual expenses, out-of-pocket expenses, cost price"
  },
  {
    "question": "猫の額",
    "answer": "ねこのひたい",
    "meaning": "tiny area, tiny surface, cat's forehead"
  },
  {
    "question": "良品",
    "answer": "りょうひん",
    "meaning": "superior article"
  },
  {
    "question": "取り殺す",
    "answer": "とりころす",
    "meaning": "to haunt to death, to possess and kill"
  },
  {
    "question": "社外",
    "answer": "しゃがい",
    "meaning": "outside the company"
  },
  {
    "question": "地盤沈下",
    "answer": "じばんちんか",
    "meaning": "land subsidence, decline in influence"
  },
  {
    "question": "馥郁",
    "answer": "ふくいく",
    "meaning": "fragrant, sweet-smelling"
  },
  {
    "question": "遅咲き",
    "answer": "おそざき",
    "meaning": "late blooming (flower, talent), late flowering"
  },
  {
    "question": "生活苦",
    "answer": "せいかつく",
    "meaning": "life's struggles"
  },
  {
    "question": "裁判沙汰",
    "answer": "さいばんざた",
    "meaning": "law suit, litigation"
  },
  {
    "question": "夢想家",
    "answer": "むそうか",
    "meaning": "dreamer"
  },
  {
    "question": "黒百合",
    "answer": "くろゆり",
    "meaning": "black lily (Fritillaria camtschatcensis), Kamchatka lily, Kamchatka fritillary"
  },
  {
    "question": "神州",
    "answer": "しんしゅう",
    "meaning": "land of the gods, Japan, China"
  },
  {
    "question": "不戦条約",
    "answer": "ふせんじょうやく",
    "meaning": "Kellogg-Briand Pact (1928), Pact of Paris"
  },
  {
    "question": "通信社",
    "answer": "つうしんしゃ",
    "meaning": "news agency"
  },
  {
    "question": "貞",
    "answer": "てい",
    "meaning": "firm adherence to one's principles, chastity (of a woman)"
  },
  {
    "question": "航海日誌",
    "answer": "こうかいにっし",
    "meaning": "ship's log, logbook"
  },
  {
    "question": "鰓",
    "answer": "えら,あぎと",
    "meaning": "gills, branchia, angle of the mandible, gonial angle, chin, jaw"
  },
  {
    "question": "有為",
    "answer": "ゆうい,うい",
    "meaning": "capable, able, talented, promising, perpetual change caused by karma, vicissitudes of life, that whi"
  },
  {
    "question": "韓国語",
    "answer": "かんこくご",
    "meaning": "Korean (language)"
  },
  {
    "question": "地質調査",
    "answer": "ちしつちょうさ",
    "meaning": "geological survey"
  },
  {
    "question": "北九州",
    "answer": "きたきゅうしゅう",
    "meaning": "Kitakyushu (city)"
  },
  {
    "question": "南中",
    "answer": "なんちゅう",
    "meaning": "crossing the meridian"
  },
  {
    "question": "落語家",
    "answer": "らくごか",
    "meaning": "rakugo story teller, comic story teller"
  },
  {
    "question": "小袖",
    "answer": "こそで",
    "meaning": "short sleeved kimono (worn as an undergarment during the Heian period), padded silk garment"
  },
  {
    "question": "朽木",
    "answer": "くちき",
    "meaning": "decayed tree, rotted tree, decayed wood, rotten wood, obscure, meaningless life (metaphor)"
  },
  {
    "question": "端然",
    "answer": "たんぜん",
    "meaning": "upright"
  },
  {
    "question": "美顔",
    "answer": "びがん",
    "meaning": "beautiful face"
  },
  {
    "question": "取り縋る",
    "answer": "とりすがる",
    "meaning": "to cling to"
  },
  {
    "question": "百物語",
    "answer": "ひゃくものがたり",
    "meaning": "round of ghost stories (trad. at night with a lamp or candle being extinguished after each story)"
  },
  {
    "question": "船足",
    "answer": "ふなあし",
    "meaning": "speed of a boat, draft, draught"
  },
  {
    "question": "胴間声",
    "answer": "どうまごえ",
    "meaning": "(vulgar) thick voice"
  },
  {
    "question": "紳士協定",
    "answer": "しんしきょうてい",
    "meaning": "gentlemen's agreement"
  },
  {
    "question": "猫っ毛",
    "answer": "ねこっけ",
    "meaning": "fine, soft hair"
  },
  {
    "question": "猛撃",
    "answer": "もうげき",
    "meaning": "furious attack"
  },
  {
    "question": "絵巻物",
    "answer": "えまきもの",
    "meaning": "picture scroll"
  },
  {
    "question": "栓抜き",
    "answer": "せんぬき",
    "meaning": "bottle opener, corkscrew"
  },
  {
    "question": "合併症",
    "answer": "がっぺいしょう",
    "meaning": "complications (in an illness)"
  },
  {
    "question": "国事",
    "answer": "こくじ",
    "meaning": "national affairs"
  },
  {
    "question": "闇取引",
    "answer": "やみとりひき",
    "meaning": "black-market dealings, underhand transactions, shady trading, illegal trade, secret dealings, secret"
  },
  {
    "question": "潮干狩り",
    "answer": "しおひがり",
    "meaning": "shell gathering (at low tide), clamming"
  },
  {
    "question": "四半世紀",
    "answer": "しはんせいき",
    "meaning": "quarter of a century"
  },
  {
    "question": "腹巻き",
    "answer": "はらまき",
    "meaning": "haramaki, bellyband, stomach band, stomach covering (worn for warmth), torso armour that opens at th"
  },
  {
    "question": "無思慮",
    "answer": "むしりょ",
    "meaning": "thoughtlessness, indiscretion"
  },
  {
    "question": "母音",
    "answer": "ぼいん,ぼおん",
    "meaning": "vowel"
  },
  {
    "question": "道義的",
    "answer": "どうぎてき",
    "meaning": "moral"
  },
  {
    "question": "依怙贔屓",
    "answer": "えこひいき",
    "meaning": "favoritism, favouritism, partiality, prejudice, bias"
  },
  {
    "question": "光度",
    "answer": "こうど",
    "meaning": "intensity of light"
  },
  {
    "question": "詮議",
    "answer": "せんぎ",
    "meaning": "discussion, deliberation, consideration, investigation (into a suspect), inquiry, enquiry, examinati"
  },
  {
    "question": "微少",
    "answer": "びしょう",
    "meaning": "infinitesimal"
  },
  {
    "question": "凹ます",
    "answer": "へこます",
    "meaning": "to dent, to indent, to depress, to humiliate"
  },
  {
    "question": "通信教育",
    "answer": "つうしんきょういく",
    "meaning": "correspondence education, correspondence course, distance education"
  },
  {
    "question": "直火",
    "answer": "じかび",
    "meaning": "open fire, direct heat"
  },
  {
    "question": "網棚",
    "answer": "あみだな",
    "meaning": "overhead luggage rack, overhead baggage rack"
  },
  {
    "question": "表玄関",
    "answer": "おもてげんかん",
    "meaning": "front door, vestibule"
  },
  {
    "question": "食い残す",
    "answer": "くいのこす",
    "meaning": "to leave food half-eaten"
  },
  {
    "question": "政局",
    "answer": "せいきょく",
    "meaning": "political situation"
  },
  {
    "question": "営業停止",
    "answer": "えいぎょうていし",
    "meaning": "suspension of business"
  },
  {
    "question": "取り下げ",
    "answer": "とりさげ",
    "meaning": "withdrawal"
  },
  {
    "question": "亜鉛",
    "answer": "あえん",
    "meaning": "zinc (Zn)"
  },
  {
    "question": "親譲り",
    "answer": "おやゆずり",
    "meaning": "inheritance from a parent"
  },
  {
    "question": "泣き上戸",
    "answer": "なきじょうご",
    "meaning": "maudlin drinker, person who is prone to crying when drunk"
  },
  {
    "question": "佐倉",
    "answer": "",
    "meaning": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "嬉野",
    "answer": "",
    "meaning": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "森厳",
    "answer": "しんげん",
    "meaning": "solemn"
  },
  {
    "question": "虚無僧",
    "answer": "こむそう",
    "meaning": "begging Zen priest of the Fuke sect (wearing a sedge hood and playing a shakuhachi flute)"
  },
  {
    "question": "色相",
    "answer": "しきそう",
    "meaning": "hue, color phase, colour phase"
  },
  {
    "question": "廃船",
    "answer": "はいせん",
    "meaning": "scrapped vessel"
  },
  {
    "question": "純水",
    "answer": "じゅんすい",
    "meaning": "pure water"
  },
  {
    "question": "叛徒",
    "answer": "はんと",
    "meaning": "rebels, insurgents"
  },
  {
    "question": "婦人警官",
    "answer": "ふじんけいかん",
    "meaning": "policewoman"
  },
  {
    "question": "株券",
    "answer": "かぶけん",
    "meaning": "stock certificate"
  },
  {
    "question": "毬",
    "answer": "まり,いが,かさ",
    "meaning": "ball (for sport, games, etc.), kemari, type of football played by courtiers in ancient Japan, burr ("
  },
  {
    "question": "内堀",
    "answer": "うちぼり",
    "meaning": "inner moat, moat within the castle walls"
  },
  {
    "question": "膵臓",
    "answer": "すいぞう",
    "meaning": "pancreas"
  },
  {
    "question": "重層",
    "answer": "じゅうそう",
    "meaning": "multistoried, multilayered"
  },
  {
    "question": "膚",
    "answer": "はだ,はだえ",
    "meaning": "skin, body (in the context of intimate bodily contact), surface, grain (e.g. of wood), texture, disp"
  },
  {
    "question": "祇園",
    "answer": "",
    "meaning": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "腰巻き",
    "answer": "こしまき",
    "meaning": "loincloth, waistcloth, kimono underskirt"
  },
  {
    "question": "硝石",
    "answer": "しょうせき",
    "meaning": "saltpeter, saltpetre, niter, nitre, potassium nitrate"
  },
  {
    "question": "写真館",
    "answer": "しゃしんかん",
    "meaning": "photo studio"
  },
  {
    "question": "回顧録",
    "answer": "かいころく",
    "meaning": "memoirs, reminiscences"
  },
  {
    "question": "屈折率",
    "answer": "くっせつりつ",
    "meaning": "refractive index"
  },
  {
    "question": "消防団",
    "answer": "しょうぼうだん",
    "meaning": "fire department (in Japan, composed of on call civilian firefighters)"
  },
  {
    "question": "産廃",
    "answer": "さんぱい",
    "meaning": "industrial waste"
  },
  {
    "question": "地所",
    "answer": "じしょ,ちしょ",
    "meaning": "estate, plot of land"
  },
  {
    "question": "風呂釜",
    "answer": "ふろがま",
    "meaning": "bath heater"
  },
  {
    "question": "落胤",
    "answer": "らくいん",
    "meaning": "nobleman's illegitimate child"
  },
  {
    "question": "光臨",
    "answer": "こうりん",
    "meaning": "arrival, visit, call"
  },
  {
    "question": "山の端",
    "answer": "やまのは",
    "meaning": "edge (brow) of mountain"
  },
  {
    "question": "慙愧",
    "answer": "ざんき,ざんぎ",
    "meaning": "(feeling of) shame"
  },
  {
    "question": "自己破産",
    "answer": "じこはさん",
    "meaning": "personal bankruptcy, voluntary bankruptcy"
  },
  {
    "question": "運転資金",
    "answer": "うんてんしきん",
    "meaning": "working capital"
  },
  {
    "question": "寄稿",
    "answer": "きこう",
    "meaning": "contribution (e.g. to newspaper)"
  },
  {
    "question": "密輸入",
    "answer": "みつゆにゅう",
    "meaning": "smuggling in"
  },
  {
    "question": "脱糞",
    "answer": "だっぷん",
    "meaning": "a bowel movement"
  },
  {
    "question": "片手落ち",
    "answer": "かたておち",
    "meaning": "one-sided, partial, unfair"
  },
  {
    "question": "喪中",
    "answer": "もちゅう",
    "meaning": "in mourning"
  },
  {
    "question": "舶来",
    "answer": "はくらい",
    "meaning": "imported, foreign-made"
  },
  {
    "question": "再犯",
    "answer": "さいはん",
    "meaning": "second offense, second offence"
  },
  {
    "question": "多産",
    "answer": "たさん",
    "meaning": "fecundity, having many children, abundant production"
  },
  {
    "question": "撥水",
    "answer": "はっすい",
    "meaning": "water repellency"
  },
  {
    "question": "恋い慕う",
    "answer": "こいしたう",
    "meaning": "to miss, to yearn for"
  },
  {
    "question": "経度",
    "answer": "けいど",
    "meaning": "longitude"
  },
  {
    "question": "戦闘的",
    "answer": "せんとうてき",
    "meaning": "militant, aggressive"
  },
  {
    "question": "生き字引",
    "answer": "いきじびき",
    "meaning": "walking encyclopedia, walking dictionary"
  },
  {
    "question": "一案",
    "answer": "いちあん",
    "meaning": "idea, plan"
  },
  {
    "question": "東北地方",
    "answer": "とうほくちほう",
    "meaning": "Tōhoku region (northernmost six prefectures of Honshu), Tohoku region"
  },
  {
    "question": "素潜り",
    "answer": "すもぐり",
    "meaning": "skin diving, free diving"
  },
  {
    "question": "水入れ",
    "answer": "みずいれ",
    "meaning": "water vessel"
  },
  {
    "question": "飛び飛び",
    "answer": "とびとび",
    "meaning": "scattered here and there, at intervals"
  },
  {
    "question": "八丁",
    "answer": "はっちょう",
    "meaning": "skillfulness"
  },
  {
    "question": "律法",
    "answer": "りっぽう",
    "meaning": "law, rule, commandment, the Torah (the law of God as revealed to Moses)"
  },
  {
    "question": "魯",
    "answer": "ろ",
    "meaning": "Russia, Lu (Chinese vassal state existing during the Spring and Autumn period)"
  },
  {
    "question": "ゼロ戦",
    "answer": "ゼロせん",
    "meaning": "Zero fighter plane"
  },
  {
    "question": "黒鍵",
    "answer": "こっけん",
    "meaning": "black key (on a piano, organ, etc.)"
  },
  {
    "question": "廻廊",
    "answer": "かいろう",
    "meaning": "corridor, gallery, hallway, cloister (i.e. covered walk typically circling a building or garden, esp"
  },
  {
    "question": "追い着く",
    "answer": "おいつく",
    "meaning": "to catch up (with), to draw level, to pull even, to reach, to be compensated, to make up for one's l"
  },
  {
    "question": "産科",
    "answer": "さんか",
    "meaning": "obstetrics"
  },
  {
    "question": "桃園",
    "answer": "ももぞの",
    "meaning": "peach orchard"
  },
  {
    "question": "真直ぐ",
    "answer": "まっすぐ,ますぐ",
    "meaning": "straight (ahead), direct, upright, erect, straightforward, honest, frank"
  },
  {
    "question": "標準時",
    "answer": "ひょうじゅんじ",
    "meaning": "standard time"
  },
  {
    "question": "蒲団",
    "answer": "ふとん",
    "meaning": "futon, Japanese bedding consisting of a mattress and a duvet, round cushion used for Zen meditation"
  },
  {
    "question": "混淆",
    "answer": "こんこう",
    "meaning": "mixture, intermixture, mixing up, jumbling together, contamination, creation of unorthodox words or"
  },
  {
    "question": "一世",
    "answer": "いっせい,いっせ",
    "meaning": "generation, lifetime, the age, the day, the First, issei, first-generation Japanese (or Korean, etc."
  },
  {
    "question": "万引",
    "answer": "まんびき",
    "meaning": "shoplifting, shoplifter"
  },
  {
    "question": "伝奇",
    "answer": "でんき",
    "meaning": "romance (fiction)"
  },
  {
    "question": "乳搾り",
    "answer": "ちちしぼり",
    "meaning": "milking, milker, milkmaid"
  },
  {
    "question": "淫欲",
    "answer": "いんよく",
    "meaning": "lust"
  },
  {
    "question": "ポリ袋",
    "answer": "ポリぶくろ",
    "meaning": "plastic bag, polyethylene bag"
  },
  {
    "question": "地鶏",
    "answer": "じどり,じとり",
    "meaning": "nationally protected chicken breed, free-range local traditional pedigree chicken, chicken meat from"
  },
  {
    "question": "置場",
    "answer": "おきば",
    "meaning": "place for something, storehouse"
  },
  {
    "question": "繊毛",
    "answer": "せんもう",
    "meaning": "cilia, cilium, fine hairs"
  },
  {
    "question": "性技",
    "answer": "せいぎ",
    "meaning": "sexual techniques"
  },
  {
    "question": "中央集権",
    "answer": "ちゅうおうしゅうけん",
    "meaning": "centralized authoritarian rule, centralised authoritarian rule"
  },
  {
    "question": "七並べ",
    "answer": "しちならべ",
    "meaning": "fan-tan (card game), sevens, parliament"
  },
  {
    "question": "海釣り",
    "answer": "うみづり",
    "meaning": "sea fishing"
  },
  {
    "question": "見映え",
    "answer": "みばえ",
    "meaning": "airs, pretensions, show, ostentation, display, appearance, vanity, charm"
  },
  {
    "question": "骨片",
    "answer": "こっぺん",
    "meaning": "bone fragment, spicule"
  },
  {
    "question": "金脈",
    "answer": "きんみゃく",
    "meaning": "vein of gold, financial connections, patron, source of money"
  },
  {
    "question": "乙女座",
    "answer": "おとめざ",
    "meaning": "Virgo (constellation), the Virgin"
  },
  {
    "question": "漢文",
    "answer": "かんぶん",
    "meaning": "Chinese classical writing, Chinese classics, writing composed entirely of kanji"
  },
  {
    "question": "物影",
    "answer": "ものかげ",
    "meaning": "form, shape, figure"
  },
  {
    "question": "伍する",
    "answer": "ごする",
    "meaning": "to rank with, to rank among"
  },
  {
    "question": "柏手",
    "answer": "かしわで,はくしゅ",
    "meaning": "clapping one's hands in prayer (at a shrine)"
  },
  {
    "question": "知謀",
    "answer": "ちぼう",
    "meaning": "ingenuity, resourcefulness"
  },
  {
    "question": "留保",
    "answer": "りゅうほ",
    "meaning": "reserving, withholding"
  },
  {
    "question": "斯く",
    "answer": "かく",
    "meaning": "like this, such, thus, in this way"
  },
  {
    "question": "頭金",
    "answer": "あたまきん",
    "meaning": "down payment, deposit"
  },
  {
    "question": "員数",
    "answer": "いんずう,いんず,いんじゅ",
    "meaning": "(total) number (of people or things), count, quota"
  },
  {
    "question": "局所",
    "answer": "きょくしょ",
    "meaning": "part, section, part of the body, affected part (of the body), local (e.g. anesthesia), topical, priv"
  },
  {
    "question": "応手",
    "answer": "おうしゅ",
    "meaning": "(primarily in shogi or go) response, countermeasure, counter-measure"
  },
  {
    "question": "愁嘆場",
    "answer": "しゅうたんば",
    "meaning": "pathetic scene"
  },
  {
    "question": "芳ばしい",
    "answer": "こうばしい",
    "meaning": "aromatic (roasted beans, roasted tea, etc.), fragrant (e.g. burning wood), pleasant-smelling, savory"
  },
  {
    "question": "則する",
    "answer": "そくする",
    "meaning": "to conform to, to agree with, to be adapted to, to be based on"
  },
  {
    "question": "病み付き",
    "answer": "やみつき",
    "meaning": "being addicted to, being wholly absorbed by, falling ill, becoming sick"
  },
  {
    "question": "直情径行",
    "answer": "ちょくじょうけいこう",
    "meaning": "impulsive and straightforward, guileless"
  },
  {
    "question": "靴擦れ",
    "answer": "くつずれ",
    "meaning": "shoe sore, foot blister (caused by shoes)"
  },
  {
    "question": "無利子",
    "answer": "むりし",
    "meaning": "(earning or paying) no interest"
  },
  {
    "question": "手付け",
    "answer": "てつけ",
    "meaning": "deposit, earnest money"
  },
  {
    "question": "底深い",
    "answer": "そこふかい,そこぶかい",
    "meaning": "very deep"
  },
  {
    "question": "第一義",
    "answer": "だいいちぎ",
    "meaning": "primary significance, primary importance, first principle, absolute truth, ultimate truth"
  },
  {
    "question": "付け足し",
    "answer": "つけたし",
    "meaning": "addition, appendix, supplement, postscript"
  },
  {
    "question": "酌量",
    "answer": "しゃくりょう",
    "meaning": "taking into consideration, making allowances"
  },
  {
    "question": "銀将",
    "answer": "ぎんしょう",
    "meaning": "silver general"
  },
  {
    "question": "輝点",
    "answer": "きてん",
    "meaning": "light spot (e.g. blip on radar), always-on pixel (as a defect in LCD screens, etc.), calescence poin"
  },
  {
    "question": "自警",
    "answer": "じけい",
    "meaning": "policing (an area, etc.) by oneself, protecting by oneself, vigilantism, cautioning oneself, taking"
  },
  {
    "question": "麿",
    "answer": "まろ",
    "meaning": "I, me, (person having) thin or shaved eyebrows, affectionate suffix for names of young men or pets"
  },
  {
    "question": "魔風",
    "answer": "まかぜ,まふう",
    "meaning": "storm caused by the devil, evil wind, eerie wind"
  },
  {
    "question": "板戸",
    "answer": "いたど",
    "meaning": "wooden door"
  },
  {
    "question": "過食",
    "answer": "かしょく",
    "meaning": "overeating"
  },
  {
    "question": "茶の湯",
    "answer": "ちゃのゆ",
    "meaning": "tea ceremony"
  },
  {
    "question": "本局",
    "answer": "ほんきょく",
    "meaning": "main office"
  },
  {
    "question": "田圃",
    "answer": "たんぼ,でんぽ,でんぼ",
    "meaning": "paddy field, farm"
  },
  {
    "question": "老中",
    "answer": "ろうじゅう,ろうぢゅう",
    "meaning": "member of shogun's council of elders"
  },
  {
    "question": "死斑",
    "answer": "しはん",
    "meaning": "postmortem lividity"
  },
  {
    "question": "荷馬",
    "answer": "にうま",
    "meaning": "pack horse"
  },
  {
    "question": "三竦み",
    "answer": "さんすくみ",
    "meaning": "three-way deadlock"
  },
  {
    "question": "日本画",
    "answer": "にほんが",
    "meaning": "Japanese painting"
  },
  {
    "question": "口寄せ",
    "answer": "くちよせ",
    "meaning": "spiritualism, spiritism, channeling, summoning a spirit and giving him voice (esp. when done by a fe"
  },
  {
    "question": "科白",
    "answer": "せりふ,かはく",
    "meaning": "speech, words, one's lines, remarks"
  },
  {
    "question": "気筒",
    "answer": "きとう",
    "meaning": "cylinder"
  },
  {
    "question": "監房",
    "answer": "かんぼう",
    "meaning": "(prison) cell, ward"
  },
  {
    "question": "法学",
    "answer": "ほうがく",
    "meaning": "law, jurisprudence"
  },
  {
    "question": "帆布",
    "answer": "はんぷ,ほぬの",
    "meaning": "sailcloth, canvas"
  },
  {
    "question": "釉薬",
    "answer": "うわぐすり,ゆうやく",
    "meaning": "glaze, overglaze, enamel"
  },
  {
    "question": "発振",
    "answer": "はっしん",
    "meaning": "oscillation"
  },
  {
    "question": "距",
    "answer": "けづめ,きょ",
    "meaning": "fetlock (horse, etc.), spur (chicken, etc.), cockspur, dewclaw (dog, etc.), tubular nectary, spur"
  },
  {
    "question": "終盤戦",
    "answer": "しゅうばんせん",
    "meaning": "end of campaign"
  },
  {
    "question": "萎",
    "answer": "しおり",
    "meaning": "interpenetration of spirit between the poet and nature in a haiku"
  },
  {
    "question": "同腹",
    "answer": "どうふく",
    "meaning": "born of the same mother, kindred spirits"
  },
  {
    "question": "浄水器",
    "answer": "じょうすいき",
    "meaning": "water filter, water purification system"
  },
  {
    "question": "変心",
    "answer": "へんしん",
    "meaning": "change of mind, inconstancy, apostasy"
  },
  {
    "question": "同性婚",
    "answer": "どうせいこん",
    "meaning": "same-sex marriage, gay marriage"
  },
  {
    "question": "植物学",
    "answer": "しょくぶつがく",
    "meaning": "botany"
  },
  {
    "question": "一雫",
    "answer": "ひとしずく",
    "meaning": "drop (of fluid)"
  },
  {
    "question": "鉄線",
    "answer": "てっせん",
    "meaning": "iron (steel) wire, Chinese clematis, Clematis florida, leather flower"
  },
  {
    "question": "四つ角",
    "answer": "よつかど",
    "meaning": "four corners, crossroads, intersecting street, street corner"
  },
  {
    "question": "黒色火薬",
    "answer": "こくしょくかやく",
    "meaning": "black powder, gunpowder"
  },
  {
    "question": "軽挙",
    "answer": "けいきょ",
    "meaning": "hasty act, rash act"
  },
  {
    "question": "徴集",
    "answer": "ちょうしゅう",
    "meaning": "levying, requisitioning, compulsory enlistment, recruitment, conscription"
  },
  {
    "question": "召喚状",
    "answer": "しょうかんじょう",
    "meaning": "call, summons, subpoena"
  },
  {
    "question": "記章",
    "answer": "きしょう",
    "meaning": "medal, badge, insignia"
  },
  {
    "question": "寸毫",
    "answer": "すんごう",
    "meaning": "(not) the slightest bit, (not) the least, (not) at all"
  },
  {
    "question": "自刃",
    "answer": "じじん",
    "meaning": "suicide by the sword"
  },
  {
    "question": "斤",
    "answer": "きん",
    "meaning": "kin, catty, traditional unit of weight, 600g, pound (unit of weight), loaf (of bread)"
  },
  {
    "question": "復する",
    "answer": "ふくする",
    "meaning": "to return to normal, to recover, to restore"
  },
  {
    "question": "帰趨",
    "answer": "きすう,きしゅ",
    "meaning": "outcome (of a course of events), consequence, tendency, trend, drift"
  },
  {
    "question": "満場",
    "answer": "まんじょう",
    "meaning": "whole house, whole audience"
  },
  {
    "question": "郎党",
    "answer": "ろうどう,ろうとう",
    "meaning": "vassals, retainers, followers"
  },
  {
    "question": "鑿",
    "answer": "のみ",
    "meaning": "chisel"
  },
  {
    "question": "軍需産業",
    "answer": "ぐんじゅさんぎょう",
    "meaning": "munitions industry, war industry"
  },
  {
    "question": "包括",
    "answer": "ほうかつ",
    "meaning": "inclusion, complete coverage, comprehensiveness"
  },
  {
    "question": "和み",
    "answer": "なごみ",
    "meaning": "feeling of calmness and relaxation"
  },
  {
    "question": "厄除け",
    "answer": "やくよけ",
    "meaning": "warding off evil, protecting against misfortune"
  },
  {
    "question": "乱行",
    "answer": "らんぎょう",
    "meaning": "violent conduct, misconduct, dissipation, profligacy, debauchery"
  },
  {
    "question": "転寝",
    "answer": "うたたね,ごろね",
    "meaning": "doze, nap, snooze, falling asleep (in one's clothes), lying down to nap, crashing out"
  },
  {
    "question": "拠る",
    "answer": "よる",
    "meaning": "to be due to, to be caused by, to depend on, to turn on, to be based on, to come from, to be based a"
  },
  {
    "question": "手空き",
    "answer": "てすき,てあき",
    "meaning": "not busy, unengaged, being free, leisure"
  },
  {
    "question": "雨空",
    "answer": "あまぞら",
    "meaning": "rainy sky, sky as it looks when it is about to rain, threatening sky"
  },
  {
    "question": "急峻",
    "answer": "きゅうしゅん",
    "meaning": "steep, sharp"
  },
  {
    "question": "退勤",
    "answer": "たいきん",
    "meaning": "leaving work, clocking out"
  },
  {
    "question": "横歩き",
    "answer": "よこあるき",
    "meaning": "side stepping, sidling"
  },
  {
    "question": "無報酬",
    "answer": "むほうしゅう",
    "meaning": "unpaid, without pay, gratuitous, voluntary"
  },
  {
    "question": "貧窮",
    "answer": "ひんきゅう",
    "meaning": "great poverty"
  },
  {
    "question": "知性的",
    "answer": "ちせいてき",
    "meaning": "intellectual"
  },
  {
    "question": "無分別",
    "answer": "むふんべつ",
    "meaning": "thoughtlessness, indiscretion"
  },
  {
    "question": "日参",
    "answer": "にっさん",
    "meaning": "daily visit (of worship), frequent visit"
  },
  {
    "question": "立ち泳ぎ",
    "answer": "たちおよぎ",
    "meaning": "treading water"
  },
  {
    "question": "精進料理",
    "answer": "しょうじんりょうり",
    "meaning": "vegetarian cuisine originally derived from the dietary restrictions of Buddhist monks"
  },
  {
    "question": "按配",
    "answer": "あんばい",
    "meaning": "seasoning, flavour, flavor, taste, condition, state, situation, (state of) health, physical conditio"
  },
  {
    "question": "掛け値",
    "answer": "かけね",
    "meaning": "inflated price (assigned in anticipation of being haggled down), overcharging, exaggeration"
  },
  {
    "question": "無闇矢鱈",
    "answer": "むやみやたら",
    "meaning": "thoughtless, reckless, rash, indiscriminate, indiscreet, excessive, unreasonable, immoderate, absurd"
  },
  {
    "question": "格式張る",
    "answer": "かくしきばる",
    "meaning": "to adhere to formalities"
  },
  {
    "question": "有名税",
    "answer": "ゆうめいぜい",
    "meaning": "price of fame, penalty of greatness"
  },
  {
    "question": "発声器官",
    "answer": "はっせいきかん",
    "meaning": "vocal organs"
  },
  {
    "question": "七賢人",
    "answer": "しちけんじん",
    "meaning": "the Seven Wise Men (of Greece), the Seven Sages of Greece"
  },
  {
    "question": "大兄",
    "answer": "たいけい",
    "meaning": "older brother, you (in ref. to male of greater age or status)"
  },
  {
    "question": "竜眼",
    "answer": "りゅうがん",
    "meaning": "longan (Euphoria longana)"
  },
  {
    "question": "値動き",
    "answer": "ねうごき",
    "meaning": "price movement, price fluctuation"
  },
  {
    "question": "長江",
    "answer": "ちょうこう",
    "meaning": "Yangtze River, Changjiang River"
  },
  {
    "question": "領国",
    "answer": "りょうごく",
    "meaning": "territory, fiefdom, feudal domain"
  },
  {
    "question": "盛岡",
    "answer": "もりおか",
    "meaning": "Morioka (city in Iwate)"
  },
  {
    "question": "杭打ち機",
    "answer": "くいうちき",
    "meaning": "pile driver, pile-driver"
  },
  {
    "question": "後陣",
    "answer": "こうじん",
    "meaning": "rear guard, reserve troops"
  },
  {
    "question": "求道",
    "answer": "きゅうどう,ぐどう",
    "meaning": "seeking for truth"
  },
  {
    "question": "石灯籠",
    "answer": "いしどうろう,いしとうろう",
    "meaning": "stone lantern"
  },
  {
    "question": "両用",
    "answer": "りょうよう",
    "meaning": "dual use"
  },
  {
    "question": "禅寺",
    "answer": "ぜんでら",
    "meaning": "Zen temple"
  },
  {
    "question": "舞妓",
    "answer": "まいこ,ぶぎ",
    "meaning": "maiko, apprentice geisha, dancing girl"
  },
  {
    "question": "応射",
    "answer": "おうしゃ",
    "meaning": "return fire, shooting back"
  },
  {
    "question": "台紙",
    "answer": "だいし",
    "meaning": "backing paper (for a photo, painting, etc.), mat, mount"
  },
  {
    "question": "鎌倉幕府",
    "answer": "かまくらばくふ",
    "meaning": "Kamakura shogunate (1185-1333 CE)"
  },
  {
    "question": "集く",
    "answer": "すだく",
    "meaning": "to chirp (of a swarm of insects), to sing, to gather, to swarm"
  },
  {
    "question": "慮外",
    "answer": "りょがい",
    "meaning": "unexpected"
  },
  {
    "question": "蕁麻疹",
    "answer": "じんましん",
    "meaning": "hives, nettle rash, urticaria"
  },
  {
    "question": "地軸",
    "answer": "ちじく",
    "meaning": "earth's axis"
  },
  {
    "question": "生化学",
    "answer": "せいかがく",
    "meaning": "biochemistry"
  },
  {
    "question": "太陽電池",
    "answer": "たいようでんち",
    "meaning": "solar cell"
  },
  {
    "question": "服務",
    "answer": "ふくむ",
    "meaning": "duty, public service"
  },
  {
    "question": "解離",
    "answer": "かいり",
    "meaning": "dissociation"
  },
  {
    "question": "運動着",
    "answer": "うんどうぎ",
    "meaning": "sportswear"
  },
  {
    "question": "資本金",
    "answer": "しほんきん",
    "meaning": "capital stock"
  },
  {
    "question": "閾値",
    "answer": "いきち,しきいち",
    "meaning": "threshold (amount, dose, etc.)"
  },
  {
    "question": "毒蜘蛛",
    "answer": "どくぐも",
    "meaning": "poisonous spider, venomous spider, wolf spider"
  },
  {
    "question": "役満",
    "answer": "やくマン",
    "meaning": "yakuman, win worth 32000 points (or, if dealer, 48000 points)"
  },
  {
    "question": "出来高",
    "answer": "できだか",
    "meaning": "yield, crop, production, volume, piecework"
  },
  {
    "question": "歴任",
    "answer": "れきにん",
    "meaning": "successive jobs, consecutive jobs"
  },
  {
    "question": "銘酒",
    "answer": "めいしゅ",
    "meaning": "famous brand of sake, choice sake"
  },
  {
    "question": "面喰らう",
    "answer": "めんくらう",
    "meaning": "to be confused, to be bewildered, to be taken aback"
  },
  {
    "question": "張り出し",
    "answer": "はりだし",
    "meaning": "overhang, poster, placard, notice, extra third or fourth wrestler of certain rank"
  },
  {
    "question": "見晴らす",
    "answer": "みはらす",
    "meaning": "to command a view, to look out over (onto, across, etc.), to overlook"
  },
  {
    "question": "公営",
    "answer": "こうえい",
    "meaning": "public management"
  },
  {
    "question": "連星",
    "answer": "れんせい",
    "meaning": "binary star"
  },
  {
    "question": "偏差",
    "answer": "へんさ",
    "meaning": "deflection, deviation, variation, declination, drift"
  },
  {
    "question": "蓋然性",
    "answer": "がいぜんせい",
    "meaning": "probability, likelihood"
  },
  {
    "question": "相続人",
    "answer": "そうぞくにん",
    "meaning": "heir, heiress, inheritor"
  },
  {
    "question": "不老長寿",
    "answer": "ふろうちょうじゅ",
    "meaning": "perpetual youth and longevity"
  },
  {
    "question": "横揺れ",
    "answer": "よこゆれ",
    "meaning": "horizontal shaking (of an earthquake), rolling (of a boat, aircraft, etc.), swaying"
  },
  {
    "question": "別紙",
    "answer": "べっし",
    "meaning": "enclosure, annex, separate sheet, accompanying sheet"
  },
  {
    "question": "混ぜ返す",
    "answer": "まぜかえす",
    "meaning": "to stir, to mix, to banter, to make fun of (what a person says), to stir up, to jeer at, to interfer"
  },
  {
    "question": "次号",
    "answer": "じごう",
    "meaning": "the next issue"
  },
  {
    "question": "警句",
    "answer": "けいく",
    "meaning": "aphorism, epigram, witticism, bon mots"
  },
  {
    "question": "文末",
    "answer": "ぶんまつ",
    "meaning": "end of a sentence"
  },
  {
    "question": "新式",
    "answer": "しんしき",
    "meaning": "new form, new formula"
  },
  {
    "question": "虫を殺す",
    "answer": "むしをころす",
    "meaning": "to control one's temper"
  },
  {
    "question": "学級崩壊",
    "answer": "がっきゅうほうかい",
    "meaning": "class disruption (e.g. due to discipline problems), classroom chaos"
  },
  {
    "question": "春一番",
    "answer": "はるいちばん",
    "meaning": "first storm of spring, strong winds during the change from winter to spring"
  },
  {
    "question": "高層階",
    "answer": "こうそうかい",
    "meaning": "upper floor (of a high-rise building)"
  },
  {
    "question": "簡便",
    "answer": "かんべん",
    "meaning": "simple, easy, convenient, handy"
  },
  {
    "question": "正常値",
    "answer": "せいじょうち",
    "meaning": "normal value, normal level"
  },
  {
    "question": "土臭い",
    "answer": "つちくさい",
    "meaning": "smelling of earth, rustic"
  },
  {
    "question": "将棋倒し",
    "answer": "しょうぎだおし",
    "meaning": "falling down one after another (like dominoes), toppling shogi pieces (lined up in a row)"
  },
  {
    "question": "年月日",
    "answer": "ねんがっぴ",
    "meaning": "date"
  },
  {
    "question": "波乗り",
    "answer": "なみのり",
    "meaning": "surfing"
  },
  {
    "question": "内省",
    "answer": "ないせい",
    "meaning": "introspection, reflection on one's self"
  },
  {
    "question": "吟じる",
    "answer": "ぎんじる",
    "meaning": "to chant, to sing, to recite, to write (a poem), to compose"
  },
  {
    "question": "一泡",
    "answer": "ひとあわ",
    "meaning": "blow, shock"
  },
  {
    "question": "月額",
    "answer": "げつがく",
    "meaning": "monthly amount (sum)"
  },
  {
    "question": "大甘",
    "answer": "おおあま",
    "meaning": "lenient, overoptimistic"
  },
  {
    "question": "蠱惑",
    "answer": "こわく",
    "meaning": "fascination, glamour, glamor, enchantment, seduction"
  },
  {
    "question": "昔気質",
    "answer": "むかしかたぎ",
    "meaning": "old-fashioned way of thinking, old-fashioned spirit, old-fashioned"
  },
  {
    "question": "荒れ模様",
    "answer": "あれもよう",
    "meaning": "stormy, threatening"
  },
  {
    "question": "抜身",
    "answer": "ぬきみ",
    "meaning": "naked sword, drawn sword, shellfish removed from the shell"
  },
  {
    "question": "速め",
    "answer": "はやめ",
    "meaning": "early, a little earlier than usual, a little faster than usual, slightly quicker"
  },
  {
    "question": "茶飲み",
    "answer": "ちゃのみ",
    "meaning": "tea drinking"
  },
  {
    "question": "丸焼け",
    "answer": "まるやけ",
    "meaning": "total fire loss, completely burned"
  },
  {
    "question": "妓女",
    "answer": "ぎじょ",
    "meaning": "woman entertainer, prostitute"
  },
  {
    "question": "胡",
    "answer": "こ",
    "meaning": "barbarian tribes surrounding ancient China"
  },
  {
    "question": "拡張現実",
    "answer": "かくちょうげんじつ",
    "meaning": "augmented reality, AR"
  },
  {
    "question": "魔鏡",
    "answer": "まきょう",
    "meaning": "makyō, Chinese magic mirror, bronze mirror that projects a hidden sacred image when reflecting a bea"
  },
  {
    "question": "裳",
    "answer": "も,チマ",
    "meaning": "ancient skirt, chima, long skirt traditionally worn by Korean women"
  },
  {
    "question": "医薬",
    "answer": "いやく",
    "meaning": "medicine, Pharmaceutical and Food Safety Bureau"
  },
  {
    "question": "北朝鮮",
    "answer": "きたちょうせん",
    "meaning": "North Korea"
  },
  {
    "question": "仙女",
    "answer": "せんじょ,せんにょ,せんにゅ",
    "meaning": "fairy, nymph, elf"
  },
  {
    "question": "狐憑き",
    "answer": "きつねつき",
    "meaning": "possession by a fox spirit, person possessed by a fox spirit"
  },
  {
    "question": "疵痕",
    "answer": "きずあと",
    "meaning": "scar"
  },
  {
    "question": "差し渡し",
    "answer": "さしわたし",
    "meaning": "distance across, diameter"
  },
  {
    "question": "印象派",
    "answer": "いんしょうは",
    "meaning": "Impressionists"
  },
  {
    "question": "凄烈",
    "answer": "せいれつ",
    "meaning": "fierce"
  },
  {
    "question": "大師",
    "answer": "だいし,たいし",
    "meaning": "great teacher (i.e. a buddha, bodhisattva or high monk, esp. Kobo Daishi), Senior Grand Tutor (senio"
  },
  {
    "question": "保育",
    "answer": "ほいく",
    "meaning": "nursing, nurturing, rearing, lactation, suckling"
  },
  {
    "question": "菜っ葉",
    "answer": "なっぱ",
    "meaning": "greens, vegetable leaves, leaf vegetable"
  },
  {
    "question": "法務省",
    "answer": "ほうむしょう",
    "meaning": "Ministry of Justice"
  },
  {
    "question": "楡",
    "answer": "にれ",
    "meaning": "elm tree (esp. the Japanese elm, Ulmus davidiana var. japonica)"
  },
  {
    "question": "出土品",
    "answer": "しゅつどひん",
    "meaning": "artifact, excavated article, archaeological find"
  },
  {
    "question": "ムール貝",
    "answer": "ムールがい",
    "meaning": "moule, common (blue) mussel"
  },
  {
    "question": "変性",
    "answer": "へんせい",
    "meaning": "denaturation, degeneration"
  },
  {
    "question": "愛知",
    "answer": "あいち",
    "meaning": "Aichi (prefecture)"
  },
  {
    "question": "此れ",
    "answer": "これ",
    "meaning": "this, this one, this person, now, this point (in time), here, used to stress the subject of a senten"
  },
  {
    "question": "前代",
    "answer": "ぜんだい",
    "meaning": "previous generation, former ages"
  },
  {
    "question": "球速",
    "answer": "きゅうそく",
    "meaning": "speed of a pitched ball, (pitcher's) pace"
  },
  {
    "question": "照星",
    "answer": "しょうせい",
    "meaning": "bead or front sight of a firearm"
  },
  {
    "question": "生チョコ",
    "answer": "なまチョコ",
    "meaning": "mixture of chocolate, cream and liquor, used in truffles, ganache, etc."
  },
  {
    "question": "捨て値",
    "answer": "すてね",
    "meaning": "priced dirt cheap"
  },
  {
    "question": "催事",
    "answer": "さいじ",
    "meaning": "special event"
  },
  {
    "question": "凱旋門",
    "answer": "がいせんもん",
    "meaning": "arch of triumph, triumphal arch"
  },
  {
    "question": "大安",
    "answer": "たいあん,だいあん",
    "meaning": "lucky day, auspicious day"
  },
  {
    "question": "乗車券",
    "answer": "じょうしゃけん",
    "meaning": "ticket (for bus, train, etc.), passenger ticket, basic fare ticket (not valid on limited express tra"
  },
  {
    "question": "使い途",
    "answer": "つかいみち",
    "meaning": "purpose, utility, objective, way to use something"
  },
  {
    "question": "自己保存",
    "answer": "じこほぞん",
    "meaning": "self-preservation"
  },
  {
    "question": "改編",
    "answer": "かいへん",
    "meaning": "reorganization, reorganisation"
  },
  {
    "question": "資本家",
    "answer": "しほんか",
    "meaning": "capitalist, financier"
  },
  {
    "question": "父子家庭",
    "answer": "ふしかてい",
    "meaning": "motherless family"
  },
  {
    "question": "交点",
    "answer": "こうてん",
    "meaning": "point of intersection"
  },
  {
    "question": "精神鑑定",
    "answer": "せいしんかんてい",
    "meaning": "psychiatric examination"
  },
  {
    "question": "人倫",
    "answer": "じんりん",
    "meaning": "human relations, humanity"
  },
  {
    "question": "軍紀",
    "answer": "ぐんき",
    "meaning": "military discipline, military regulations, military rules"
  },
  {
    "question": "鎌倉時代",
    "answer": "かまくらじだい",
    "meaning": "Kamakura period (1185-1333 CE)"
  },
  {
    "question": "元金",
    "answer": "がんきん,もときん",
    "meaning": "capital, principal"
  },
  {
    "question": "玄妙",
    "answer": "げんみょう",
    "meaning": "abstruse, occult, mysterious"
  },
  {
    "question": "殊勲",
    "answer": "しゅくん",
    "meaning": "distinguished services, meritorious deeds"
  },
  {
    "question": "本邦",
    "answer": "ほんぽう",
    "meaning": "this country, our country"
  },
  {
    "question": "訣別",
    "answer": "けつべつ",
    "meaning": "separation, farewell, parting"
  },
  {
    "question": "後尾",
    "answer": "こうび",
    "meaning": "the rear"
  },
  {
    "question": "出物",
    "answer": "だしもの,でもの",
    "meaning": "program (e.g. theatre, theater), programme, (theatrical) piece, number, performance, feature, rash,"
  },
  {
    "question": "版権",
    "answer": "はんけん",
    "meaning": "copyright"
  },
  {
    "question": "花模様",
    "answer": "はなもよう",
    "meaning": "floral pattern"
  },
  {
    "question": "ど根性",
    "answer": "どこんじょう",
    "meaning": "utter gutsiness, plenty of guts, grit"
  },
  {
    "question": "具沢山",
    "answer": "ぐだくさん",
    "meaning": "full of ingredients, hearty, substantial"
  },
  {
    "question": "草いきれ",
    "answer": "くさいきれ",
    "meaning": "strong smell of grass (esp. in summer heat)"
  },
  {
    "question": "汚れ物",
    "answer": "よごれもの",
    "meaning": "dirty things (dishes, laundry, etc.)"
  },
  {
    "question": "有形無形",
    "answer": "ゆうけいむけい",
    "meaning": "tangible and intangible, material and spiritual"
  },
  {
    "question": "応用問題",
    "answer": "おうようもんだい",
    "meaning": "application problem, exercises"
  },
  {
    "question": "最高学府",
    "answer": "さいこうがくふ",
    "meaning": "highest institute of education"
  },
  {
    "question": "交際費",
    "answer": "こうさいひ",
    "meaning": "entertainment expenses"
  },
  {
    "question": "事を好む",
    "answer": "ことをこのむ",
    "meaning": "to revel in trouble and discord, to be bent on making trouble, to like starting fights"
  },
  {
    "question": "類似品",
    "answer": "るいじひん",
    "meaning": "imitation, similar article, similar goods"
  },
  {
    "question": "着色料",
    "answer": "ちゃくしょくりょう",
    "meaning": "(food) coloring, pigment, dye, coloring agent"
  },
  {
    "question": "鼻柱",
    "answer": "はなばしら",
    "meaning": "septum, bridge of nose"
  },
  {
    "question": "天引き",
    "answer": "てんびき",
    "meaning": "deduction in advance (of tax, interest, etc.)"
  },
  {
    "question": "実数",
    "answer": "じっすう",
    "meaning": "real number"
  },
  {
    "question": "目配り",
    "answer": "めくばり",
    "meaning": "being watchful, keeping watch, keeping an eye open"
  },
  {
    "question": "布施",
    "answer": "ふせ",
    "meaning": "alms-giving, charity, offerings (usu. money) to a priest (for reading sutras, etc.)"
  },
  {
    "question": "空気銃",
    "answer": "くうきじゅう",
    "meaning": "air gun, air rifle"
  },
  {
    "question": "幕僚長",
    "answer": "ばくりょうちょう",
    "meaning": "chief of staff"
  },
  {
    "question": "水精",
    "answer": "すいしょう",
    "meaning": "(rock) crystal, high purity quartz"
  },
  {
    "question": "児童館",
    "answer": "じどうかん",
    "meaning": "children's house, child welfare residential facility"
  },
  {
    "question": "本会議",
    "answer": "ほんかいぎ",
    "meaning": "plenary session, regular session"
  },
  {
    "question": "虎の巻",
    "answer": "とらのまき",
    "meaning": "book of (trade) secrets, secrets, study guide (to supplement a textbook), crib, key"
  },
  {
    "question": "屋上庭園",
    "answer": "おくじょうていえん",
    "meaning": "rooftop garden"
  },
  {
    "question": "一眼",
    "answer": "いちがん",
    "meaning": "one eye, single lens (e.g. camera)"
  },
  {
    "question": "日暮",
    "answer": "ひぐれ",
    "meaning": "twilight, sunset, dusk, evening"
  },
  {
    "question": "雑木",
    "answer": "ぞうき,ざつぼく,ぞうぼく",
    "meaning": "various kinds of small trees, assorted trees"
  },
  {
    "question": "獣脂",
    "answer": "じゅうし",
    "meaning": "tallow"
  },
  {
    "question": "地勢",
    "answer": "ちせい",
    "meaning": "topography"
  },
  {
    "question": "賞罰",
    "answer": "しょうばつ",
    "meaning": "reward and punishment"
  },
  {
    "question": "凜然",
    "answer": "りんぜん",
    "meaning": "commanding, awe-inspiring"
  },
  {
    "question": "送検",
    "answer": "そうけん",
    "meaning": "sending the person accused to the prosecutor"
  },
  {
    "question": "祭神",
    "answer": "さいじん,さいしん",
    "meaning": "enshrined deity"
  },
  {
    "question": "臨床試験",
    "answer": "りんしょうしけん",
    "meaning": "clinical study, clinical trial"
  },
  {
    "question": "森閑",
    "answer": "しんかん",
    "meaning": "silent, still, quiet, hushed"
  },
  {
    "question": "糾合",
    "answer": "きゅうごう",
    "meaning": "rally, muster"
  },
  {
    "question": "減税",
    "answer": "げんぜい",
    "meaning": "tax reduction"
  },
  {
    "question": "憫笑",
    "answer": "びんしょう",
    "meaning": "smiling with pity"
  },
  {
    "question": "仮契約",
    "answer": "かりけいやく",
    "meaning": "provisional contract"
  },
  {
    "question": "曙",
    "answer": "あけぼの",
    "meaning": "dawn, daybreak, beginning"
  },
  {
    "question": "扁平",
    "answer": "へんぺい",
    "meaning": "flatness"
  },
  {
    "question": "経文",
    "answer": "きょうもん",
    "meaning": "scriptural text, scriptures, sutras"
  },
  {
    "question": "西進",
    "answer": "せいしん",
    "meaning": "proceeding west"
  },
  {
    "question": "賛嘆",
    "answer": "さんたん",
    "meaning": "praise, extolment, extollment"
  },
  {
    "question": "売春婦",
    "answer": "ばいしゅんふ,ばいしゅんぷ",
    "meaning": "prostitute"
  },
  {
    "question": "二人称",
    "answer": "ににんしょう",
    "meaning": "second person"
  },
  {
    "question": "老朽",
    "answer": "ろうきゅう",
    "meaning": "decrepitude, senescence, superannuation"
  },
  {
    "question": "抑",
    "answer": "そもそも,そも",
    "meaning": "in the first place, to begin with, from the start, originally, ab initio, after all, anyway, actuall"
  },
  {
    "question": "祭り囃子",
    "answer": "まつりばやし",
    "meaning": "festival music"
  },
  {
    "question": "構文",
    "answer": "こうぶん",
    "meaning": "sentence structure, grammatical construction"
  },
  {
    "question": "法律家",
    "answer": "ほうりつか",
    "meaning": "lawyer, jurist"
  },
  {
    "question": "進化論",
    "answer": "しんかろん",
    "meaning": "evolutionary theory, theory of evolution"
  },
  {
    "question": "真ん丸い",
    "answer": "まんまるい",
    "meaning": "perfectly round, perfectly circular"
  },
  {
    "question": "近親婚",
    "answer": "きんしんこん",
    "meaning": "consanguineous marriage"
  },
  {
    "question": "絶縁状",
    "answer": "ぜつえんじょう",
    "meaning": "letter breaking off with someone, Dear John letter"
  },
  {
    "question": "不良債権",
    "answer": "ふりょうさいけん",
    "meaning": "bad debt, nonperforming loan"
  },
  {
    "question": "枯死",
    "answer": "こし",
    "meaning": "withering, dying"
  },
  {
    "question": "諾々",
    "answer": "だくだく",
    "meaning": "obediently, yes, yes!"
  },
  {
    "question": "偏狭",
    "answer": "へんきょう",
    "meaning": "narrow-mindedness, intolerance, illiberality, narrowness"
  },
  {
    "question": "口を切る",
    "answer": "くちをきる",
    "meaning": "to be the first to speak, to break the silence, to open something for the first time, to broach (e.g"
  },
  {
    "question": "各駅停車",
    "answer": "かくえきていしゃ",
    "meaning": "train that stops at every station, local train"
  },
  {
    "question": "赤地",
    "answer": "あかじ",
    "meaning": "red cloth, red background"
  },
  {
    "question": "何処ぞ",
    "answer": "どこぞ",
    "meaning": "somewhere (very vague), someplace (very vague)"
  },
  {
    "question": "誤動作",
    "answer": "ごどうさ",
    "meaning": "malfunction"
  },
  {
    "question": "適",
    "answer": "たまたま,たま",
    "meaning": "occasionally, once in a while, seldom, casually, unexpectedly, accidentally, by chance, occasional,"
  },
  {
    "question": "植え付け",
    "answer": "うえつけ",
    "meaning": "planting, planting out, transplanting"
  },
  {
    "question": "菊の花",
    "answer": "きくのはな",
    "meaning": "chrysanthemum"
  },
  {
    "question": "倍数",
    "answer": "ばいすう",
    "meaning": "multiple"
  },
  {
    "question": "総決算",
    "answer": "そうけっさん",
    "meaning": "complete financial statement, summing up, concluding"
  },
  {
    "question": "出典",
    "answer": "しゅってん",
    "meaning": "source (e.g. quotation), authority"
  },
  {
    "question": "事由",
    "answer": "じゆう",
    "meaning": "reason, cause"
  },
  {
    "question": "チラ見せ",
    "answer": "チラみせ",
    "meaning": "giving someone a peek (of cleavage, etc.)"
  },
  {
    "question": "継ぎ",
    "answer": "つぎ",
    "meaning": "patch, patching, join, joining, successor, heir"
  },
  {
    "question": "注ぎ口",
    "answer": "つぎくち,つぎぐち,そそぎぐち",
    "meaning": "spout"
  },
  {
    "question": "心を配る",
    "answer": "こころをくばる",
    "meaning": "to give attention"
  },
  {
    "question": "因数分解",
    "answer": "いんすうぶんかい",
    "meaning": "factorization, factorisation"
  },
  {
    "question": "歌謡曲",
    "answer": "かようきょく",
    "meaning": "kayōkyoku, form of Japanese popular music that developed during the Showa era, (Western) pop song"
  },
  {
    "question": "矢面",
    "answer": "やおもて",
    "meaning": "firing line, position where one is subject to questioning, criticism, etc., in front of a flying arr"
  },
  {
    "question": "聖上",
    "answer": "せいじょう",
    "meaning": "the Emperor, His Majesty the Emperor"
  },
  {
    "question": "音無し",
    "answer": "おとなし",
    "meaning": "silence, without sound"
  },
  {
    "question": "木簡",
    "answer": "もっかん,もくかん",
    "meaning": "narrow, long, and thin pieces of wood strung together that were used to write on in ancient times"
  },
  {
    "question": "永の",
    "answer": "ながの",
    "meaning": "long, eternal"
  },
  {
    "question": "扶桑",
    "answer": "ふそう",
    "meaning": "land east of China, Japan"
  },
  {
    "question": "副大臣",
    "answer": "ふくだいじん",
    "meaning": "vice minister"
  },
  {
    "question": "長久",
    "answer": "ちょうきゅう",
    "meaning": "permanence, perpetuity, Chōkyū era (1040.11.10-1044.11.24)"
  },
  {
    "question": "正餐",
    "answer": "せいさん",
    "meaning": "(Western-style) banquet, formal dinner"
  },
  {
    "question": "政庁",
    "answer": "せいちょう",
    "meaning": "government office"
  },
  {
    "question": "大夫",
    "answer": "たゆう,だいぶ,たいふ",
    "meaning": "high-ranking noh actor, head of a school of noh performance, high ranking courtesan (esp. in Yoshiwa"
  },
  {
    "question": "和議",
    "answer": "わぎ",
    "meaning": "peace conference, peace negotiations"
  },
  {
    "question": "書記長",
    "answer": "しょきちょう",
    "meaning": "secretary general, chief secretary"
  },
  {
    "question": "吾が",
    "answer": "わが",
    "meaning": "my, our, one's own"
  },
  {
    "question": "隕鉄",
    "answer": "いんてつ",
    "meaning": "meteoric iron"
  },
  {
    "question": "刀工",
    "answer": "とうこう",
    "meaning": "swordsmith, swordmaker"
  },
  {
    "question": "門松",
    "answer": "かどまつ",
    "meaning": "New Year's pine decoration"
  },
  {
    "question": "本宮",
    "answer": "ほんぐう,もとみや",
    "meaning": "main shrine"
  },
  {
    "question": "山男",
    "answer": "やまおとこ",
    "meaning": "giant, woodsman, alpinist"
  },
  {
    "question": "中日",
    "answer": "ちゅうにち,なかび",
    "meaning": "China and Japan, the middle day, the equinoctial day, middle day (e.g. sumo tournament, run of theat"
  },
  {
    "question": "入山",
    "answer": "にゅうざん",
    "meaning": "entering a mountain area (for climbing), entering a monastery, coming to live in a temple"
  },
  {
    "question": "南進",
    "answer": "なんしん",
    "meaning": "proceeding south"
  },
  {
    "question": "薫製",
    "answer": "くんせい",
    "meaning": "smoked food, smoking (fish, meat, etc.), smoked"
  },
  {
    "question": "草笛",
    "answer": "くさぶえ",
    "meaning": "reed pipe"
  },
  {
    "question": "非表示",
    "answer": "ひひょうじ",
    "meaning": "hidden, non-display, to hide (window, etc.)"
  },
  {
    "question": "抵抗運動",
    "answer": "ていこううんどう",
    "meaning": "resistance movement"
  },
  {
    "question": "変声",
    "answer": "へんせい",
    "meaning": "voice change, voice break"
  },
  {
    "question": "応報",
    "answer": "おうほう",
    "meaning": "retribution"
  },
  {
    "question": "口内炎",
    "answer": "こうないえん",
    "meaning": "mouth ulcer, stomatitis"
  },
  {
    "question": "甚い",
    "answer": "いたい",
    "meaning": "painful, sore, cringy, embarrassing, exceeding"
  },
  {
    "question": "休部",
    "answer": "きゅうぶ",
    "meaning": "club that has suspended its activities, not attending one's club"
  },
  {
    "question": "下巻",
    "answer": "げかん",
    "meaning": "last volume (in set)"
  },
  {
    "question": "紐付き",
    "answer": "ひもつき",
    "meaning": "having strings attached (of a loan, etc.), having conditions attached, having restrictions attached,"
  },
  {
    "question": "胃壁",
    "answer": "いへき",
    "meaning": "stomach lining, gastric wall"
  },
  {
    "question": "中抜き",
    "answer": "なかぬき",
    "meaning": "outlined, lacking content, getting rid of the middleman"
  },
  {
    "question": "板壁",
    "answer": "いたかべ",
    "meaning": "wooden wall"
  },
  {
    "question": "古道具屋",
    "answer": "ふるどうぐや",
    "meaning": "secondhand store"
  },
  {
    "question": "穴熊",
    "answer": "あなぐま,あなくま",
    "meaning": "badger, Eurasian badger (Meles meles), defensive opening for shogi"
  },
  {
    "question": "乾麺",
    "answer": "かんめん",
    "meaning": "dried noodles"
  },
  {
    "question": "通し番号",
    "answer": "とおしばんごう",
    "meaning": "serial number, consecutive number"
  },
  {
    "question": "腑分け",
    "answer": "ふわけ",
    "meaning": "dissection, autopsy"
  },
  {
    "question": "婚家",
    "answer": "こんか",
    "meaning": "one's in-laws (esp. a woman's in-laws)"
  },
  {
    "question": "基地局",
    "answer": "きちきょく",
    "meaning": "base station"
  },
  {
    "question": "草臥れる",
    "answer": "くたびれる",
    "meaning": "to get tired, to become exhausted, to grow weary, to become worn out, to become battered (from long"
  },
  {
    "question": "亡びる",
    "answer": "ほろびる",
    "meaning": "to go to ruin, to go under, to fall, to be destroyed, to die out, to become extinct, to perish"
  },
  {
    "question": "克己心",
    "answer": "こっきしん",
    "meaning": "spirit of self-denial"
  },
  {
    "question": "庭石",
    "answer": "にわいし",
    "meaning": "garden stone"
  },
  {
    "question": "紡績",
    "answer": "ぼうせき",
    "meaning": "spinning (textiles), spun yarn"
  },
  {
    "question": "捻くれ者",
    "answer": "ひねくれもの",
    "meaning": "contrary person, sourpuss, dog-in-the-manger"
  },
  {
    "question": "別称",
    "answer": "べっしょう",
    "meaning": "alias, pseudonym, pen name, nom de plume"
  },
  {
    "question": "夕風",
    "answer": "ゆうかぜ",
    "meaning": "evening breeze"
  },
  {
    "question": "横隊",
    "answer": "おうたい",
    "meaning": "rank, line"
  },
  {
    "question": "満潮",
    "answer": "まんちょう,みちしお",
    "meaning": "high tide, high water, full tide"
  },
  {
    "question": "役名",
    "answer": "やくめい",
    "meaning": "official title"
  },
  {
    "question": "内示",
    "answer": "ないじ,ないし",
    "meaning": "unofficial announcement"
  },
  {
    "question": "手の物",
    "answer": "てのもの",
    "meaning": "one's own thing, thing held in one's hand(s), one's speciality, one's forte, one's strong point"
  },
  {
    "question": "好天",
    "answer": "こうてん",
    "meaning": "fine weather"
  },
  {
    "question": "漂わす",
    "answer": "ただよわす",
    "meaning": "to set adrift, to let loose, to cut loose"
  },
  {
    "question": "指差し",
    "answer": "ゆびさし,ゆびざし",
    "meaning": "pointing at"
  },
  {
    "question": "絶不調",
    "answer": "ぜつふちょう,ぜっふちょう",
    "meaning": "very bad condition, (in) terrible form, serious slump"
  },
  {
    "question": "読了",
    "answer": "どくりょう",
    "meaning": "finishing reading"
  },
  {
    "question": "昇給",
    "answer": "しょうきゅう",
    "meaning": "salary raise"
  },
  {
    "question": "遊覧飛行",
    "answer": "ゆうらんひこう",
    "meaning": "sightseeing flight"
  },
  {
    "question": "寄り合う",
    "answer": "よりあう",
    "meaning": "to gather, to meet"
  },
  {
    "question": "訓戒",
    "answer": "くんかい",
    "meaning": "warning, admonition, lesson or a phrase that teaches you not to do something"
  },
  {
    "question": "肝が太い",
    "answer": "きもがふとい",
    "meaning": "bold, daring, unflappable"
  },
  {
    "question": "一目散",
    "answer": "いちもくさん",
    "meaning": "running at full speed, going as fast as one can go"
  },
  {
    "question": "私掠船",
    "answer": "しりゃくせん",
    "meaning": "privateer, corsair"
  },
  {
    "question": "東宮",
    "answer": "とうぐう",
    "meaning": "crown prince"
  },
  {
    "question": "空売り",
    "answer": "からうり",
    "meaning": "short selling"
  },
  {
    "question": "公司",
    "answer": "こうし,コンス",
    "meaning": "company, firm (in China)"
  },
  {
    "question": "星影",
    "answer": "ほしかげ",
    "meaning": "starlight"
  },
  {
    "question": "浅葱色",
    "answer": "あさぎいろ",
    "meaning": "pale blue-green"
  },
  {
    "question": "近衛師団",
    "answer": "このえしだん",
    "meaning": "Imperial Guard Division (pre-1945)"
  },
  {
    "question": "毘沙門天",
    "answer": "びしゃもんてん",
    "meaning": "Vaisravana (guardian god of Buddhism)"
  },
  {
    "question": "襟巻",
    "answer": "えりまき",
    "meaning": "muffler (often fur), scarf, comforter"
  },
  {
    "question": "島根",
    "answer": "しまね",
    "meaning": "Shimane (city, prefecture), island country"
  },
  {
    "question": "膏",
    "answer": "あぶら",
    "meaning": "fat, tallow, lard, grease"
  },
  {
    "question": "皮革",
    "answer": "ひかく",
    "meaning": "leather, hide"
  },
  {
    "question": "霊長",
    "answer": "れいちょう",
    "meaning": "crown (of creation), apex, the best"
  },
  {
    "question": "人頭税",
    "answer": "じんとうぜい,にんとうぜい",
    "meaning": "poll tax"
  },
  {
    "question": "中央政府",
    "answer": "ちゅうおうせいふ",
    "meaning": "central government"
  },
  {
    "question": "集英",
    "answer": "しゅうえい",
    "meaning": "gathering of talented people, group of geniuses"
  },
  {
    "question": "文人",
    "answer": "ぶんじん,ふみびと",
    "meaning": "person of letters, literary person, poet"
  },
  {
    "question": "培養液",
    "answer": "ばいようえき",
    "meaning": "culture fluid, culture solution, broth"
  },
  {
    "question": "軽機関銃",
    "answer": "けいきかんじゅう",
    "meaning": "light machine gun"
  },
  {
    "question": "従容",
    "answer": "しょうよう",
    "meaning": "calm, composed, tranquil"
  },
  {
    "question": "打電",
    "answer": "だでん",
    "meaning": "sending a telegram, telegraph"
  },
  {
    "question": "位牌",
    "answer": "いはい",
    "meaning": "Buddhist mortuary tablet"
  },
  {
    "question": "砂礫",
    "answer": "されき",
    "meaning": "pebbles"
  },
  {
    "question": "一周年",
    "answer": "いっしゅうねん",
    "meaning": "one full year"
  },
  {
    "question": "専従",
    "answer": "せんじゅう",
    "meaning": "working exclusively for, working full-time (for)"
  },
  {
    "question": "桜貝",
    "answer": "さくらがい",
    "meaning": "Nitidotellina nitidula (species of tellin)"
  },
  {
    "question": "牛馬",
    "answer": "ぎゅうば",
    "meaning": "horses and cattle"
  },
  {
    "question": "球拾い",
    "answer": "たまひろい",
    "meaning": "fetching balls (tennis, baseball, etc.), ball boy"
  },
  {
    "question": "踊り手",
    "answer": "おどりて",
    "meaning": "dancer"
  },
  {
    "question": "煮豆",
    "answer": "にまめ",
    "meaning": "cooked beans"
  },
  {
    "question": "賑々しい",
    "answer": "にぎにぎしい",
    "meaning": "lively, merry, gay"
  },
  {
    "question": "約する",
    "answer": "やくする",
    "meaning": "to promise, to abridge, to simplify, to shorten, to reduce"
  },
  {
    "question": "専用回線",
    "answer": "せんようかいせん",
    "meaning": "leased line, private circuit, private line"
  },
  {
    "question": "糊塗",
    "answer": "こと",
    "meaning": "patching up (e.g. a failure), covering up (e.g. a mistake), glossing over"
  },
  {
    "question": "衣料",
    "answer": "いりょう",
    "meaning": "clothing"
  },
  {
    "question": "諍う",
    "answer": "いさかう,あらがう",
    "meaning": "to quarrel, to dispute, to go against, to fight against, to oppose, to resist, to deny"
  },
  {
    "question": "通常兵器",
    "answer": "つうじょうへいき",
    "meaning": "conventional weapon"
  },
  {
    "question": "市政",
    "answer": "しせい",
    "meaning": "municipal government"
  },
  {
    "question": "国を売る",
    "answer": "くにをうる",
    "meaning": "to betray one's country (to an enemy)"
  },
  {
    "question": "得票",
    "answer": "とくひょう",
    "meaning": "number of votes polled, poll votes"
  },
  {
    "question": "投げ遣り",
    "answer": "なげやり",
    "meaning": "negligent, careless, slipshod, slovenly, reckless, irresponsible, offhand"
  },
  {
    "question": "日系",
    "answer": "にっけい",
    "meaning": "(of) Japanese descent, non-Japanese of Japanese descent, nikkeijin, company, etc. set up with Japane"
  },
  {
    "question": "安定剤",
    "answer": "あんていざい",
    "meaning": "stabilizer"
  },
  {
    "question": "今時分",
    "answer": "いまじぶん",
    "meaning": "about this time"
  },
  {
    "question": "年度末",
    "answer": "ねんどまつ",
    "meaning": "end of the fiscal year, end of the school year"
  },
  {
    "question": "帯域",
    "answer": "たいいき",
    "meaning": "band, zone, range, bandwidth"
  },
  {
    "question": "連写",
    "answer": "れんしゃ",
    "meaning": "continuous shooting (photography), consecutive shooting, rapid shooting"
  },
  {
    "question": "追い追い",
    "answer": "おいおい",
    "meaning": "gradually, by degrees, little by little, step by step"
  },
  {
    "question": "浸入",
    "answer": "しんにゅう",
    "meaning": "infiltration (e.g. of water), flooding"
  },
  {
    "question": "多国籍",
    "answer": "たこくせき",
    "meaning": "multinational, transnational"
  },
  {
    "question": "公用",
    "answer": "こうよう",
    "meaning": "official business, government business, public business, company duties, public use, government use"
  },
  {
    "question": "終演",
    "answer": "しゅうえん",
    "meaning": "end of a performance"
  },
  {
    "question": "安全弁",
    "answer": "あんぜんべん",
    "meaning": "safety valve"
  },
  {
    "question": "体温調節",
    "answer": "たいおんちょうせつ",
    "meaning": "thermoregulation (of the body)"
  },
  {
    "question": "自薦",
    "answer": "じせん",
    "meaning": "self-recommendation"
  },
  {
    "question": "本家本元",
    "answer": "ほんけほんもと",
    "meaning": "original home, birthplace, originator"
  },
  {
    "question": "空論",
    "answer": "くうろん",
    "meaning": "abstract or impracticable theory"
  },
  {
    "question": "不快指数",
    "answer": "ふかいしすう",
    "meaning": "discomfort index, temperature-humidity index"
  },
  {
    "question": "茅場",
    "answer": "かやば",
    "meaning": "hayfield, field of miscanthus"
  },
  {
    "question": "世界政府",
    "answer": "せかいせいふ",
    "meaning": "world government"
  },
  {
    "question": "闇黒",
    "answer": "あんこく",
    "meaning": "darkness"
  },
  {
    "question": "樹冠",
    "answer": "じゅかん",
    "meaning": "tree canopy, tree crown"
  },
  {
    "question": "陰裂",
    "answer": "いんれつ",
    "meaning": "pudendal cleft, rima pudendi"
  },
  {
    "question": "裏サイト",
    "answer": "うらサイト",
    "meaning": "underground website (often critical or containing unofficial information)"
  },
  {
    "question": "安打",
    "answer": "あんだ",
    "meaning": "safe hit"
  },
  {
    "question": "雑技",
    "answer": "ざつぎ",
    "meaning": "performing arts, acrobatics"
  },
  {
    "question": "遊牧",
    "answer": "ゆうぼく",
    "meaning": "nomadism"
  },
  {
    "question": "八岐大蛇",
    "answer": "やまたのおろち",
    "meaning": "eight-headed, eight-tailed serpent (in Japanese mythology)"
  },
  {
    "question": "踞る",
    "answer": "うずくまる",
    "meaning": "to crouch, to squat, to cower"
  },
  {
    "question": "椰子",
    "answer": "やし",
    "meaning": "palm tree (any tree of family Arecaceae)"
  },
  {
    "question": "焦熱",
    "answer": "しょうねつ",
    "meaning": "scorching heat"
  },
  {
    "question": "独眼",
    "answer": "どくがん",
    "meaning": "one-eyed"
  },
  {
    "question": "軍法",
    "answer": "ぐんぽう",
    "meaning": "military law, martial law, tactics, strategy"
  },
  {
    "question": "史学",
    "answer": "しがく",
    "meaning": "study of history"
  },
  {
    "question": "値下がり",
    "answer": "ねさがり",
    "meaning": "price decline, fall in price"
  },
  {
    "question": "球種",
    "answer": "きゅうしゅ",
    "meaning": "type of pitch"
  },
  {
    "question": "懐紙",
    "answer": "かいし,ふところがみ",
    "meaning": "paper folded and tucked inside the front of one's kimono (esp. for use at the tea ceremony), paper u"
  },
  {
    "question": "円舞",
    "answer": "えんぶ",
    "meaning": "waltz"
  },
  {
    "question": "筒先",
    "answer": "つつさき",
    "meaning": "nozzle, muzzle, gunpoint"
  },
  {
    "question": "立川",
    "answer": "",
    "meaning": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "裸婦",
    "answer": "らふ",
    "meaning": "nude woman, naked woman"
  },
  {
    "question": "清清しい",
    "answer": "すがすがしい",
    "meaning": "refreshing (e.g. feeling, scene, wind, morning air), brisk, bracing, fresh, refreshed"
  },
  {
    "question": "気不味い",
    "answer": "きまずい",
    "meaning": "unpleasant, awkward, embarrassing, uneasy"
  },
  {
    "question": "水晶体",
    "answer": "すいしょうたい",
    "meaning": "the crystalline lens (of the eye)"
  },
  {
    "question": "地水火風",
    "answer": "ちすいかふう,じすいかふう",
    "meaning": "earth, water, fire, and wind (the four elements)"
  },
  {
    "question": "遅参",
    "answer": "ちさん",
    "meaning": "late attendance, lateness, tardiness"
  },
  {
    "question": "昨夕",
    "answer": "さくゆう",
    "meaning": "yesterday evening, last night"
  },
  {
    "question": "見積書",
    "answer": "みつもりしょ",
    "meaning": "written estimate, quotation, quote"
  },
  {
    "question": "後述",
    "answer": "こうじゅつ",
    "meaning": "mentioning later, discussing below"
  },
  {
    "question": "取立て",
    "answer": "とりたて",
    "meaning": "collection (e.g. of a debt), dunning, selection (for a position), exceptional promotion, patronage,"
  },
  {
    "question": "人事不省",
    "answer": "じんじふせい",
    "meaning": "unconsciousness"
  },
  {
    "question": "堅持",
    "answer": "けんじ",
    "meaning": "holding on to, sticking to"
  },
  {
    "question": "永らく",
    "answer": "ながらく",
    "meaning": "long, (for a) long time"
  },
  {
    "question": "ミルク色",
    "answer": "ミルクいろ",
    "meaning": "milk-white, milky"
  },
  {
    "question": "中破",
    "answer": "ちゅうは",
    "meaning": "half damage"
  },
  {
    "question": "主体的",
    "answer": "しゅたいてき",
    "meaning": "independent, responsible, active, proactive, subjective"
  },
  {
    "question": "顰め面",
    "answer": "しかめづら,しかめつら",
    "meaning": "frown, scowl, grimace"
  },
  {
    "question": "払暁",
    "answer": "ふつぎょう",
    "meaning": "dawn, daybreak"
  },
  {
    "question": "高見",
    "answer": "たかみ,こうけん",
    "meaning": "height, elevated place, your views, your opinion, great idea, excellent idea"
  },
  {
    "question": "機械工学",
    "answer": "きかいこうがく",
    "meaning": "mechanical engineering"
  },
  {
    "question": "合理化",
    "answer": "ごうりか",
    "meaning": "rationalization, rationalisation, rationalize, rationalise"
  },
  {
    "question": "音信",
    "answer": "おんしん,いんしん",
    "meaning": "correspondence, news, letter, tidings"
  },
  {
    "question": "和式",
    "answer": "わしき",
    "meaning": "Japanese-style (esp. in reference to squat toilets)"
  },
  {
    "question": "払い下げ",
    "answer": "はらいさげ",
    "meaning": "disposal (usu. of unwanted government assets), sale"
  },
  {
    "question": "横棒",
    "answer": "よこぼう",
    "meaning": "bar set in a horizontal position, horizontal bar"
  },
  {
    "question": "冷や",
    "answer": "ひや",
    "meaning": "cold water, cold sake, cold, cool, chilled, unheated"
  },
  {
    "question": "思想家",
    "answer": "しそうか",
    "meaning": "thinker"
  },
  {
    "question": "煮立てる",
    "answer": "にたてる",
    "meaning": "to boil or simmer"
  },
  {
    "question": "十月十日",
    "answer": "とつきとおか",
    "meaning": "babies born on October 10, supposedly conceived on New Year's Day, normal gestation time (i.e. 9 mon"
  },
  {
    "question": "合議制",
    "answer": "ごうぎせい",
    "meaning": "parliamentary system"
  },
  {
    "question": "槍投げ",
    "answer": "やりなげ",
    "meaning": "javelin (throw)"
  },
  {
    "question": "男っ気",
    "answer": "おとこっけ",
    "meaning": "male presence"
  },
  {
    "question": "責任能力",
    "answer": "せきにんのうりょく",
    "meaning": "legal competency, criminal responsibility, ability to fulfil one's responsibilities, full accountabi"
  },
  {
    "question": "略語",
    "answer": "りゃくご",
    "meaning": "abbreviation, acronym"
  },
  {
    "question": "白杖",
    "answer": "はくじょう",
    "meaning": "white cane (for the blind or visually impaired)"
  },
  {
    "question": "鵜飼",
    "answer": "うかい,うがい",
    "meaning": "cormorant fishing, cormorant fisherman"
  },
  {
    "question": "南朝",
    "answer": "なんちょう",
    "meaning": "Southern Dynasty"
  },
  {
    "question": "蝗害",
    "answer": "こうがい",
    "meaning": "locust plague, damage to crops by grasshoppers"
  },
  {
    "question": "霊威",
    "answer": "れいい",
    "meaning": "mysterious power"
  },
  {
    "question": "光背",
    "answer": "こうはい",
    "meaning": "halo"
  },
  {
    "question": "急迫",
    "answer": "きゅうはく",
    "meaning": "urgency, imminence"
  },
  {
    "question": "長虫",
    "answer": "ながむし",
    "meaning": "snake"
  },
  {
    "question": "朝敵",
    "answer": "ちょうてき",
    "meaning": "an enemy of the court, traitor"
  },
  {
    "question": "大公国",
    "answer": "たいこうこく",
    "meaning": "grand duchy"
  },
  {
    "question": "庄屋",
    "answer": "しょうや",
    "meaning": "village headman (esp. in the Kansai region)"
  },
  {
    "question": "行司",
    "answer": "ぎょうじ",
    "meaning": "referee (in sumo)"
  },
  {
    "question": "通信文",
    "answer": "つうしんぶん",
    "meaning": "message"
  },
  {
    "question": "交流試合",
    "answer": "こうりゅうじあい",
    "meaning": "interleague game, interleague match"
  },
  {
    "question": "鬩ぎ合い",
    "answer": "せめぎあい",
    "meaning": "conflict, fighting each other"
  },
  {
    "question": "石棺",
    "answer": "せっかん,せきかん",
    "meaning": "sarcophagus, stone coffin"
  },
  {
    "question": "薄荷",
    "answer": "はっか,はか",
    "meaning": "mint (e.g. peppermint, spearmint, etc.), Japanese peppermint (Mentha arvensis var. piperascens)"
  },
  {
    "question": "店子",
    "answer": "たなこ,たなご",
    "meaning": "tenant (esp. in contrast to a landlord), renter"
  },
  {
    "question": "半鐘",
    "answer": "はんしょう",
    "meaning": "fire alarm, fire bell"
  },
  {
    "question": "悲憤",
    "answer": "ひふん",
    "meaning": "indignation, resentment"
  },
  {
    "question": "親知らず",
    "answer": "おやしらず",
    "meaning": "wisdom tooth, not knowing who your parents are, person who doesn't know who their parents are"
  },
  {
    "question": "胡瓜",
    "answer": "きゅうり,きうり",
    "meaning": "cucumber (Cucumis sativus)"
  },
  {
    "question": "智将",
    "answer": "ちしょう",
    "meaning": "skilled manager, resourceful general"
  },
  {
    "question": "目付",
    "answer": "めつけ",
    "meaning": "censor, overseer, inspector (Edo period)"
  },
  {
    "question": "輪舞",
    "answer": "りんぶ",
    "meaning": "round dance, dancing in a circle"
  },
  {
    "question": "狂犬病",
    "answer": "きょうけんびょう",
    "meaning": "rabies, hydrophobia"
  },
  {
    "question": "乗り合い",
    "answer": "のりあい",
    "meaning": "riding together, fellow passenger, joint partnership"
  },
  {
    "question": "民法",
    "answer": "みんぽう",
    "meaning": "civil law, civil code"
  },
  {
    "question": "非国民",
    "answer": "ひこくみん",
    "meaning": "unpatriotic individual"
  },
  {
    "question": "初夢",
    "answer": "はつゆめ",
    "meaning": "first dream of the year"
  },
  {
    "question": "鑑定書",
    "answer": "かんていしょ",
    "meaning": "expert's written opinion or report"
  },
  {
    "question": "告示",
    "answer": "こくじ",
    "meaning": "notice, bulletin"
  },
  {
    "question": "独唱",
    "answer": "どくしょう",
    "meaning": "vocal solo"
  },
  {
    "question": "縦揺れ",
    "answer": "たてゆれ",
    "meaning": "vertical shaking (of an earthquake), pitching (of a boat, aircraft, etc.)"
  },
  {
    "question": "注水",
    "answer": "ちゅうすい",
    "meaning": "pouring water, flooding, douche"
  },
  {
    "question": "我が夫",
    "answer": "わがつま",
    "meaning": "my spouse (esp. used to refer to one's wife), my wife, my husband"
  },
  {
    "question": "陳述",
    "answer": "ちんじゅつ",
    "meaning": "statement, declaration"
  },
  {
    "question": "史跡",
    "answer": "しせき",
    "meaning": "historic landmark, historic site, historic remains"
  },
  {
    "question": "上巻",
    "answer": "じょうかん",
    "meaning": "first volume (in set), volume one, book one"
  },
  {
    "question": "早稲田",
    "answer": "わせだ,わさだ",
    "meaning": "field of early-blooming (or ripening) rice"
  },
  {
    "question": "粘り着く",
    "answer": "ねばりつく",
    "meaning": "to adhere to, to stick to, to cling to"
  },
  {
    "question": "巻き舌",
    "answer": "まきじた",
    "meaning": "speaking with a trill, rolling one's r's"
  },
  {
    "question": "名優",
    "answer": "めいゆう",
    "meaning": "great actor, famous actor, star"
  },
  {
    "question": "帰城",
    "answer": "きじょう",
    "meaning": "return to a castle"
  },
  {
    "question": "老境",
    "answer": "ろうきょう",
    "meaning": "old age"
  },
  {
    "question": "天然水",
    "answer": "てんねんすい",
    "meaning": "natural water, untreated water, spring water"
  },
  {
    "question": "新興国",
    "answer": "しんこうこく",
    "meaning": "emerging market, emerging nation, emergent nation, developing country, developing nation"
  },
  {
    "question": "死出",
    "answer": "しで",
    "meaning": "death (and entering the hereafter)"
  },
  {
    "question": "苦役",
    "answer": "くえき",
    "meaning": "toil, drudgery, penal servitude, imprisonment (with hard labour)"
  },
  {
    "question": "引き出物",
    "answer": "ひきでもの",
    "meaning": "gift, souvenir"
  },
  {
    "question": "底値",
    "answer": "そこね",
    "meaning": "bottom price"
  },
  {
    "question": "加工食品",
    "answer": "かこうしょくひん",
    "meaning": "processed food"
  },
  {
    "question": "労災",
    "answer": "ろうさい",
    "meaning": "work-related injury, work-related illness, work-related death, on-the-job accident, workers' compens"
  },
  {
    "question": "大名行列",
    "answer": "だいみょうぎょうれつ",
    "meaning": "daimyo's procession"
  },
  {
    "question": "利己主義",
    "answer": "りこしゅぎ",
    "meaning": "egoism, egotism, selfishness"
  },
  {
    "question": "革表紙",
    "answer": "かわびょうし",
    "meaning": "leather cover, leather binding"
  },
  {
    "question": "死の商人",
    "answer": "しのしょうにん",
    "meaning": "merchant of death, arms dealer"
  },
  {
    "question": "捕れる",
    "answer": "とれる",
    "meaning": "to be caught, to be captured, to be able to catch, to be able to capture"
  },
  {
    "question": "民間伝承",
    "answer": "みんかんでんしょう",
    "meaning": "folklore"
  },
  {
    "question": "多神教",
    "answer": "たしんきょう",
    "meaning": "polytheism"
  },
  {
    "question": "渡世",
    "answer": "とせい",
    "meaning": "livelihood, subsistence, business, trade, profession"
  },
  {
    "question": "反す",
    "answer": "かえす",
    "meaning": "to return (something), to restore, to put back, to turn over, to turn upside down, to overturn, to p"
  },
  {
    "question": "敷き布団",
    "answer": "しきぶとん",
    "meaning": "futon (laid on the floor), (Japanese) mattress, underquilt, sleeping mat"
  },
  {
    "question": "就学",
    "answer": "しゅうがく",
    "meaning": "entering school, school attendance"
  },
  {
    "question": "建て付け",
    "answer": "たてつけ",
    "meaning": "fitting (e.g. door, window), fit"
  },
  {
    "question": "一つ覚え",
    "answer": "ひとつおぼえ",
    "meaning": "the one thing that is well-remembered"
  },
  {
    "question": "実親",
    "answer": "じつおや",
    "meaning": "biological parent"
  },
  {
    "question": "津山",
    "answer": "",
    "meaning": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "感得",
    "answer": "かんとく",
    "meaning": "deep realization (realisation), profound realization, one's faith being transmitted to a deity and o"
  },
  {
    "question": "壁新聞",
    "answer": "かべしんぶん",
    "meaning": "wall newspaper, wall poster"
  },
  {
    "question": "方術",
    "answer": "ほうじゅつ",
    "meaning": "means, method, art, magic"
  },
  {
    "question": "電磁場",
    "answer": "でんじば",
    "meaning": "electromagnetic field"
  },
  {
    "question": "駕",
    "answer": "が",
    "meaning": "vehicle, horse-drawn carriage"
  },
  {
    "question": "轢き逃げ",
    "answer": "ひきにげ",
    "meaning": "hit-and-run (causing personal injury)"
  },
  {
    "question": "月餅",
    "answer": "げっぺい",
    "meaning": "mooncake, disc-shaped confection of wheat-flour dough filled with bean paste, usu. eaten during Autu"
  },
  {
    "question": "焼成",
    "answer": "しょうせい",
    "meaning": "firing (pottery)"
  },
  {
    "question": "山川",
    "answer": "さんせん,やまかわ,やまがわ",
    "meaning": "mountains and rivers, mountain river, mountain stream"
  },
  {
    "question": "恢復",
    "answer": "かいふく",
    "meaning": "restoration, rehabilitation, recovery, return, replevin, improvement, recovery (from an illness), re"
  },
  {
    "question": "共同浴場",
    "answer": "きょうどうよくじょう",
    "meaning": "public bath, communal bath, public bath or hot springs maintained by the local community and free or"
  },
  {
    "question": "司直",
    "answer": "しちょく",
    "meaning": "judge, judiciary, administration of justice, judicial authorities"
  },
  {
    "question": "馬主",
    "answer": "うまぬし,ばしゅ,ばぬし",
    "meaning": "owner of a horse (esp. racehorse), registered owner (of a racehorse)"
  },
  {
    "question": "耀く",
    "answer": "かがやく",
    "meaning": "to shine, to glitter, to sparkle"
  },
  {
    "question": "船腹",
    "answer": "せんぷく,ふなばら",
    "meaning": "side or bottom of a ship, ship's hold, bottoms, shipping, tonnage, freight space"
  },
  {
    "question": "目安箱",
    "answer": "めやすばこ",
    "meaning": "suggestion box, comment box, complaints box placed in front of the supreme court (Edo period)"
  },
  {
    "question": "嘆声",
    "answer": "たんせい",
    "meaning": "sigh (of admiration or lamentation)"
  },
  {
    "question": "文科省",
    "answer": "もんかしょう,ぶんかしょう",
    "meaning": "Ministry of Education, Culture, Sports, Science and Technology, MEXT"
  },
  {
    "question": "試料",
    "answer": "しりょう",
    "meaning": "sample, specimen, test piece"
  },
  {
    "question": "畦道",
    "answer": "あぜみち",
    "meaning": "(raised) footpath between rice fields, ridge between rice fields"
  },
  {
    "question": "阿婆擦れ",
    "answer": "あばずれ",
    "meaning": "bitch"
  },
  {
    "question": "捻じる",
    "answer": "ねじる",
    "meaning": "to screw, to twist, to distort, to parody, to make a pun, to torture, to wrest"
  },
  {
    "question": "饗応",
    "answer": "きょうおう",
    "meaning": "entertaining with food and drink, treating to dinner, wining and dining, immediately agreeing with s"
  },
  {
    "question": "成算",
    "answer": "せいさん",
    "meaning": "hope of success, prospects of success"
  },
  {
    "question": "笊",
    "answer": "ざる",
    "meaning": "draining basket (traditionally made of bamboo), colander, strainer, sieve, something full of holes,"
  },
  {
    "question": "青酸",
    "answer": "せいさん",
    "meaning": "hydrocyanic acid, prussic acid, hydrogen cyanide"
  },
  {
    "question": "糾す",
    "answer": "ただす",
    "meaning": "to ascertain, to confirm, to verify, to make sure of"
  },
  {
    "question": "戦国大名",
    "answer": "せんごくだいみょう",
    "meaning": "daimyo in the Warring States period"
  },
  {
    "question": "巨峰",
    "answer": "きょほう",
    "meaning": "gigantic peak, kyoho grape, large purple-black slip-skin grape variety, like Concord grapes"
  },
  {
    "question": "去就",
    "answer": "きょしゅう",
    "meaning": "leaving or staying, (one's) course of action, (one's) position, (one's) attitude"
  },
  {
    "question": "万年床",
    "answer": "まんねんどこ",
    "meaning": "bedding that is never put away during the day, permanently laid-out futon"
  },
  {
    "question": "五十音順",
    "answer": "ごじゅうおんじゅん",
    "meaning": "standard gojūon syllabary order (aiueo, etc.)"
  },
  {
    "question": "乳歯",
    "answer": "にゅうし",
    "meaning": "baby tooth, milk tooth, first set of teeth"
  },
  {
    "question": "原曲",
    "answer": "げんきょく",
    "meaning": "original song, original melody"
  },
  {
    "question": "内勤",
    "answer": "ないきん",
    "meaning": "office or indoor work"
  },
  {
    "question": "市場価値",
    "answer": "しじょうかち",
    "meaning": "market value"
  },
  {
    "question": "耕地",
    "answer": "こうち",
    "meaning": "arable land"
  },
  {
    "question": "豚小屋",
    "answer": "ぶたごや",
    "meaning": "pigsty"
  },
  {
    "question": "縄文時代",
    "answer": "じょうもんじだい",
    "meaning": "Jōmon period (ca. 14000-1000 BCE)"
  },
  {
    "question": "火達磨",
    "answer": "ひだるま",
    "meaning": "ball of flames, mass of flames, body covered with flames"
  },
  {
    "question": "移管",
    "answer": "いかん",
    "meaning": "transfer of control"
  },
  {
    "question": "損益",
    "answer": "そんえき",
    "meaning": "profit and loss, advantage and disadvantage"
  },
  {
    "question": "石器",
    "answer": "せっき",
    "meaning": "stone implement (e.g. stone age arrowheads), stone tool"
  },
  {
    "question": "車上",
    "answer": "しゃじょう",
    "meaning": "aboard a vehicle, in a car, on a train"
  },
  {
    "question": "決る",
    "answer": "きまる,しゃくる,さくる",
    "meaning": "to be decided, to be settled, to be fixed, to be arranged, to be unchanging, to be the same (as alwa"
  },
  {
    "question": "汲み出す",
    "answer": "くみだす",
    "meaning": "to bail out (water), to dip out, to ladle out, to scoop out, to pump out, to start drawing (water)"
  },
  {
    "question": "諸兄",
    "answer": "しょけい",
    "meaning": "dear friends, (all of) you or those men"
  },
  {
    "question": "貯える",
    "answer": "たくわえる",
    "meaning": "to store, to save up, to stock up on, to lay in stock, to set aside, to accumulate (e.g. knowledge),"
  },
  {
    "question": "係争",
    "answer": "けいそう",
    "meaning": "contention, dispute, conflict, controversy"
  },
  {
    "question": "心服",
    "answer": "しんぷく",
    "meaning": "admiration and devotion, hearty submission"
  },
  {
    "question": "微睡",
    "answer": "まどろみ,びすい",
    "meaning": "doze, nap, slumber"
  },
  {
    "question": "幼名",
    "answer": "ようめい,ようみょう,おさなな",
    "meaning": "childhood name"
  },
  {
    "question": "節足動物",
    "answer": "せっそくどうぶつ",
    "meaning": "arthropod"
  },
  {
    "question": "教育ママ",
    "answer": "きょういくママ",
    "meaning": "woman who is obsessed with the education of her children"
  },
  {
    "question": "圧迫面接",
    "answer": "あっぱくめんせつ",
    "meaning": "stress interview"
  },
  {
    "question": "屍山血河",
    "answer": "しざんけつが",
    "meaning": "heaps of bodies and streams of blood, fierce battle"
  },
  {
    "question": "前頭",
    "answer": "まえがしら",
    "meaning": "rank-and-file wrestlers in the highest division"
  },
  {
    "question": "丸文字",
    "answer": "まるもじ",
    "meaning": "rounded handwriting"
  },
  {
    "question": "浪費癖",
    "answer": "ろうひへき,ろうひぐせ",
    "meaning": "wasteful habits"
  },
  {
    "question": "年を食う",
    "answer": "としをくう",
    "meaning": "to grow older, to advance in age, to be very aged"
  },
  {
    "question": "下馬評",
    "answer": "げばひょう",
    "meaning": "rumor, rumour, gossip, speculation, irresponsible criticism, hearsay"
  },
  {
    "question": "漫談",
    "answer": "まんだん",
    "meaning": "chat, desultory conversation"
  },
  {
    "question": "燃え出す",
    "answer": "もえだす",
    "meaning": "to catch fire"
  },
  {
    "question": "惜別",
    "answer": "せきべつ",
    "meaning": "reluctance to part, sorrow at parting"
  },
  {
    "question": "逃れ",
    "answer": "のがれ",
    "meaning": "escaping, evading"
  },
  {
    "question": "一般大衆",
    "answer": "いっぱんたいしゅう",
    "meaning": "ordinary people, general public, public at large"
  },
  {
    "question": "当て込む",
    "answer": "あてこむ",
    "meaning": "to count on, to anticipate, to expect"
  },
  {
    "question": "商売柄",
    "answer": "しょうばいがら",
    "meaning": "nature of one's business, business instinct"
  },
  {
    "question": "顔を貸す",
    "answer": "かおをかす",
    "meaning": "to grant a person a moment"
  },
  {
    "question": "悠",
    "answer": "ゆう",
    "meaning": "quiet, calm, leisurely, distant, far off, boundless, endless"
  },
  {
    "question": "降服",
    "answer": "こうふく",
    "meaning": "capitulation, surrender, submission, yield"
  },
  {
    "question": "尾頭付き",
    "answer": "おかしらつき",
    "meaning": "fish served whole (complete with head and tail)"
  },
  {
    "question": "止水",
    "answer": "しすい",
    "meaning": "stagnant water, still water, water stopping"
  },
  {
    "question": "天堂",
    "answer": "てんどう",
    "meaning": "heaven, paradise"
  },
  {
    "question": "弓手",
    "answer": "ゆんで",
    "meaning": "one's left hand, bow hand"
  },
  {
    "question": "回生",
    "answer": "かいせい",
    "meaning": "resurrection, resuscitation, regeneration, university student in ... year"
  },
  {
    "question": "焼夷",
    "answer": "しょうい",
    "meaning": "burning (something) away, burning (something) down"
  },
  {
    "question": "韮",
    "answer": "にら,みら,かみら",
    "meaning": "Chinese chive, garlic chive (Allium tuberosum)"
  },
  {
    "question": "茣蓙",
    "answer": "ござ",
    "meaning": "rush mat, matting, mat"
  },
  {
    "question": "竜頭",
    "answer": "りゅうず",
    "meaning": "crown (of a watch), stem, cannon (of a bell)"
  },
  {
    "question": "咄",
    "answer": "はなし",
    "meaning": "topic, subject, rumor, talk, hearsay, tale, story, fable, circumstances, particulars"
  },
  {
    "question": "馬面",
    "answer": "うまづら,ばめん,うまがお",
    "meaning": "long thin face, Black Scraper (fish)"
  },
  {
    "question": "従卒",
    "answer": "じゅうそつ",
    "meaning": "orderly, underling"
  },
  {
    "question": "模造紙",
    "answer": "もぞうし",
    "meaning": "imitation Japanese vellum"
  },
  {
    "question": "転科",
    "answer": "てんか",
    "meaning": "changing one's academic course"
  },
  {
    "question": "発効",
    "answer": "はっこう",
    "meaning": "coming into effect"
  },
  {
    "question": "彼奴等",
    "answer": "あいつら",
    "meaning": "they"
  },
  {
    "question": "持久",
    "answer": "じきゅう",
    "meaning": "endurance, persistence"
  },
  {
    "question": "二子",
    "answer": "ふたご",
    "meaning": "twins, twin"
  },
  {
    "question": "阿吽",
    "answer": "あうん",
    "meaning": "Om, Aun, syllable representing the primordial trinity of Vishnu, Shiva and Brahma, inspiration and e"
  },
  {
    "question": "健忘",
    "answer": "けんぼう",
    "meaning": "forgetfulness"
  },
  {
    "question": "粉塵爆発",
    "answer": "ふんじんばくはつ",
    "meaning": "dust explosion"
  },
  {
    "question": "花売り",
    "answer": "はなうり",
    "meaning": "flower vendor"
  },
  {
    "question": "御案内",
    "answer": "ごあんない",
    "meaning": "acquaintance, knowledge"
  },
  {
    "question": "鉄板焼き",
    "answer": "てっぱんやき",
    "meaning": "teppanyaki (Japanese cooking prepared on a hot steel plate in the center of the table)"
  },
  {
    "question": "眉目",
    "answer": "びもく",
    "meaning": "face, looks, features"
  },
  {
    "question": "清酒",
    "answer": "せいしゅ",
    "meaning": "refined sake"
  },
  {
    "question": "置き引き",
    "answer": "おきびき",
    "meaning": "walking off with someone's bag, luggage theft, luggage thief"
  },
  {
    "question": "閣議",
    "answer": "かくぎ",
    "meaning": "cabinet meeting"
  },
  {
    "question": "中二階",
    "answer": "ちゅうにかい",
    "meaning": "mezzanine floor"
  },
  {
    "question": "過半",
    "answer": "かはん",
    "meaning": "the greater part"
  },
  {
    "question": "水遣り",
    "answer": "みずやり",
    "meaning": "watering (plants)"
  },
  {
    "question": "髭もじゃ",
    "answer": "ひげもじゃ",
    "meaning": "bearded"
  },
  {
    "question": "先遣",
    "answer": "せんけん",
    "meaning": "sending ahead"
  },
  {
    "question": "塩酸",
    "answer": "えんさん",
    "meaning": "hydrochloric acid"
  },
  {
    "question": "出廷",
    "answer": "しゅってい",
    "meaning": "appearance in court"
  },
  {
    "question": "理髪店",
    "answer": "りはつてん",
    "meaning": "barbershop, barber shop"
  },
  {
    "question": "青天井",
    "answer": "あおてんじょう",
    "meaning": "blue sky, skyrocketing (of prices), having no limit, the sky being the limit"
  },
  {
    "question": "和名",
    "answer": "わみょう,わめい",
    "meaning": "Japanese name (often of plants and animals, and written in kana)"
  },
  {
    "question": "とば口",
    "answer": "とばくち",
    "meaning": "entrance, threshold, beginning, first step, start"
  },
  {
    "question": "初婚",
    "answer": "しょこん",
    "meaning": "first marriage"
  },
  {
    "question": "調味",
    "answer": "ちょうみ",
    "meaning": "seasoning, flavoring, flavouring"
  },
  {
    "question": "パン食",
    "answer": "パンしょく",
    "meaning": "bread-centered diet (as opposed to rice)"
  },
  {
    "question": "誤植",
    "answer": "ごしょく",
    "meaning": "misprint, typographical error, typo"
  },
  {
    "question": "計算尽く",
    "answer": "けいさんずく,けいさんづく",
    "meaning": "calculated, premeditated, considered"
  },
  {
    "question": "食い切る",
    "answer": "くいきる",
    "meaning": "to bite through, to eat up, to consume entirely"
  },
  {
    "question": "顔芸",
    "answer": "かおげい",
    "meaning": "(skill of) making funny faces, facial performance"
  },
  {
    "question": "遡上",
    "answer": "そじょう",
    "meaning": "going upstream, swimming upstream"
  },
  {
    "question": "流線",
    "answer": "りゅうせん",
    "meaning": "flow line, streamline, lines representing the flow of a fluid"
  },
  {
    "question": "安んじる",
    "answer": "やすんじる",
    "meaning": "to be contented, to be at ease"
  },
  {
    "question": "恐悦",
    "answer": "きょうえつ",
    "meaning": "delight"
  },
  {
    "question": "末期的",
    "answer": "まっきてき",
    "meaning": "terminal, final"
  },
  {
    "question": "縦割り",
    "answer": "たてわり",
    "meaning": "dividing vertically, vertical split, top-to-bottom sectioning, division into sections, splitting len"
  },
  {
    "question": "再々",
    "answer": "さいさい",
    "meaning": "often, frequently"
  },
  {
    "question": "畢竟",
    "answer": "ひっきょう",
    "meaning": "after all"
  },
  {
    "question": "拾得物",
    "answer": "しゅうとくぶつ",
    "meaning": "found article"
  },
  {
    "question": "慢性",
    "answer": "まんせい",
    "meaning": "chronic (illness)"
  },
  {
    "question": "三日坊主",
    "answer": "みっかぼうず",
    "meaning": "person who cannot stick to anything, unsteady worker, monk for three days"
  },
  {
    "question": "絞殺す",
    "answer": "しめころす",
    "meaning": "to strangle to death"
  },
  {
    "question": "人物評",
    "answer": "じんぶつひょう",
    "meaning": "personal criticism, character sketch"
  },
  {
    "question": "雇い",
    "answer": "やとい",
    "meaning": "employee, employment"
  },
  {
    "question": "私大",
    "answer": "しだい",
    "meaning": "private university"
  },
  {
    "question": "大目",
    "answer": "おおめ",
    "meaning": "magnanimity, tolerance, large eyes"
  },
  {
    "question": "負け越す",
    "answer": "まけこす",
    "meaning": "to have more losses than wins"
  },
  {
    "question": "功罪",
    "answer": "こうざい",
    "meaning": "merits and demerits, good points and bad points, strengths and weaknesses"
  },
  {
    "question": "一風",
    "answer": "いっぷう",
    "meaning": "oddity, eccentricity, peculiarity"
  },
  {
    "question": "泣き所",
    "answer": "なきどころ",
    "meaning": "weak point, vulnerable point, Achilles' heel"
  },
  {
    "question": "万難",
    "answer": "ばんなん",
    "meaning": "many obstacles, innumerable difficulties"
  },
  {
    "question": "一季",
    "answer": "いっき,ひとき",
    "meaning": "one season, one year (esp. as an Edo-period duration of employment)"
  },
  {
    "question": "紅殻",
    "answer": "べにがら",
    "meaning": "red iron oxide, rouge"
  },
  {
    "question": "高砂",
    "answer": "たかさご",
    "meaning": "double-lined fusilier (Pterocaesio digramma), Taiwan (nickname), Takasago (classic noh play by Zeami"
  },
  {
    "question": "城代",
    "answer": "じょうだい",
    "meaning": "chamberlain, castle keeper"
  },
  {
    "question": "双子座",
    "answer": "ふたござ",
    "meaning": "Gemini (constellation), the Twins"
  },
  {
    "question": "糞虫",
    "answer": "くそむし,ふんちゅう",
    "meaning": "dung beetle, gold beetle, goldbug, scarab beetle, maggots in faeces (feces)"
  },
  {
    "question": "脱会",
    "answer": "だっかい",
    "meaning": "withdrawal (from membership of organization, organisation)"
  },
  {
    "question": "鉄火",
    "answer": "てっか",
    "meaning": "red-hot iron, gunfire, gambling, violent-tempered"
  },
  {
    "question": "立入",
    "answer": "たちいり",
    "meaning": "entering, going into"
  },
  {
    "question": "万博",
    "answer": "ばんぱく",
    "meaning": "world fair, international exposition"
  },
  {
    "question": "餐",
    "answer": "さん,ざん",
    "meaning": "dining"
  },
  {
    "question": "自動式",
    "answer": "じどうしき",
    "meaning": "automatic (e.g. door, gun, etc.)"
  },
  {
    "question": "キャラ弁",
    "answer": "キャラべん",
    "meaning": "homemade bento containing food decorated to look like cute characters (from anime, etc.)"
  },
  {
    "question": "交感",
    "answer": "こうかん",
    "meaning": "rapport, mutual sympathy"
  },
  {
    "question": "真空管",
    "answer": "しんくうかん",
    "meaning": "vacuum tube"
  },
  {
    "question": "養い親",
    "answer": "やしないおや",
    "meaning": "godparents, foster parents"
  },
  {
    "question": "防風林",
    "answer": "ぼうふうりん",
    "meaning": "windbreak (forest), shelterbelt"
  },
  {
    "question": "双生児",
    "answer": "そうせいじ",
    "meaning": "twins"
  },
  {
    "question": "山刀",
    "answer": "やまがたな",
    "meaning": "woodman's hatchet"
  },
  {
    "question": "空挺部隊",
    "answer": "くうていぶたい",
    "meaning": "airborne troops"
  },
  {
    "question": "神曲",
    "answer": "かみきょく",
    "meaning": "incredible song, great song"
  },
  {
    "question": "心の色",
    "answer": "こころのいろ",
    "meaning": "one's emotional state, one's mood, human interest, kindness, simple-heartedness"
  },
  {
    "question": "四股",
    "answer": "しこ",
    "meaning": "wrestler's ceremonial leg raising and stomping"
  },
  {
    "question": "サラ金",
    "answer": "サラきん",
    "meaning": "consumer financing firm, loan shark"
  },
  {
    "question": "学生運動",
    "answer": "がくせいうんどう",
    "meaning": "student movement"
  },
  {
    "question": "暗黒物質",
    "answer": "あんこくぶっしつ",
    "meaning": "dark matter"
  },
  {
    "question": "逸早く",
    "answer": "いちはやく",
    "meaning": "promptly, quickly, without delay, before others, first"
  },
  {
    "question": "国防総省",
    "answer": "こくぼうそうしょう",
    "meaning": "Department of Defense (U.S.), the Pentagon"
  },
  {
    "question": "日露戦争",
    "answer": "にちろせんそう",
    "meaning": "Russo-Japanese War (1904-5)"
  },
  {
    "question": "糸車",
    "answer": "いとぐるま",
    "meaning": "spinning wheel"
  },
  {
    "question": "生え出る",
    "answer": "はえでる",
    "meaning": "to sprout, to spring up, to come out"
  },
  {
    "question": "貨幣経済",
    "answer": "かへいけいざい",
    "meaning": "monetary economy"
  },
  {
    "question": "言上",
    "answer": "ごんじょう",
    "meaning": "telling, stating"
  },
  {
    "question": "投機",
    "answer": "とうき",
    "meaning": "speculation, venture, stockjobbing, gambling (on stocks)"
  },
  {
    "question": "取り舵",
    "answer": "とりかじ",
    "meaning": "port (side of a ship)"
  },
  {
    "question": "口舌",
    "answer": "くぜつ,こうぜつ",
    "meaning": "lovers' tiff, quarrel between lovers, chattering, idle talk, manner of speaking, way of speaking, in"
  },
  {
    "question": "絵付け",
    "answer": "えつけ",
    "meaning": "ceramics painting, porcelain painting, painting on china"
  },
  {
    "question": "諸事",
    "answer": "しょじ",
    "meaning": "various matters, everything"
  },
  {
    "question": "直撃弾",
    "answer": "ちょくげきだん",
    "meaning": "direct hit"
  },
  {
    "question": "を措いて",
    "answer": "をおいて",
    "meaning": "other than, excluding, without"
  },
  {
    "question": "洋間",
    "answer": "ようま",
    "meaning": "Western-style room"
  },
  {
    "question": "ビル風",
    "answer": "ビルかぜ",
    "meaning": "eddies of wind around high buildings"
  },
  {
    "question": "壮烈",
    "answer": "そうれつ",
    "meaning": "heroic, brave"
  },
  {
    "question": "職業意識",
    "answer": "しょくぎょういしき",
    "meaning": "professional sense"
  },
  {
    "question": "演ずる",
    "answer": "えんずる",
    "meaning": "to perform, to play"
  },
  {
    "question": "漉す",
    "answer": "こす",
    "meaning": "to filter, to strain"
  },
  {
    "question": "自動改札",
    "answer": "じどうかいさつ",
    "meaning": "automatic turnstile (ticket gate)"
  },
  {
    "question": "封じ込め",
    "answer": "ふうじこめ",
    "meaning": "containment"
  },
  {
    "question": "吹き出物",
    "answer": "ふきでもの",
    "meaning": "(skin) eruption, rash, pimple, spot, acne, boil"
  },
  {
    "question": "無感覚",
    "answer": "むかんかく",
    "meaning": "numb, impervious"
  },
  {
    "question": "勘所",
    "answer": "かんどころ",
    "meaning": "position on the fingerboard (of a shamisen, koto, etc.), vital point, crux"
  },
  {
    "question": "直列",
    "answer": "ちょくれつ",
    "meaning": "series (e.g. electrical), serial"
  },
  {
    "question": "零点",
    "answer": "れいてん",
    "meaning": "zero (points, marks), no marks, zero (of a function), root, zero degrees (Celsius), freezing point"
  },
  {
    "question": "盛夏",
    "answer": "せいか",
    "meaning": "midsummer, height of summer"
  },
  {
    "question": "掛け替え",
    "answer": "かけがえ,かけかえ",
    "meaning": "replacement, substitution, rebuilding, changing"
  },
  {
    "question": "有終の美",
    "answer": "ゆうしゅうのび",
    "meaning": "crowning glory (e.g. winning the last game of the season, creating a final spectacular art work)"
  },
  {
    "question": "今際",
    "answer": "いまわ",
    "meaning": "one's dying moment or hour"
  },
  {
    "question": "征する",
    "answer": "せいする",
    "meaning": "to conquer, to subjugate, to overcome"
  },
  {
    "question": "寒暖",
    "answer": "かんだん",
    "meaning": "cold and heat, (degree of) temperature"
  },
  {
    "question": "丁々発止",
    "answer": "ちょうちょうはっし",
    "meaning": "(sound) of clashing swords, (arguing) as fiercely as clashing and blocking swords"
  },
  {
    "question": "扶養",
    "answer": "ふよう",
    "meaning": "support (e.g. of one's dependents), maintenance"
  },
  {
    "question": "取り上げ",
    "answer": "とりあげ",
    "meaning": "adoption, acceptance, confiscation, midwifery, midwife"
  },
  {
    "question": "回し飲み",
    "answer": "まわしのみ",
    "meaning": "drinking in turn from one cup"
  },
  {
    "question": "歯触り",
    "answer": "はざわり",
    "meaning": "texture (e.g. chewiness, hardness, crispiness, crunchiness, etc.) of food"
  },
  {
    "question": "顰蹙",
    "answer": "ひんしゅく",
    "meaning": "frowning on, looking on with scorn, showing disapproval"
  },
  {
    "question": "甲乙",
    "answer": "こうおつ",
    "meaning": "first and second, A and B, superiority and (or) inferiority, distinction (in quality), discernment,"
  },
  {
    "question": "色落ち",
    "answer": "いろおち",
    "meaning": "colour loss (color)"
  },
  {
    "question": "心待ち",
    "answer": "こころまち",
    "meaning": "anticipation, expectation"
  },
  {
    "question": "牧童",
    "answer": "ぼくどう",
    "meaning": "cowboy, shepherd"
  },
  {
    "question": "富嶽",
    "answer": "ふがく",
    "meaning": "Mount Fuji, Mt. Fuji"
  },
  {
    "question": "蒼海",
    "answer": "そうかい",
    "meaning": "blue waters"
  },
  {
    "question": "主星",
    "answer": "しゅせい",
    "meaning": "primary star"
  },
  {
    "question": "志摩",
    "answer": "しま",
    "meaning": "Shima (former province located at the eastern tip of present-day Mie Prefecture)"
  },
  {
    "question": "共産党",
    "answer": "きょうさんとう",
    "meaning": "Communist Party"
  },
  {
    "question": "定時制",
    "answer": "ていじせい",
    "meaning": "part time (school system)"
  },
  {
    "question": "佐野",
    "answer": "",
    "meaning": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "屍骸",
    "answer": "しがい",
    "meaning": "(dead) body, corpse, carcass, remains"
  },
  {
    "question": "枡",
    "answer": "ます",
    "meaning": "measuring container, measure, box (seating at a theatre, etc.), square on a grid, cell of a grid"
  },
  {
    "question": "一天",
    "answer": "いってん",
    "meaning": "the whole sky, firmament"
  },
  {
    "question": "譜代",
    "answer": "ふだい",
    "meaning": "successive generations, hereditary daimyo (whose ancestors supported Tokugawa Ieyasu prior to the ba"
  },
  {
    "question": "頭陀袋",
    "answer": "ずだぶくろ,ずたぶくろ",
    "meaning": "sack, carry-all bag"
  },
  {
    "question": "伊吹",
    "answer": "いぶき",
    "meaning": "Chinese juniper (Juniperus chinensis)"
  },
  {
    "question": "天パ",
    "answer": "てんパ",
    "meaning": "naturally curly hair"
  },
  {
    "question": "常備軍",
    "answer": "じょうびぐん",
    "meaning": "standing army"
  },
  {
    "question": "送球",
    "answer": "そうきゅう",
    "meaning": "throwing a ball, handball"
  },
  {
    "question": "大学校",
    "answer": "だいがっこう",
    "meaning": "educational facility established in affiliation with a government agency"
  },
  {
    "question": "騎馬民族",
    "answer": "きばみんぞく",
    "meaning": "equestrian tribe, equestrian people"
  },
  {
    "question": "青玉",
    "answer": "せいぎょく",
    "meaning": "sapphire, jacinth"
  },
  {
    "question": "経済制裁",
    "answer": "けいざいせいさい",
    "meaning": "economic sanctions"
  },
  {
    "question": "発行所",
    "answer": "はっこうしょ,はっこうじょ",
    "meaning": "publishing house, publishing office"
  },
  {
    "question": "哨戒機",
    "answer": "しょうかいき",
    "meaning": "patrol plane"
  },
  {
    "question": "方形",
    "answer": "ほうけい",
    "meaning": "square"
  },
  {
    "question": "魚拓",
    "answer": "ぎょたく",
    "meaning": "fish print, snapshot of a web page (to preserve its contents)"
  },
  {
    "question": "振り翳す",
    "answer": "ふりかざす",
    "meaning": "to raise (esp. overhead), to brandish (e.g. sword), to flourish, to wield (e.g. power, authority), t"
  },
  {
    "question": "朝稽古",
    "answer": "あさげいこ",
    "meaning": "early-morning practice"
  },
  {
    "question": "法要",
    "answer": "ほうよう",
    "meaning": "Buddhist memorial service"
  },
  {
    "question": "南洋",
    "answer": "なんよう",
    "meaning": "South Seas"
  },
  {
    "question": "孫の手",
    "answer": "まごのて",
    "meaning": "backscratcher"
  },
  {
    "question": "薄毛",
    "answer": "うすげ",
    "meaning": "thinning hair, sparse hair (as in balding)"
  },
  {
    "question": "銘々",
    "answer": "めいめい",
    "meaning": "each, individual"
  },
  {
    "question": "回転椅子",
    "answer": "かいてんいす",
    "meaning": "swivel chair"
  },
  {
    "question": "手前味噌",
    "answer": "てまえみそ",
    "meaning": "self-flattery, sing one's own praises"
  },
  {
    "question": "警戒警報",
    "answer": "けいかいけいほう",
    "meaning": "preliminary alert (flood, typhoon, air-raid, etc.), precautionary warning"
  },
  {
    "question": "糺す",
    "answer": "ただす",
    "meaning": "to ascertain, to confirm, to verify, to make sure of"
  },
  {
    "question": "霊安室",
    "answer": "れいあんしつ",
    "meaning": "morgue, mortuary"
  },
  {
    "question": "話し手",
    "answer": "はなして",
    "meaning": "speaker, one who is skilled at speaking"
  },
  {
    "question": "請",
    "answer": "しょう",
    "meaning": "request, invitation, privilege in criminal law given to nobles of the fifth rank or above (ritsuryo"
  },
  {
    "question": "溶剤",
    "answer": "ようざい",
    "meaning": "solvent, solution, flux"
  },
  {
    "question": "習い性",
    "answer": "ならいしょう",
    "meaning": "ingrained habit, second nature"
  },
  {
    "question": "建築学",
    "answer": "けんちくがく",
    "meaning": "architecture"
  },
  {
    "question": "西北",
    "answer": "せいほく,にしきた",
    "meaning": "north-west"
  },
  {
    "question": "悶死",
    "answer": "もんし",
    "meaning": "death in agony"
  },
  {
    "question": "在庫管理",
    "answer": "ざいこかんり",
    "meaning": "inventory control"
  },
  {
    "question": "外圧",
    "answer": "がいあつ",
    "meaning": "external pressure, outside pressure, foreign pressure"
  },
  {
    "question": "若芽",
    "answer": "わかめ",
    "meaning": "sprouts, new shoots, young buds"
  },
  {
    "question": "退屈凌ぎ",
    "answer": "たいくつしのぎ",
    "meaning": "killing time, staving off boredom"
  },
  {
    "question": "潑剌",
    "answer": "はつらつ",
    "meaning": "lively, vigorous, sprightly, animated, vivid"
  },
  {
    "question": "国家機関",
    "answer": "こっかきかん",
    "meaning": "organs of the state, machinery of the state"
  },
  {
    "question": "宵越し",
    "answer": "よいごし",
    "meaning": "(kept) overnight"
  },
  {
    "question": "健啖",
    "answer": "けんたん",
    "meaning": "gluttony, voracity"
  },
  {
    "question": "北北東",
    "answer": "ほくほくとう",
    "meaning": "north-northeast, north-north-east"
  },
  {
    "question": "産湯",
    "answer": "うぶゆ",
    "meaning": "a baby's first bath"
  },
  {
    "question": "大飯",
    "answer": "おおめし",
    "meaning": "large meal, large meals"
  },
  {
    "question": "車高",
    "answer": "しゃこう",
    "meaning": "vehicle height"
  },
  {
    "question": "軽侮",
    "answer": "けいぶ",
    "meaning": "contempt, scorn"
  },
  {
    "question": "中休み",
    "answer": "なかやすみ",
    "meaning": "rest, recess"
  },
  {
    "question": "流言飛語",
    "answer": "りゅうげんひご",
    "meaning": "false rumour (rumor), groundless rumour, canard"
  },
  {
    "question": "催涙弾",
    "answer": "さいるいだん",
    "meaning": "tear-gas bomb"
  },
  {
    "question": "田舎臭い",
    "answer": "いなかくさい",
    "meaning": "rustic, unsophisticated, provincial, hick, cornball"
  },
  {
    "question": "人知れぬ",
    "answer": "ひとしれぬ",
    "meaning": "secret, hidden, unseen, inward"
  },
  {
    "question": "店前",
    "answer": "たなさき",
    "meaning": "storefront, front of a store"
  },
  {
    "question": "縮こめる",
    "answer": "ちぢこめる",
    "meaning": "to draw in (one's body), to duck (one's head)"
  },
  {
    "question": "読み違い",
    "answer": "よみちがい",
    "meaning": "misreading"
  },
  {
    "question": "諸悪",
    "answer": "しょあく",
    "meaning": "various evils, every kind of evil, all evils"
  },
  {
    "question": "方が付く",
    "answer": "かたがつく",
    "meaning": "to settle (a problem), to put an end to (a dispute), to be disposed of, to be settled, to come to an"
  },
  {
    "question": "内の人",
    "answer": "うちのひと",
    "meaning": "my husband, one's family, family member"
  },
  {
    "question": "白妙",
    "answer": "しろたえ,しらたえ",
    "meaning": "white cloth, white"
  },
  {
    "question": "化外",
    "answer": "けがい,かがい",
    "meaning": "benighted lands outside of imperial influence"
  },
  {
    "question": "里人",
    "answer": "さとびと,りじん",
    "meaning": "villager, village folk, countryfolk"
  },
  {
    "question": "軍国",
    "answer": "ぐんこく",
    "meaning": "nation at war, militant nation"
  },
  {
    "question": "殷",
    "answer": "いん",
    "meaning": "Shang dynasty (China, approx. 1600-1046 BCE), Yin dynasty"
  },
  {
    "question": "凶人",
    "answer": "きょうじん",
    "meaning": "scoundrel, ruffian, villain"
  },
  {
    "question": "妖花",
    "answer": "ようか",
    "meaning": "enchantingly beautiful flower, bewitching beauty"
  },
  {
    "question": "行政区",
    "answer": "ぎょうせいく",
    "meaning": "administrative district, ward"
  },
  {
    "question": "撥",
    "answer": "ばち",
    "meaning": "plectrum, pick, drumstick for Japanese drums (e.g. taiko)"
  },
  {
    "question": "訊問",
    "answer": "じんもん",
    "meaning": "questioning, interrogation, examination (of a witness)"
  },
  {
    "question": "経絡",
    "answer": "けいらく",
    "meaning": "meridian (e.g. in acupuncture), channel, one of the lines connecting vital points in the body, threa"
  },
  {
    "question": "障碍",
    "answer": "しょうがい,しょうげ",
    "meaning": "obstacle, impediment, hindrance, difficulty, barrier, handicap, impairment, disability, disorder, ma"
  },
  {
    "question": "帷",
    "answer": "とばり",
    "meaning": "curtain, hanging, bunting"
  },
  {
    "question": "政経",
    "answer": "せいけい",
    "meaning": "politics and economics"
  },
  {
    "question": "添乗員",
    "answer": "てんじょういん",
    "meaning": "tour conductor, tour guide"
  },
  {
    "question": "生協",
    "answer": "せいきょう",
    "meaning": "cooperative association, co-op store"
  },
  {
    "question": "筋肉組織",
    "answer": "きんにくそしき",
    "meaning": "muscle tissue"
  },
  {
    "question": "近畿",
    "answer": "きんき",
    "meaning": "Kinki (region around Osaka, Kyoto, Nara)"
  },
  {
    "question": "浸蝕",
    "answer": "しんしょく",
    "meaning": "erosion, corrosion"
  },
  {
    "question": "民心",
    "answer": "みんしん",
    "meaning": "popular sentiment"
  },
  {
    "question": "茫",
    "answer": "ぼう",
    "meaning": "extensive, spacious, vague, hazy"
  },
  {
    "question": "独演会",
    "answer": "どくえんかい",
    "meaning": "(holding of) a solo recital or performance"
  },
  {
    "question": "目張り",
    "answer": "めばり",
    "meaning": "weather strip, weather stripping, sealing up (a window), putting on eyeliner (in theatre)"
  },
  {
    "question": "真面",
    "answer": "まとも",
    "meaning": "the front, honesty, uprightness, directness, decency, normality"
  },
  {
    "question": "植物油",
    "answer": "しょくぶつゆ",
    "meaning": "vegetable oil"
  },
  {
    "question": "五角形",
    "answer": "ごかくけい,ごかっけい",
    "meaning": "pentagon"
  },
  {
    "question": "大業",
    "answer": "おおわざ,たいぎょう",
    "meaning": "bold move (in sumo, judo, etc.), daring move, powerful technique, great deed, great enterprise, grea"
  },
  {
    "question": "中継ぎ",
    "answer": "なかつぎ",
    "meaning": "joining, joint, intermediation, acting as an intermediary, relaying, taking over, middle relief pitc"
  },
  {
    "question": "焙る",
    "answer": "あぶる",
    "meaning": "to warm (e.g. one's hands over a fire), to dry, to toast, to grill, to broil, to roast, to scorch"
  },
  {
    "question": "記憶装置",
    "answer": "きおくそうち",
    "meaning": "storage (device), memory"
  },
  {
    "question": "生す",
    "answer": "むす,なす",
    "meaning": "to grow (of moss, etc.), to have a child"
  },
  {
    "question": "空費",
    "answer": "くうひ",
    "meaning": "waste, wastefulness"
  },
  {
    "question": "剛健",
    "answer": "ごうけん",
    "meaning": "vigour, vigor, virility, health, sturdiness"
  },
  {
    "question": "市議会",
    "answer": "しぎかい",
    "meaning": "city council"
  },
  {
    "question": "月齢",
    "answer": "げつれい",
    "meaning": "age of the Moon, number of days since the new moon, age in months (esp. of an infant)"
  },
  {
    "question": "荒天",
    "answer": "こうてん",
    "meaning": "stormy weather"
  },
  {
    "question": "紙テープ",
    "answer": "かみテープ",
    "meaning": "paper tape, paper streamer"
  },
  {
    "question": "バック転",
    "answer": "バックてん",
    "meaning": "backward somersault, back handspring, backflip"
  },
  {
    "question": "演算装置",
    "answer": "えんざんそうち",
    "meaning": "arithmetic unit"
  },
  {
    "question": "地滑り",
    "answer": "じすべり",
    "meaning": "landslide"
  },
  {
    "question": "社会現象",
    "answer": "しゃかいげんしょう",
    "meaning": "social phenomenon"
  },
  {
    "question": "小役人",
    "answer": "こやくにん",
    "meaning": "petty official"
  },
  {
    "question": "青竹",
    "answer": "あおだけ",
    "meaning": "green bamboo"
  },
  {
    "question": "楽隠居",
    "answer": "らくいんきょ",
    "meaning": "comfortable retirement"
  },
  {
    "question": "根治",
    "answer": "こんじ,こんち",
    "meaning": "complete cure, radical cure, complete recovery"
  },
  {
    "question": "功徳",
    "answer": "くどく",
    "meaning": "merit, virtuous deed, act of merit, act of charity, divine reward (for virtuous deeds), grace (of th"
  },
  {
    "question": "公職",
    "answer": "こうしょく",
    "meaning": "public office"
  },
  {
    "question": "形見分け",
    "answer": "かたみわけ",
    "meaning": "distribution of mementos"
  },
  {
    "question": "獣肉",
    "answer": "じゅうにく",
    "meaning": "animal flesh"
  },
  {
    "question": "哀惜",
    "answer": "あいせき",
    "meaning": "grief, sorrow"
  },
  {
    "question": "先鋭化",
    "answer": "せんえいか",
    "meaning": "radicalization, radicalisation, becoming a radical, intensification, aggravation, becoming acute, sh"
  },
  {
    "question": "実印",
    "answer": "じついん",
    "meaning": "officially registered seal"
  },
  {
    "question": "香典",
    "answer": "こうでん",
    "meaning": "gift brought to a funeral (usu. money), funeral offering, condolence gift, incense money"
  },
  {
    "question": "自己欺瞞",
    "answer": "じこぎまん",
    "meaning": "self-deception, self-deceit"
  },
  {
    "question": "真似っこ",
    "answer": "まねっこ",
    "meaning": "imitating, copying, mimicking"
  },
  {
    "question": "南南西",
    "answer": "なんなんせい",
    "meaning": "south-southwest, south-south-west"
  },
  {
    "question": "寸暇",
    "answer": "すんか",
    "meaning": "moment's leisure, free minute"
  },
  {
    "question": "式次第",
    "answer": "しきしだい",
    "meaning": "program of a ceremony (programme)"
  },
  {
    "question": "吝嗇",
    "answer": "りんしょく",
    "meaning": "stinginess, miser, miserliness, selfishness"
  },
  {
    "question": "切れっ端",
    "answer": "きれっぱし",
    "meaning": "scraps, cut end, cut-off piece"
  },
  {
    "question": "鼻骨",
    "answer": "びこつ",
    "meaning": "nasal bone"
  },
  {
    "question": "有名無実",
    "answer": "ゆうめいむじつ",
    "meaning": "in name but not in reality"
  },
  {
    "question": "中高年",
    "answer": "ちゅうこうねん",
    "meaning": "middle and old age"
  },
  {
    "question": "古色蒼然",
    "answer": "こしょくそうぜん",
    "meaning": "antique-looking, looking hoary with patina"
  },
  {
    "question": "分つ",
    "answer": "わかつ,あかつ",
    "meaning": "to divide, to separate, to share, to distribute, to distinguish"
  },
  {
    "question": "現実性",
    "answer": "げんじつせい",
    "meaning": "realistic, practical, feasible"
  },
  {
    "question": "保証付き",
    "answer": "ほしょうつき",
    "meaning": "guaranteed, certified, warranty included"
  },
  {
    "question": "吹き替え",
    "answer": "ふきかえ",
    "meaning": "dubbing, stand-in, dummy"
  },
  {
    "question": "誇大広告",
    "answer": "こだいこうこく",
    "meaning": "deceptive advertising, misleading advertisement (presenting one's product as being better or cheaper"
  },
  {
    "question": "転換炉",
    "answer": "てんかんろ",
    "meaning": "converter reactor"
  },
  {
    "question": "青石",
    "answer": "あおいし",
    "meaning": "bluish stone, greenish stone, blue-tinged tuff"
  },
  {
    "question": "入塾",
    "answer": "にゅうじゅく",
    "meaning": "entering a private school"
  },
  {
    "question": "関東軍",
    "answer": "かんとうぐん",
    "meaning": "Kwantung Army (Japanese armed forces in Manchukuo)"
  },
  {
    "question": "未到",
    "answer": "みとう",
    "meaning": "unreached, unattained, unachieved, unprecedented"
  },
  {
    "question": "擾乱",
    "answer": "じょうらん",
    "meaning": "disturbance"
  },
  {
    "question": "原生",
    "answer": "げんせい",
    "meaning": "primeval, primordial, primitive, pristine"
  },
  {
    "question": "要撃",
    "answer": "ようげき",
    "meaning": "ambush, interception, counter-attack"
  },
  {
    "question": "写し絵",
    "answer": "うつしえ",
    "meaning": "sketch (depicting real people or nature), drawing sketched from real life, magic-lantern picture, ch"
  },
  {
    "question": "アキバ系",
    "answer": "アキバけい",
    "meaning": "Akihabara style, nerdy"
  },
  {
    "question": "打線",
    "answer": "だせん",
    "meaning": "batting lineup (line-up)"
  },
  {
    "question": "兇",
    "answer": "きょう",
    "meaning": "evil, wickedness"
  },
  {
    "question": "県庁",
    "answer": "けんちょう",
    "meaning": "prefectural office"
  },
  {
    "question": "長城",
    "answer": "ちょうじょう",
    "meaning": "great wall (of China), long wall"
  },
  {
    "question": "原チャリ",
    "answer": "げんチャリ",
    "meaning": "motor scooter, moped, motorized bicycle"
  },
  {
    "question": "内裏",
    "answer": "だいり",
    "meaning": "imperial palace, festival dolls representing the emperor and the empress"
  },
  {
    "question": "侍大将",
    "answer": "さぶらいだいしょう,さむらいだいしょう",
    "meaning": "samurai general (esp. during the Sengoku period)"
  },
  {
    "question": "林間",
    "answer": "りんかん",
    "meaning": "in the forest"
  },
  {
    "question": "兵種",
    "answer": "へいしゅ",
    "meaning": "branch of an army"
  },
  {
    "question": "幻夢",
    "answer": "げんむ",
    "meaning": "dreams, visions, phantasms"
  },
  {
    "question": "専制君主",
    "answer": "せんせいくんしゅ",
    "meaning": "absolute monarch, despot, autocrat, tyrant"
  },
  {
    "question": "夜具",
    "answer": "やぐ",
    "meaning": "bedding, bedclothes"
  },
  {
    "question": "凍て付く",
    "answer": "いてつく",
    "meaning": "to freeze"
  },
  {
    "question": "氷片",
    "answer": "ひょうへん",
    "meaning": "ice shard, ice shards"
  },
  {
    "question": "玉鋼",
    "answer": "たまはがね",
    "meaning": "steel made from iron sand or black sand (used in sword blades)"
  },
  {
    "question": "天照大神",
    "answer": "あまてらすおおみかみ",
    "meaning": "Sun Goddess, Amaterasu Ōmikami"
  },
  {
    "question": "浪速",
    "answer": "なにわ",
    "meaning": "Naniwa (former name for Osaka region)"
  },
  {
    "question": "殺虫",
    "answer": "さっちゅう",
    "meaning": "killing insects or pests"
  },
  {
    "question": "撃発",
    "answer": "げきはつ",
    "meaning": "percussion (fuse)"
  },
  {
    "question": "隊伍",
    "answer": "たいご",
    "meaning": "rank (of troops), line, formation, array, procession"
  },
  {
    "question": "ト書き",
    "answer": "トがき",
    "meaning": "stage directions"
  },
  {
    "question": "世論調査",
    "answer": "よろんちょうさ,せろんちょうさ",
    "meaning": "public opinion poll"
  },
  {
    "question": "衆生",
    "answer": "しゅじょう,しゅうせい,すじょう",
    "meaning": "all living things, mankind, the people, the world"
  },
  {
    "question": "統廃合",
    "answer": "とうはいごう",
    "meaning": "reorganization (e.g. of a company), reorganisation, consolidation, scrap-and-build"
  },
  {
    "question": "夜歩き",
    "answer": "よあるき",
    "meaning": "walking around at night"
  },
  {
    "question": "密教",
    "answer": "みっきょう",
    "meaning": "esoteric Buddhism, Tantric Buddhism, Vajrayana, secret Buddhist teachings, Mikkyō"
  },
  {
    "question": "学芸員",
    "answer": "がくげいいん",
    "meaning": "curator (e.g. museum)"
  },
  {
    "question": "意識障害",
    "answer": "いしきしょうがい",
    "meaning": "disturbance of consciousness"
  },
  {
    "question": "遠洋",
    "answer": "えんよう",
    "meaning": "ocean, deep sea"
  },
  {
    "question": "眩惑",
    "answer": "げんわく",
    "meaning": "dazzling, blinding"
  },
  {
    "question": "受託",
    "answer": "じゅたく",
    "meaning": "being entrusted with, taking charge of"
  },
  {
    "question": "掘削機",
    "answer": "くっさくき",
    "meaning": "excavator"
  },
  {
    "question": "小片",
    "answer": "しょうへん",
    "meaning": "small piece, fragment, bit"
  },
  {
    "question": "志気",
    "answer": "しき",
    "meaning": "determination, esprit de corps"
  },
  {
    "question": "白墨",
    "answer": "はくぼく",
    "meaning": "blackboard chalk"
  },
  {
    "question": "目方",
    "answer": "めかた",
    "meaning": "weight"
  },
  {
    "question": "二重螺旋",
    "answer": "にじゅうらせん",
    "meaning": "double helix (structure of DNA)"
  },
  {
    "question": "接ぎ木",
    "answer": "つぎき",
    "meaning": "grafting"
  },
  {
    "question": "概",
    "answer": "がい",
    "meaning": "appearance, look, aspect, strong spirit, mettle"
  }
]}